<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--This file is generated by the LocalizationEditor!-->
<Root>
	<Entry>
		<zType />
		<en-US />
		<es />
		<de />
		<fr />
		<ja />
		<zh-TW />
		<ru />
		<zh-CN />
		<pt-BR />
		<ko />
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_START_HITTITE</zType>
		<en-US>You are {CHARACTER-SHORT-1}, warrior king of the {PLAYER-0,3}.

First called Labarnas, you have earned your throne-name of {CHARACTER-SHORT-1} through fighting to unite the heartlands. Although the people now stand behind you, there is still the threat of intrigue. Your family will need to be brought in line if {PLAYER-0} is to become a grand nation to surpass the kingdom of your forefathers.

The established civilizations of this Old World do not yet know of the strength and splendor of {PLAYER-0}, but they will learn. </en-US>
		<es>Eres {CHARACTER-SHORT-1}, el rey guerrero de los {lowercase:{PLAYER-0,3}}.

Antiguamente te conocían como Labarnas, pero te has ganado tu nombre de rey, {CHARACTER-SHORT-1}, al luchar por la unión de las tierras más importantes. Aunque ahora el pueblo te apoya, la amenaza de las intrigas nunca desaparece. Tu familia tendrá que unificarse para que los hititas se conviertan en una gran nación, mucho mayor que la de tus antepasados.

Las civilizaciones que ahora existen en este Viejo Mundo no conocen aún la fuerza y la virtud hitita, pero pronto lo harán.</es>
		<de>Ihr seid {CHARACTER-SHORT-1}, Kriegerkönig der Hethiter.

Einst unter dem Namen Labarna bekannt, habt Ihr Euch Euren Thronnamen {CHARACTER-SHORT-1} durch Eure Kriege zur Vereinigung der hethitischen Kernlande verdient. Obwohl das Volk nun geschlossen hinter Euch steht, besteht die Gefahr einer Intrige. Eure Familie muss für die Erbfolge in Stellung gebracht werden, wenn Hatti als Großmacht den Ruhm des Königreichs Eurer Vorväter übertreffen soll.

Die anderen Zivilisationen dieser alten Welt wissen noch nichts von der Stärke und Tugend der Hethiter – doch sie werden bald davon erfahren. </de>
		<fr>Vous êtes {CHARACTER-SHORT-1}, roi guerrier des Hittites.

Précedemment appelé Labarnas, vous avez obtenu votre nom de trône, {CHARACTER-SHORT-1}, en vous battant pour unir les terres centrales. Même si le peuple se tient aujourd'hui derrière vous, la menace du complot pèse encore. Votre famille devra être mise au pas si les Hittites venaient à devenir une grande nation surpassant le royaume de vos ancêtres.

Les civilisations existantes de ce vieux monde ne sont pas encore conscientes de la force et de la vertu des Hittites, mais cela ne saurait tarder. </fr>
		<ja>あなた、{CHARACTER-SHORT-1}はヒッタイトの戦士王である。

当初はラバルナスと呼ばれていたが、中部地域統一の戦いを通じて、{CHARACTER-SHORT-1}という王の名を得た。今は民衆があなたを支えてくれているが、それでも陰謀の脅威が存在する。ヒッタイトが、あなたの先祖の王国を超える偉大な国になるためには、氏族が一致団結する必要がある。

Old Worldの既存の文明は、まだヒッタイトの強さと美徳を知らない。しかし、いずれ知ることになるだろう。 </ja>
		<zh-TW>你是{CHARACTER-SHORT-1}，西臺人的戰士國王。

起初你叫做拉巴爾那，後來透過戰鬥統一國家腹地，贏得了王位稱號{CHARACTER-SHORT-1}。雖然現在人民在背後支持你，但你依然有被暗算的威脅。若要讓西臺成為超越祖先王國的偉大國家，你必須讓家人服從你。

舊世界現存的文明還不知道西臺的能耐和美善，但他們很快就會明白了。 </zh-TW>
		<ru>Вы {CHARACTER-SHORT-1}, царь-воин хеттов.

Сначала вас звали Лабарнасом, но затем, сражаясь и объединяя земли, вы заработали тронное имя {CHARACTER-SHORT-1}. Народ стоит за вами, но угроза интриги сохраняется. Чтобы хетты стали процветающей нацией и превзошли величием царство ваших предков, вам нужно усмирить собственную семью.

Цивилизации этого древнего мира еще не ведают о силе и доблести хеттов, но скоро это изменится. </ru>
		<zh-CN>你是{CHARACTER-SHORT-1}，西台人的战士国王。

起初你叫做拉巴尔那，后来透过战斗统一国家腹地，赢得了王位称号{CHARACTER-SHORT-1}。虽然现在人民在背后支持你，但你依然有被暗算的威胁。若要让西台成为超越祖先王国的伟大国家，你必须让家人服从你。

旧世界现存的文明还不知道西台的能耐和美善，但他们很快就会明白了。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Você é {CHARACTER-SHORT-1}, rei guerreiro dos {PLAYER-0,3}.
 
Chamado inicialmente de Labarnas, você ganhou o nome real de {CHARACTER-SHORT-1} ao lutar para unir suas terras. Embora o povo agora lhe apoie, as intrigas ainda são uma ameaça. A sua família precisará ser colocada na linha para que {PLAYER-0,4} se torne uma grande nação que supere o reino de seus antepassados.
 
As civilizações existentes nesse Velho Mundo podem ainda não saber sobre a força e o esplendor de {PLAYER-0}, mas logo saberão.</pt-BR>
		<ko>당신은 {PLAYER-0,3}의 전사 왕 {CHARACTER-SHORT-1}입니다.

처음에 라바르나라고 불린 당신은 중심지의 통합을 위한 전투를 통해 {CHARACTER-SHORT-1}(이)라는 호칭을 얻었습니다. 지금은 백성들이 당신을 지지하고 있지만, 모반의 위협이 아직 도사리고 있습니다. {PLAYER-0}가 선조들의 왕국을 뛰어넘는 강대한 국가가 되려면 당신의 가문이 일선에 나설 필요가 있습니다.

기존의 고대 문명들은 {PLAYER-0}의 힘과 탁월함을 아직 모르지만, 곧 알게 될 것입니다. </ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_STUDY_CHARIOT_COMBAT</zType>
		<en-US>{CHARACTER-1}'s tutors are reporting that {G1:he:she} has been showing keen interest and remarkable skill in fighting with mounted units.
How should they focus these great aptitudes?</en-US>
		<es>Los tutores de {CHARACTER-SHORT-1} nos informan de que ha estado mostrado mucho interés y habilidad en la lucha con unidades montadas. ¿Cómo deberían enfocarse estas aptitudes?</es>
		<de>Laut {G1:seinen:ihren} Lehrern zeigt {CHARACTER-1} großes Interesse und Talent beim Kampf mit berittenen Einheiten.
Wie sollen diese Fähigkeiten eingesetzt werden?</de>
		<fr>Les tuteurs {CHARACTER-SHORT-1,1} rapportent qu'{G1:il:elle} fait part d'un grand intérêt et d'une habilité remarquable pour le combat sur unités montées.
Comment devraient-ils focaliser ces grandes aptitudes ?</fr>
		<ja>{CHARACTER-1}の家庭教師によると、{G1:彼:彼女}は騎兵部隊での戦闘に強い関心を示し、驚くべき腕前を発揮しているとのことだ。
この素晴らしい才能をどう生かすべきだろうか？</ja>
		<zh-TW>{CHARACTER-1}的教師向你回報說，{G1:他:她}在與騎兵單位的戰鬥中展現出相當大的興趣及非凡的技巧。
他們應該如何引導這樣的天賦？</zh-TW>
		<ru>Наставники {CHARACTER-1,1} отмечают, что {G1:мальчик преуспел:девочка преуспела} в верховой езде и проявляет неподдельный интерес к конным сражениям.
В какое русло стоит направить {G1:его:ее} таланты?</ru>
		<zh-CN>{CHARACTER-1}的教师向你回报说，{G1:他:她}在与骑兵单位的战斗中展现出相当大的兴趣及非凡的技巧。
他们应该如何引导这样的天赋？</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Os tutores de {CHARACTER-SHORT-1} estão dizendo que {G1:ele:ela} tem demonstrado grande interesse e habilidade em lutas com unidades montadas.
Qual foco eles devem dar para essas aptidões?</pt-BR>
		<ko>{CHARACTER-1}의 교사들이 보고하기를 {G1:그:그녀}가 기병전에 굉장한 관심을 가지고 있으며, 놀라운 기술을 보여 준다고 합니다.
이 훌륭한 적성을 어떻게 살려야 할까요?</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_STUDY_RICHES_OF_THE_HILLS</zType>
		<en-US><![CDATA["We people of the thousand gods inherited the riches of the hills", {CHARACTER-1} tutor explains as they contemplate the countryside from the link(PROJECT_WALLS) of {CITY-2}.<br>
"The hills hide crucial resources, iron and stone, for one crafty enough to find them. They also are a most precious ally in the defense of our lands."<br>
{G1:His:Her} chest swelling with pride, {CHARACTER-1} exclaims:]]></en-US>
		<es>—Nosotros, el pueblo de mil dioses, hemos heredado las riquezas de las colinas —explica el tutor de {CHARACTER-SHORT-1} mientras contemplan el campo desde las link(PROJECT_WALLS) de {CITY-2}—. Las colinas esconden hierro y piedra, recursos cruciales, a la espera de alguien con la habilidad necesaria para hallarlos. Son nuestro aliado más preciado en la defensa de nuestras tierras.

{CHARACTER-1} responde, con el pecho henchido de orgullo:</es>
		<de><![CDATA[„Wir, das Volk der tausend Götter, haben den Reichtum der Hügel geerbt“, erklärt der Lehrer, während er und {CHARACTER-1} das Land von den link(PROJECT_WALLS,3) von {CITY-2} überblicken.<br>
„Die Hügel bergen wichtige Rohstoffe wie Eisen und Stein für jene, die klug genug sind, sie zu finden. Sie sind auch einer unserer wertvollsten Verbündeten bei der Verteidigung unserer Gebiete.“<br>
Mit Stolz im Herzen ruft {CHARACTER-1}:]]></de>
		<fr><![CDATA[« Nous, le peuple aux mille dieux avons hérité des richesses des collines », explique le tuteur {CHARACTER-SHORT-1,1} alors qu'ils contemplent ensemble la campagne depuis les link(PROJECT_WALLS) {CITY-2,1}.<br>
« Les collines renferment des ressources cruciales : du fer et de la pierre, pour ceux assez astucieux pour les trouver. Elles sont également notre plus précieux allié dans la défense de nos terres. »<br>
Sa poitrine se gonflant de fierté, {CHARACTER-1} s'exclame :]]></fr>
		<ja><![CDATA[「千の神々の民である我々は、丘陵の富を神から受け継いだ」 {CHARACTER-1}の家庭教師が{CITY-2}のlink(PROJECT_WALLS)で、田園風景を眺めながらそう説明する。<br>
「丘には重要な資源である鉄と石材が隠されている。少し悪知恵を働かせば、それらを見つけることができるだろう。また、丘は我々の領土を守ってくれる貴重な味方でもある」<br>
{CHARACTER-1}は誇らしげに大声でこう言った。]]></ja>
		<zh-TW><![CDATA[「我們千神之人繼承了丘陵的財富。」在{CHARACTER-1}和教師從{CITY-2}的link(PROJECT_WALLS)上對著鄉村沉思時，教師解釋道。<br>
「丘陵藏有關鍵的資源：鐵礦及石材，要擁有足夠工藝本領的人才能找到它們。它們也是我們抵禦領土時最珍貴的盟友。」<br>
{CHARACTER-1}驕傲地挺起胸膛，{G1:他:她}發出讚嘆：]]></zh-TW>
		<ru><![CDATA[«Мы, народ тысячи богов, унаследовали богатства гор», — слушает {CHARACTER-1} слова наставника, взирая на долину с высоких {lowercase:link(PROJECT_WALLS,1)} {CITY-2,1}.<br>
«Их недра полны железа и камня — важнейших ресурсов, найти которые под силу лишь самым находчивым. Сами же горы — наш ценнейший союзник и первый защитник».<br>
{CHARACTER-1}, гордо выпятив грудь, провозглашает:]]></ru>
		<zh-CN><![CDATA[「我们千神之人继承了丘陵的财富。」在{CHARACTER-1}和教师从{CITY-2}的link(PROJECT_WALLS)上对着乡村沉思时，教师解释道。 <br>
「丘陵藏有关键的资源：铁矿及石材，要拥有足够工艺本领的人才能找到它们。它们也是我们抵御领土时最珍贵的盟友。」<br>
{CHARACTER-1}骄傲地挺起胸膛，{G1:他:她}发出赞叹：]]></zh-CN>
		<pt-BR><![CDATA["Nós, o povo dos mil deuses, herdamos as riquezas das colinas", explica o tutor de {CHARACTER-SHORT-1}, enquanto ambos contemplam a vista dos campos das link(PROJECT_WALLS) de {CITY-2}.<br>
"As colinas escondem recursos cruciais, ferro e pedra, pois alguém com habilidade o suficiente pode encontrá-los. Eles também são nossos valiosos aliados na defesa de nossas terras."<br>
Com seu peito cheio de orgulho, {CHARACTER-SHORT-1} exclama:]]></pt-BR>
		<ko><![CDATA["우리 민족은 수천 명의 신으로부터 언덕의 부를 물려받았습니다." {CHARACTER-1}의 교사가 {CITY-2}의 link(PROJECT_WALLS)을 바라보며 설명합니다.<br>
"언덕에는 철과 석재 같은 귀중한 자원이 숨겨져 있답니다. 머리를 조금 쓰면 충분히 찾을 수 있지요. 언덕은 우리 영토를 보호하는 귀중한 아군이기도 합니다."<br>
가슴에 자부심이 가득한 {CHARACTER-1}(은)는 이렇게 외칩니다.]]></ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_STUDY_THE_FAIREST_OF_LAWS</zType>
		<en-US>"We {PLAYER-0,3} are a lawful people. Our laws were set by wise kings of old and are the fairest of all laws.", {CHARACTER-1} recites.
		
"And how do we know that our laws are the fairest of all?", {G1:his:her} tutor asks.</en-US>
		<es>—Nosotros, los {PLAYER-0,3}, nos ceñimos a las leyes que recibimos de los sabios reyes de antaño: las leyes más justas de todas —recita {CHARACTER-SHORT-1}.

—¿Y cómo sabemos que nuestras leyes son las más justas de todas? —le pregunta su tutor.</es>
		<de><![CDATA[„Wir {PLAYER-0,11} sind ein rechtschaffenes Volk. Unsere Gesetze wurden von den weisen Königen aus alter Zeit geschaffen und sind die gerechtesten“, wiederholt {CHARACTER-1}.<br>
„Und wie wissen wir, dass unsere Gesetze die gerechtesten sind?“, fragt {G1:sein:ihr} Lehrer.]]></de>
		<fr><![CDATA[« Nous les {PLAYER-0,6} sommes un peuple respectueux de la loi. Nos lois ont été établies par les sages roi d'antan et sont les plus justes qui soient », récite {CHARACTER-1}. <br>
« Et comment sait-on que nos lois sont les plus justes de toutes ? », demande son tuteur.]]></fr>
		<ja><![CDATA[「我々{PLAYER-0,3}は法を順守する民である。古代の賢明な王たちによって定められた我々の法律は、あらゆる法律の中でも最も公正に作られている」{CHARACTER-1}が朗読した。 <br>
「我々の法律が最も公正なものだと言えるのは、どうしてだと思う？」と家庭教師が尋ねた。]]></ja>
		<zh-TW><![CDATA[「我們{PLAYER-0,3}是守法的人。我們的法律是由先古的英明國王制定而成，是所有法律中最公平的。」{CHARACTER-1}如此背誦。<br>
「而我們要怎麼知道，我們的法律是所有法律中最公平的呢？」{G1:他的:她的}教師問道。]]></zh-TW>
		<ru><![CDATA[«Мы, {lowercase:{PLAYER-0,12}}, чтим законы. Приняты они мудрейшими из царей древности, и нету на свете законов справедливее», — повторяет {CHARACTER-1}.<br>
«Но почему мы уверены, что наши законы самые справедливые?» — спрашивает {G1:его:ее} наставник.]]></ru>
		<zh-CN><![CDATA[「我们{PLAYER-0,3}是守法的人。我们的法律是由先古的英明国王制定而成，是所有法律中最公平的。」{CHARACTER-1}如此背诵。 <br>
「而我们要怎么知道，我们的法律是所有法律中最公平的呢？」{G1:他的:她的}教师问道。]]></zh-CN>
		<pt-BR><![CDATA["Nós, os {PLAYER-0,3}, obedecemos as leis. Nossas leis foram escritas por sábios reis da antiguidade e são as mais justas das leis", {CHARACTER-SHORT-1} recita.<br>
"E como sabemos que nossas leis são as mais justas de todas?", seu tutor pergunta.]]></pt-BR>
		<ko>"우리 {PLAYER-0,3}은 법을 수호하는 민족이다. 현명한 선대왕들께서 만드신 우리의 법률은 모든 법 중에서 으뜸이다." {CHARACTER-1}(이)가 낭독합니다.
		
"우리의 법률이 모든 법률 중에서 으뜸인 이유는 무엇일까요?" 교사가 묻습니다.</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_STUDY_A_THOUSAND_GODS</zType>
		<en-US>"We {PLAYER-0,3} are the people of a thousand gods! We don't deny the gods of anyone, or the gods from any place."

As {G1:his:her} tutor emphasizes the great number of divinities revered by our people, {CHARACTER-1} asks how best to respect them all.</en-US>
		<es><![CDATA[¡Los {PLAYER-0,3} somos el pueblo de los mil dioses!<br>
No negamos los dioses de nadie, ni los de ningún lugar. A medida que su tutor hace hincapié en el gran número de deidades veneradas por nuestro pueblo, {CHARACTER-SHORT-1} pregunta por la mejor manera de respetarlas a todas.]]></es>
		<de><![CDATA[Wir {PLAYER-0,11} sind das Volk der tausend Götter!<br>
Wir verleumden nicht die Götter der anderen, von woher diese auch stammen mögen. Während {G1:sein:ihr} Lehrer die Unzahl an Göttern, die unser Volk verehrt, hervorhebt, fragt {CHARACTER-1}, was der beste Weg ist, ihnen allen gleichermaßen Respekt zu zollen.]]></de>
		<fr><![CDATA[Nous les {PLAYER-0,6} sommes le peuple aux mille dieux !<br>
Nous ne nions les dieux de personne, peu importe l'endroit. Alors que son tuteur souligne le grand nombre de divinités vénérées par notre peuple, {CHARACTER-1} demande comment toutes les respecter au mieux.]]></fr>
		<ja><![CDATA[我ら{PLAYER-0,3}は千の神々の民だ。<br>
我らはあらゆる神々を認める。誰が何処でどんな神々を崇拝していようと否定することはない。家庭教師が我が国に存在する数多くの神々について述べていると、{CHARACTER-1}が「すべての神々を敬うには、どうするのが一番良いのですか？」と尋ねた。]]></ja>
		<zh-TW><![CDATA[我們{PLAYER-0,3}是千神之人！<br>
我們不否定任何人、或任何地方來的神祈。隨著{CHARACTER-1}的教師強調我國人民崇敬的大量神靈，{G0:他:她}詢問尊崇祂們所有神最好的辦法是什麼。]]></zh-TW>
		<ru><![CDATA[«Мы, {lowercase:{PLAYER-0,12}}, — народ тысячи богов! Мы принимаем всех богов и богов отовсюду», — отмечает наставник многообразие верований хеттов.<br>
«Но как же нам выказать уважение стольким богам?» — вопрошает {CHARACTER-1}.]]></ru>
		<zh-CN><![CDATA[我们{PLAYER-0,3}是千神之人！ <br>
我们不否定任何人、或任何地方来的神祈。随着{CHARACTER-1}的教师强调我国人民崇敬的大量神灵，{G0:他:她}询问尊崇祂们所有神最好的办法是什么。]]></zh-CN>
		<pt-BR><![CDATA["Nós, os {PLAYER-0,3}, somos o povo de mil deuses!"<br>
"Nós não rejeitamos os deuses de ninguém nem de qualquer lugar." Enquanto seu tutor enfatiza a grande quantidade de deuses reverenciados por nosso povo, {CHARACTER-SHORT-1} pergunta como melhor respeitar a todos.]]></pt-BR>
		<ko>"우리 {PLAYER-0,3}은 수천 명의 신을 거느리고 있습니다! 우리는 그 누구의 신도, 그 어느 곳의 신도 부정하지 않지요."

우리가 섬기는 수많은 신성을 강조하는 교사에게 {CHARACTER-1}(이)가 어떻게 하면 신들을 잘 섬길 수 있는지 묻습니다.</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_STUDY_THE_CITY_GATES</zType>
		<en-US>Making the most of a rare occasion to spend time with your {G2:son:daughter} {CHARACTER-SHORT-2}, you take a stroll on {CITY-1} sacred road. As you go through the gates of the city, you explain how each gate illustrates one of the great virtues of the {PLAYER-0,3}. Which gate do you chose to conclude the lesson ?</en-US>
		<es>Sacándole todo el partido a una de las escasas oportunidades de pasar tiempo con tu {G2:hijo:hija} {CHARACTER-SHORT-2}, te das un paseo por la carretera sagrada de {CITY-1}. Mientras pasáis por las puertas de la ciudad, le explicas cómo cada puerta ilustra una de las grandes virtudes de los {PLAYER-0,3}. ¿Qué puerta eliges para finalizar la lección?</es>
		<de>Um die seltene Gelegenheit zu nutzen, mit {G2:Eurem Sohn:Eurer Tochter} {CHARACTER-SHORT-2} Zeit zu verbringen, spaziert Ihr zusammen auf der heiligen Straße von {CITY-1}. Während Ihr durch die Tore der Stadt schreitet, erklärt Ihr, wie jedes von ihnen eine der Tugenden der {PLAYER-0,11} darstellt. Mit welchem Tor wollt Ihr abschließen?</de>
		<fr>Profitant au maximum d'une rare occasion de passer du temps avec votre {G2:fils:fille} {CHARACTER-SHORT-2}, vous vous promenez sur la route sacrée {CITY-1,1}. Alors que vous passez les portes de la cité, vous expliquez comment chaque porte illustre une des grandes vertus des {PLAYER-0,6}. Quelle porte choisissez-vous pour conclure la leçon ?</fr>
		<ja>あなたは{G2:息子:娘}{CHARACTER-SHORT-2}と過ごす貴重な機会を最大限に活用し、{CITY-1}の聖なる道を一緒に散策することにした。散歩中、都市の城門がそれぞれ{PLAYER-0,3}の偉大な美徳の一つを表していることを説明しながら、二人は門を通過する。散歩の締めくくりとして、最後にどの城門を選ぶべきだろうか？</ja>
		<zh-TW>為了充分享受你和你{G2:兒子:女兒}{CHARACTER-SHORT-2}難得的相處時光，你們在{CITY-1}的神聖道路上散步。在你們穿越城市的大門時，你解釋每一扇門都描繪著{PLAYER-0,3}的一項崇高美德。你要用哪道門來當作這堂課的結尾？</zh-TW>
		<ru><![CDATA[Вам наконец выпадает столь редкая возможность провести день с {G2:вашим сыном:вашей дочерью} {CHARACTER-SHORT-2,4}.<br>
Прогуливаясь по священной дороге {CITY-1,1}, вы выходите к городским вратам. «Каждые из этих врат, — объясняете вы, — символизируют одну из великих добродетелей {PLAYER-0,1}». На каких вратах вы завершите урок?]]></ru>
		<zh-CN>为了充分享受你和你{G2:儿子:女儿}{CHARACTER-SHORT-2}难得的相处时光，你们在{CITY-1}的神圣道路上散步。在你们穿越城市的大门时，你解释每一扇门都描绘着{PLAYER-0,3}的一项崇高美德。你要用哪道门来当作这堂课的结尾？</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Aproveitando ao máximo esta rara ocasião para passar algum tempo com {G2:seu filho:sua filha} {CHARACTER-SHORT-2}, vocês vão caminhar na rua sagrada de {CITY-1}. Conforme vocês passam pelas portas da cidade, você explica como cada uma das portas demonstra uma das grandes virtudes dos {PLAYER-0,3}. Qual porta você escolhe para terminar a sua lição?</pt-BR>
		<ko>당신은 {G2:아들:딸}인 {CHARACTER-SHORT-2}과(와) 지낼 수 있는 몇 안 되는 시간 동안 함께 {CITY-1}의 신성한 길을 산책합니다. 도시의 여러 관문을 지나면서 당신은 각 관문이 왜 {PLAYER-0,3}의 위대한 업적인지를 설명합니다. 어느 관문에서 마무리하겠습니까?</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_BLESSING_OF_ARINNITTI</zType>
		<en-US>It has been a propitious season, all have praised your rule, and even enemies have flinched from your gaze. {CHARACTER-2} effuses "It is the mark of Arinnitti upon you, my {TITLE-3}! See, the way the scent of cedar follows you, and the light of the sun catches in your hair! We must thank the goddess for the strength she gifts you. Let us hasten to the opening and dedication of the great link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_ARINNITTI) in {CITY-0}, and show men and gods your piety." </en-US>
		<es>Ha sido una estación propicia, todos han alabado tu reinado e incluso los enemigos se encogieron ante tu mirada. {CHARACTER-2} explica el motivo con alegría:

—¡Se trata de la marca de Arinnitti, mi {TITLE-3}! ¡Se aprecia en el aroma a cedro que le persigue y la forma en que la luz del sol brilla en su cabello! Debemos dar gracias a la diosa por la fuerza que te ha concedido. Apresurémonos a la apertura y dedicación del gran link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_ARINNITTI) en {CITY-0} y mostremos su piedad a los hombres y los dioses.</es>
		<de>Es war eine gute Jahreszeit, alle haben Eure Herrschaft gelobt und Eure Feinde sind vor Eurem Blick zurückgewichen. {CHARACTER-2} spricht ganz begeistert: „Es liegt am Zeichen der Arinnitti auf Euch, {choice_GL:mein:meine} {TITLE-3}! Seht, wie der Duft der Zedern Euch folgt und das Licht der Sonne Euer Haar glänzen lässt! Wir müssen der Göttin für die Stärke danken, die sie Euch schenkt. Beeilen wir uns mit der Eröffnung und Weihung vom großen link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_ARINNITTI) in {CITY-0} und lasst uns unseren Leuten und Göttern Eure Frömmigkeit beweisen.“ </de>
		<fr>Cela a été une saison propice, tous ont fait l'éloge de votre règne et même des ennemis ont reculé face à votre regard. {CHARACTER-2} déclare : « La marque d'Arinnitti est sur vous, ô {TITLE-3} ! Voyez comment l'odeur de cèdre vous suit, et comment la lumière du soleil se répand dans vos cheveux ! Nous devons remercier la déesse pour la force qu'elle vous accorde. Hâtons-nous à l'inauguration et consécration du grand link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_ARINNITTI) à {CITY-0} et montrez aux hommes et aux dieux votre piété. » </fr>
		<ja>今季はあらゆる物事が順風満帆に進んだ。誰もが我が国の統治を賞賛し、敵さえもあなたの視線にたじろいでいる。{CHARACTER-2}は、「{TITLE-3}よ、あなた様にはアリンニティの力が宿っています。ほら、杉の香りが周囲に広がり、太陽の光が髪を照らしているでしょう？女神様が与えてくれる力に感謝しなければなりません。なるべく早く{CITY-0}に巨大なlink(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_ARINNITTI)を開き、人々や 神々に敬虔な精神を示しましょう」と述べた。 </ja>
		<zh-TW>這個季節目前看來很樂觀，所有人都稱讚你的統治，甚至連敵人都因為你的目光而退縮。{CHARACTER-2}發出讚嘆：「這是阿麗寧提在你身上留下的印記，我敬愛的{TITLE-3}！看哪，在你所到之處都有雪松的香氣，還有陽光灑在你的頭髮上的樣子！我們必須感謝女神贈與力量給你。讓我們盡快在{CITY-0}中啟用link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_ARINNITTI)並舉辦奉獻典禮，向眾人及諸神展現你的虔誠。」 </zh-TW>
		<ru><![CDATA[Наступил период процветания. Хеттский народ восхваляет ваше лидерство, а враги дрожат от одного лишь упоминания вашего имени.<br>
«То Ариннити коснулась тебя дланью своею, {G3:мой:моя} {lowercase:{TITLE-3}}, — изрекает {CHARACTER-2}. — Видишь, как следует за тобою всюду аромат кедра, как в локоны твои вплетаются лучи солнца! Восславь же богиню за то, что даровала тебе такое могущество. В {CITY-0,5}, на церемонии освящения {lowercase:link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_ARINNITTI,1)} предстань пред людьми и богами во всем своем благочестии». ]]></ru>
		<zh-CN>这个季节目前看来很乐观，所有人都称赞你的统治，甚至连敌人都因为你的目光而退缩。 {CHARACTER-2}发出赞叹：「这是阿丽宁提在你身上留下的印记，我敬爱的{TITLE-3}！看哪，在你所到之处都有雪松的香气，还有阳光洒在你的头发上的样子！我们必须感谢女神赠与力量给你。让我们尽快在{CITY-0}中启用link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_ARINNITTI)并举办奉献典礼，向众人及诸神展现你的虔诚。」 </zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Foi uma estação auspiciosa, todos elogiaram o seu governo e mesmo os inimigos se acovardaram do seu olhar. {CHARACTER-2} diz animadamente: "É a marca de Arinnitti sobre você, {TITLE-3,3}! Veja a forma com que o aroma do cedro lhe segue e a forma com que a luz do sol bate em seus cabelos! Nós devemos agradecer à deusa pela força que ela lhe concede. Vamos agilizar a abertura e a dedicação do grande link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_ARINNITTI) em {CITY-0}, e mostrar aos homens e deuses a sua piedade."</pt-BR>
		<ko>자비로운 계절이 찾아왔습니다. 모두가 당신의 통치를 찬양했고, 적들조차 당신의 시선 앞에 움츠러들었습니다. {CHARACTER-2}(이)가 토로합니다. "{TITLE-3}(이)시여, 이는 당신께 아린니티의 표식이 남은 것입니다! 보십시오, 백향목 향기가 당신의 뒤를 따르고 태양빛이 당신의 머릿결에 스며들고 있지 않습니까! 당신에게 힘을 내리신 여신께 감사를 표해야 합니다. {CITY-0}의 위대한 link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_ARINNITTI)에서 진행하는 식전 행사와 의식을 재촉해 백성들과 신들께 당신의 신심을 보여야 합니다." </ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_DEDICATION_OF_ARINNITTI</zType>
		<en-US>You feel drowsy as the scent of cedar fills the warm hall and the priestess intones "...and so she set me upon her lap and she took me by the hand and went before me in the battle..." Time seems to blur until, with a start, you realize the recitation is complete and {CHARACTER-2} is in the midst of animated conversation with you. "...can't imagine how they would react, but regardless, we can expect you for the full ceremony at the new link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_ARINNITTI) in {CITY-0}?"</en-US>
		<es>Notas la somnolencia mientras el aroma a cedro inunda el cálido salón y la sacerdotisa entona su cántico:

—Y así me puso en su regazo, me cogió de la mano y me guio a la batalla... —el tiempo parece fundirse hasta que caes en la cuenta de que el cántico ha acabado y estás en medio de una conversación animada con {CHARACTER-SHORT-2}—... no puedo imaginar cómo habrían reaccionado, pero no importa, porque podemos contar con usted para la ceremonia completa en el nuevo link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_ARINNITTI) en {CITY-0}, ¿verdad?</es>
		<de>Ihr fühlt Euch ganz schläfrig in der warmen, mit Zedernduft erfüllten Halle, während Ihr den Worten der Priesterin lauscht: „… und so nahm sie mich auf den Schoß und hielt mich an der Hand und lief vor mir im Kampf …“ Die Zeit scheint zu verschwimmen, bis Ihr ganz überrascht feststellt, dass die Lesung vorbei ist und {CHARACTER-2} mitten in einer angeregten Unterhaltung mit Euch steckt. „… schwer vorstellbar, wie sie reagieren würden, aber können wir mit Euch nichtsdestotrotz bei der ganzen Zeremonie am neuen link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_ARINNITTI) in {CITY-0} rechnen?“</de>
		<fr>Vous avez sommeil quand l'odeur de cèdre remplit la grande salle et que la prêtresse entonne « … et ainsi elle m'a placé sur ses genoux et m'a pris par la main et m'a précédé dans la bataille… » Le temps semble se brouiller, avec un sursaut, vous réalisez que la récitation est terminée et {CHARACTER-SHORT-2,2} est en pleine conversation animée avec vous. « …je ne peux pas m'imaginer comment ils réagiraient, mais quoi qu'il en soit, nous pouvons nous attendre à vous voir à la cérémonie complète au nouveau link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_ARINNITTI) à {CITY-0}, n'est-ce pas ? »</fr>
		<ja>杉の香りが暖かい広間を満たす中、巫女が暗唱する経典の文句を聞いていると、眠気を感じてきた。「そして女神は我を膝の上に置き、我の手を取って、戦いに赴き…」あっという間に時間が過ぎ、気がつくと朗読が終わっていて、あなたは{CHARACTER-2}と楽しげに話している最中だった。 「彼らがどう反応するのか想像もつかないですが、ともかく、{CITY-0}の新しいlink(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_ARINNITTI)で行われる正式な儀式にご参加してくださるということでよいのですね？」</ja>
		<zh-TW>雪松的氣味充滿了溫暖的大廳，使你感到昏昏沉沉，女祭司用莊嚴而緩慢的語氣說：「…於是，她讓我坐在她的大腿上，再牽起我的手，然後在我之前踏上戰場…」時間變得模糊，直到你嚇了一跳，意識到朗誦已經完成，而{CHARACTER-2}正在與你進行熱烈的交談。「…真不敢相信他們會怎麼反應，但不管怎樣，我們是否能期待你會參加{CITY-0}的新link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_ARINNITTI)的完整儀式？」</zh-TW>
		<ru>В зале тепло и пахнет кедром. Сквозь полудрему вы слышите слова молитвы: «…и усадила меня на колени, и руку мою в свою взяла, и первой пошла в бой…» В какой-то момент кажется, будто время остановилось, но вдруг вы понимаете, что молитва окончена, а {CHARACTER-2} обращается к вам с пылкой речью: «…не представляю, как они к этому отнесутся, ну да ладно. Вы же посетите церемонию освящения нового {lowercase:link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_ARINNITTI,1)} в {CITY-0,5}?»</ru>
		<zh-CN>雪松的气味充满了温暖的大厅，使你感到昏昏沉沉，女祭司用庄严而缓慢的语气说：「…于是，她让我坐在她的大腿上，再牵起我的手，然后在我之前踏上战场…」时间变得模糊，直到你吓了一跳，意识到朗诵已经完成，而{CHARACTER-2}正在与你进行热烈的交谈。 「…真不敢相信他们会怎么反应，但不管怎样，我们是否能期待你会参加{CITY-0}的新link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_ARINNITTI)的完整仪式？」</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Você sente uma sonolência conforme o aroma do cedro preenche o salão quente e a sacerdotisa entona: "...e então ela me deitou sobre seu colo e me tomou pela mão e tomou minha frente na batalha..." O tempo parece se estender infinitamente até que, com um susto, você percebe que o recital está completo e que {CHARACTER-SHORT-2} lhe fala animadamente: "...nem posso imaginar como eles reagiriam, mas de qualquer forma, podemos contar com sua presença para a cerimônia completa no novo link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_ARINNITTI) em {CITY-0}?"</pt-BR>
		<ko>백향목의 향기가 감도는 따뜻한 회랑에서 졸음이 느껴지는 와중 여사제의 목소리가 들립니다. "...그렇게 여신께서는 저를 무릎 위에 앉히시고 제 손을 쥔 다음 저를 두고 전장으로 떠나셨습니다..." 몽롱한 시간 끝에 정신을 차렸더니 낭송은 끝났고 당신은 {CHARACTER-2}(과)와 열띤 대화를 나누던 중이었습니다. "...저들이 어떻게 반응할지는 상상할 수 없지만, 그래도 {CITY-0}의 새로운 link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_ARINNITTI)에서 열리는 전체 행사에 당신의 참석을 기대해도 되겠지요?"</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_DISPLEASURE_OF_ARINNITTI</zType>
		<en-US>{CHARACTER-2} enters the hall at the head of a formation of stern-looking priestesses clad in the bright gold of the sun. "My {TITLE-3}, I shall not mince words, Arinnitti has forsaken you and so soon will the people, sure as darkness follows the sunset. But each night brings a new dawn, and even one such as you may supplicate yourself for forgiveness at the great ceremony dedicating the link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_ARINNITTI) in {CITY-0}." </en-US>
		<es>{CHARACTER-2} entra en el salón a la cabeza de una formación de sacerdotisas con mirada severa envueltas en la luz dorada del sol.

—Mi {TITLE-3}, no me andaré con rodeos: Arinnitti le ha abandonado y pronto lo hará su pueblo, con la certeza de que la oscuridad persigue al ocaso. Pero cada noche termina en el alba, e incluso alguien de su magnitud puede suplicar por el perdón en la gran ceremonia que tendrá lugar en el link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_ARINNITTI) en {CITY-0}.</es>
		<de>{CHARACTER-2} betritt die Halle an der Spitze eines Zuges aus ernsten Priesterinnen, die im hellen Gold der Sonne gekleidet sind. „{choice_GL:Mein:Meine} {TITLE-3}, meine Worte sollen klar sein: Arinnitti hat Euch verlassen und das Volk wird es ihr bald gleichtun, so sicher wie die Dunkelheit auf den Sonnenuntergang folgt. Doch jede Nacht hält einen neuen Morgen bereit und selbst jemand wie Ihr darf demütig um Vergebung bei der großen Zeremonie zur Weihung link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_ARINNITTI,3) in {CITY-0} bitten.“ </de>
		<fr>{CHARACTER-2} entre dans la grande salle à la tête d'une procession de prêtresses austères habillées de la lumineuse couleur or du soleil. « {TITLE-3}, je ne mâcherai pas mes mots, Arinnitti vous a {choice_GL:abandonné:abandonnée} et bientôt, le peuple le sera également, aussi certain que l'obscurité suivant le coucher du soleil. Mais chaque nuit amène une nouvelle aube et même quelqu'un de votre stature peut implorer le pardon lors de la grande cérémonie de consécration du link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_ARINNITTI) à {CITY-0}. » </fr>
		<ja>太陽の輝きに包まれた、厳粛な面持ちの巫女たちを先頭に、{CHARACTER-2}が広間に入ってくる。「{TITLE-3}よ、言葉を選ばずに申し上げましょう。アリンニティはあなた様を見捨てました。闇が日没の後に続くように、やがて民も見放されることになるでしょう。それでも、明けない夜はありません。あなた様のような方でも、{CITY-0}のlink(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_ARINNITTI)で行われる盛大な奉献式で、赦しを請うことができます。 </ja>
		<zh-TW>{CHARACTER-2}走進大廳，身後領著一隊相貌莊嚴的女祭司，她們身穿著陽光般的豔麗金色服飾。「我敬愛的{TITLE-3}，我就直說了，阿麗寧提已經拋棄了你，而如同黑暗會隨著日落而來一般，人民很快也會拋棄你。不過，每個夜晚都會帶來新的晨曦，就連像你這樣的人也可以在{CITY-0}為link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_ARINNITTI)舉辦盛大的落成儀式來祈求寬恕。」 </zh-TW>
		<ru>{CHARACTER-2} ведет к трону процессию из жриц, чьи взгляды суровы, а одеяния пылают солнечным блеском. «{G3:Мой:Моя} {lowercase:{TITLE-3}}, позволь говорить прямо: Ариннити от тебя отвернулась, а скоро отвернется и хеттский народ. Неизбежно это, как неизбежен закат солнца. Но как за каждым закатом неминуемо следует рассвет, так и ты сможешь вернуть милость богини на церемонии освящения {lowercase:link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_ARINNITTI,1)} в {CITY-0,5}». </ru>
		<zh-CN>{CHARACTER-2}走进大厅，身后领着一队相貌庄严的女祭司，她们身穿着阳光般的艳丽金色服饰。 「我敬爱的{TITLE-3}，我就直说了，阿丽宁提已经抛弃了你，而如同黑暗会随着日落而来一般，人民很快也会抛弃你。不过，每个夜晚都会带来新的晨曦，就连像你这样的人也可以在{CITY-0}为link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_ARINNITTI)举办盛大的落成仪式来祈求宽恕。」 </zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>{CHARACTER-2} adentra o salão encabeçando uma formação de sacerdotisas de aparência severa envoltas pela luz dourada do sol. "{sentencecase:{TITLE-3,3}}, não medirei minhas palavras: Arinnitti lhe abandonou e logo seu povo também o fará, assim como é certo que a escuridão segue o pôr do sol. Mas cada noite traz um novo amanhecer, e mesmo alguém como você pode suplicar por perdão na grande cerimônia de dedicação ao link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_ARINNITTI) em {CITY-0}."</pt-BR>
		<ko>{CHARACTER-2}(이)가 태양의 밝은 금빛을 두른 근엄한 여사제 행렬의 선두에 서서 회랑으로 들어옵니다. "{TITLE-3}(이)시여, 둘러말하지 않겠습니다. 아린니티께서 당신을 저버리셨으며, 곧 백성들 역시 노을이 끝나고 덮치는 어둠처럼 그리할 것입니다. 하나 모든 밤 뒤에는 새벽이 있듯, 당신 같은 사람일지라도 {CITY-0}의 link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_ARINNITTI)에서 진행하는 대제를 통해 용서를 구할 수 있습니다." </ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_BLESSING_OF_TARHUN</zType>
		<en-US>On a tour of defenses along with your closest advisors, {CHARACTER-2} walks beside you. "My {TITLE-3}, our forces are strong, but none can prevail in war without the gods at their back. Seek the blessing of Tarhun. Bring His lightning down on our foes, let them tremble at the feet of His oxen. Come to {CITY-0}, take an honored place at the sanctification of the link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_TARHUN), and I am sure He will take note." </en-US>
		<es>{CHARACTER-2} camina a tu lado junto a tus consejeros más cercanos en una visita por las defensas.

—Mi {TITLE-3}, nuestros ejércitos son fuertes, pero nadie prevalece en la guerra sin el apoyo de los dioses. Busque la bendición de Tarhu, haga caer su rayo sobre nuestros enemigos: que tiemblen a los pies de sus bueyes. Venga a {CITY-0}, ocupe una posición de honor en la santificación del link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_TARHUN), y tenga por seguro que Él se percatará de su presencia.</es>
		<de>Bei einer Begehung der Verteidigungsanlagen mit Euren engsten Beratern läuft {CHARACTER-2} an Eurer Seite. „{choice_GL:Mein:Meine} {TITLE-3}, unsere Truppen mögen stark sein, doch niemand kann in einem Krieg ohne die Hilfe der Götter bestehen. Bittet Tarḫunna um seinen Segen. Seine Blitze sollen Eure Feinde treffen und sie sollen zu Füßen seines Ochsen zittern. Kommt nach {CITY-0}, nehmt einen Ehrenplatz bei der Weihung link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_TARHUN,3) ein und ich bin sicher, dass er diese Geste zu Kenntnis nehmen wird.“ </de>
		<fr>Lors d'une inspection des défenses avec vos proches conseillers, {CHARACTER-2} marche à vos côtés. « Ô {TITLE-3}, nos forces sont puissantes, mais personne ne peut l'emporter à la guerre sans l'appui des dieux. Sollicitez la bénédiction de Tahrun. Faites tomber sa foudre sur nos ennemis, laissez-les trembler au pied de Ses bœufs. Venez à {CITY-0}, faites-nous l'honneur d'assister à la sanctification du link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_TARHUN), et je suis {G1:certain:certaine} qu'Il prêtera attention. » </fr>
		<ja>あなたは側近の{CHARACTER-2}と共に我が国の防衛施設を視察して回った。「{TITLE-3}よ、我が軍は確かに強い。しかし、神々の後ろ盾なしには、何人も戦争に勝つことはできませぬ。タルフンのご加護を求めましょう。敵に稲妻を降らせ、主の雄牛の足元で震え上がらせるのです。{CITY-0}へおいでください。link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_TARHUN)でお待ちしております。きっと主や民も歓迎してくれるはずです」 </ja>
		<zh-TW>在你和最親近的顧問一起參觀防禦工事時，{CHARACTER-2}走在你的身邊。「我敬愛的{TITLE-3}，我們的部隊很強大，然而，少了眾神的支持，任何人都無法在戰爭中獲勝。請祈求塔爾亨的祝福。讓他的閃電降於我們的敵人，讓他們在他的聖牛腳邊顫抖吧。請到{CITY-0}來，在link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_TARHUN)的聖化過程中接受榮耀的位置，這樣祂一定會注意到你的。」 </zh-TW>
		<ru>Вы проводите осмотр оборонительных сооружений в компании верных советников, среди которых и {CHARACTER-2}. «Нашим воинам мало равных, {lowercase:{TITLE-3}}, — рассуждает {G2:он:она}, шагая поодаль, — но даже им не выиграть войну без помощи богов. Попроси Тархунта ниспослать благословение. Пускай враг содрогнется от блеска молний Его, пускай задохнется под копытами Его буйволов. Явись в {CITY-0,3} на освящение {lowercase:link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_TARHUN,1)}: {G2:уверен:уверена}, Тархунту будет это угодно». </ru>
		<zh-CN>在你和最亲近的顾问一起参观防御工事时，{CHARACTER-2}走在你的身边。 「我敬爱的{TITLE-3}，我们的部队很强大，然而，少了众神的支持，任何人都无法在战争中获胜。请祈求塔尔亨的祝福。让他的闪电降于我们的敌人，让他们在他的圣牛脚边颤抖吧。请到{CITY-0}来，在link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_TARHUN)的圣化过程中接受荣耀的位置，这样祂一定会注意到你的。」 </zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Em uma ronda das defesas junto com seus conselheiros mais próximos, {CHARACTER-2} caminha ao seu lado. "{sentencecase:{TITLE-3,3}}, nossas tropas são fortes, mas ninguém pode prevalecer sem o apoio dos deuses. Busque as bênçãos de Tahrun. Que os raios dele caiam sobre nossos inimigos, que eles tremam aos pés dos bois dele. Venha a {CITY-0}, e assuma uma posição honrada na santificação do link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_TARHUN), tenho certeza que não passará despercebido a ele."</pt-BR>
		<ko>당신이 측근들과 방비를 시찰하는 동안 {CHARACTER-2}(은)는 당신 곁에서 걷고 있습니다. "{TITLE-3}(이)시여, 우리의 군대는 강력하나 신들의 보살핌이 없는 한 절대로 전쟁에서 승리할 수 없습니다. 타르훈의 축복을 구하십시오. 적들에게 그분의 번개를 내려 신성한 황소들의 발치에서 그들이 떨게 하십시오. {CITY-0}의 link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_TARHUN)에 오셔서 축성이 이루어지는 신성한 자리에 참석하시면 그분께서도 분명 주목하실 것입니다." </ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_DEDICATION_OF_TARHUN</zType>
		<en-US>There is a clatter of hooves as {CHARACTER-2} leads a procession of priests of Tarhun and their sacred bulls before you. "My {TITLE-3}, the gods demand your attention. Lightning struck thrice and thrice more in last night's storm and the omens are right to dedicate the great link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_TARHUN) at {CITY-0}. If you wish the strength of Tarhun behind our armies, I implore you to attend." </en-US>
		<es>Los cascos resuenan a medida que {CHARACTER-SHORT-2} lidera la procesión de sacerdotes de Tarhu y sus toros sagrados ante ti.

—Mi {TITLE-3}, los dioses piden su atención. El rayo golpeó tres veces, y tres veces más en la tormenta de anoche. Los presagios no mienten: hay que inaugurar el gran link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_TARHUN) en {CITY-0}. Si desea que la fuerza de Tarhu acompañe a nuestros ejércitos, le suplico que acuda.</es>
		<de>Das Klopfen von Hufen ertönt, als {CHARACTER-2} eine Prozession mit Priestern des Tarḫunna und den heiligen Bullen vor Euch anführt. „{choice_GL:Mein:Meine} {TITLE-3}, die Götter verlangen Eure Aufmerksamkeit. Während des Sturms von letzter Nacht schlug der Blitz dreimal und dreimal mehr ein. Die Omen stehen richtig für die Weihung vom großen link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_TARHUN) bei {CITY-0}. Wenn Ihr wollt, dass Tarḫunna Eure Truppen stärkt, bitte ich Euch inständig, daran teilzunehmen.“ </de>
		<fr>Un fracas de sabots se fait entendre alors {CHARACTER-SHORT-2,2} amène devant vous une procession de prêtres de Tarhun accompagnés par leurs taureaux sacrés. « Ô {TITLE-3}, les dieux exigent votre attention. La foudre a frappé par trois fois et trois fois encore lors de la tempête de la nuit dernière et les présages pointent à la consécration du grand link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_TARHUN) à {CITY-0}. Si vous souhaitez obtenir la force de Tarhun pour vos armées, je vous implore d'y assister. » </fr>
		<ja>蹄の音が響く中、{CHARACTER-2}がタルフンの司祭と彼らの神聖な雄牛から成る行列を率いて、あなたの前に現れる。「{TITLE-3}よ、神々が注目を求めています。昨夜の嵐で雷が何度も鳴り響きました。これは主のお告げです。{CITY-0}のlink(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_TARHUN)で奉献式を開くべきでしょう。我が軍にタルフンの力を望むのであれば、是非とも参加していただきたい」 </ja>
		<zh-TW>隨著一陣蹄聲，{CHARACTER-2}帶領著一群塔爾亨祭司和他們的的聖牛來到你面前。「我敬愛的{TITLE-3}，諸神需要你的關注。在昨夜的暴風雨中，閃電先打下三次，隨後又再次打下三次，所有的徵兆都符合要在{CITY-0}的大link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_TARHUN)舉行奉獻典禮一事。如果你想要塔爾亨的力量在背後加持你的軍隊，我懇請你前來參加。」 </zh-TW>
		<ru>Земля дрожит от стука копыт, {CHARACTER-2} ведет вам навстречу процессию жрецов Тархунта и стадо священных быков. «Внемли зову богов, {G3:мой:моя} {lowercase:{TITLE-3}}! Вчера в разгар ночной бури трижды била молния, а после — снова трижды, знаменуя час освящения великого {lowercase:link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_TARHUN,1)} в городе {CITY-0,5}. Приходи на церемонию и ты, если желаешь получить силу Тархунта». </ru>
		<zh-CN>随着一阵蹄声，{CHARACTER-2}带领着一群塔尔亨祭司和他们的的圣牛来到你面前。 「我敬爱的{TITLE-3}，诸神需要你的关注。在昨夜的暴风雨中，闪电先打下三次，随后又再次打下三次，所有的征兆都符合要在{CITY-0}的大link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_TARHUN)举行奉献典礼一事。如果你想要塔尔亨的力量在背后加持你的军队，我恳请你前来参加。」 </zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Ouve-se o som de cascos quando {CHARACTER-2} vem liderando uma procissão de sacerdotes de Tarhun e seus bois sagrados ante você. "{sentencecase:{TITLE-3,3}}, os deuses exigem sua atenção. Os raios caíram três vezes e três vezes mais na tempestade de ontem a noite, e os sinais indicam que o grande link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_TARHUN) em {CITY-0} deve ser aberto. Se você deseja a força de Tarhun encorajando nossos exércitos, eu lhe imploro que esteja presente na dedicação."</pt-BR>
		<ko>{CHARACTER-2}(이)가 당신 앞으로 이끄는 타르훈의 사제들과 신성한 황소들의 발소리가 들립니다. "{TITLE-3}(이)시여, 신들께서 당신의 관심을 원하십니다. 간밤의 폭풍 때 벼락이 세 번 하고도 세 번 더 내리쳤으며, 이는 {CITY-0}의 위대한 link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_TARHUN)에 봉헌하라는 징조가 분명합니다. 타르훈의 힘이 우리 군대를 편들어 주기를 원하신다면 그 자리에 참석해 주시기를 간청합니다." </ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_DISPLEASURE_OF_TARHUN</zType>
		<en-US>As you make to ride out and meet with your generals in the field, {CHARACTER-2} stands in your path. "You are not mightier than the gods, O {TITLE-3}. If you do not make amends for your reckless impiety, Tarhun will ensure spear or lightning fells every man sworn to you, that your own hubris cuts you down sure as any blade. Repent, supplicate yourself at the dedication of the link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_TARHUN) in {CITY-0}, and you and your men might yet be saved."</en-US>
		<es>Mientras te diriges a caballo al encuentro con tus generales en el campo, {CHARACTER-SHORT-2} te sale al paso.

—No tiene más poder que los dioses, oh, {TITLE-3}. Si no soluciona su impiedad imprudente, Tarhu se asegurará de que lluevan lanzas y rayos sobre todo aquel que le haya prestado juramento, y de que su propia soberbia le lacere como una hoja afilada. Arrepiéntase y suplique en la inauguración del link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_TARHUN) en {CITY-0}, y habrá esperanza para la salvación de usted y sus hombres.</es>
		<de>Als Ihr Euch aufmachen wollt, um Euch mit Euren Generälen auf dem Feld zu treffen, stellt sich Euch {CHARACTER-2} in den Weg. „Ihr seid nicht mächtiger als die Götter, o {TITLE-3}. Wenn Ihr Eure leichtsinnige Gottlosigkeit nicht bald sühnt, wird Tarḫunna dafür sorgen, dass Speere oder Blitze jeden Mann in Euren Diensten niederstrecken – dass Ihr Eurer Überheblichkeit so sicher erliegt wie einem Messerstich. Tut Buße, zeigt Demut bei der Weihung link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_TARHUN,3) in {CITY-0} und es besteht noch Hoffnung für Euch und Eure Männer.“</de>
		<fr>Alors que vous vous apprêtez à chevaucher pour aller rejoindre vos généraux sur le terrain, {CHARACTER-2} se dresse sur votre chemin. « Vous n'êtes pas plus fort que les dieux, ô {TITLE-3}. Si vous ne vous rachetez pas pour votre impiété imprudente, Tarhun s'assurera que les lances ou la foudre abattent tous vos hommes et que votre propre orgueil vous fauche tel une lame. Repentez-vous, implorez son pardon lors de la consécration du link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_TARHUN) à {CITY-0} et vos hommes et vous pourront peut-être encore être sauvés. »</fr>
		<ja>戦場に乗り込み、将官たちに合流しようとするあなたの前に、{CHARACTER-2}が立ちはだかる。「{TITLE-3}よ、あなた様の力は神々には及びません。もし神々を敬わず、自らの不信心な行為を償わないのなら、タルフンが必ずや、あなた様に忠誠を誓う者の上に槍や雷を振り落とすことでしょう。己の驕りで身を滅ぼすことになりますよ。悔い改め、{CITY-0}のlink(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_TARHUN)で行われる奉献式にご参加ください。まだ救いの可能性は残されています」</ja>
		<zh-TW>在你騎馬出去和你的將軍在原野中會合時，{CHARACTER-2}擋在你的面前。「噢，{TITLE-3}，你並不比諸神偉大。如果你不想要為你張狂的褻瀆贖罪的話，塔爾亨會確保所有效忠你的人都被長矛或閃電擊倒，讓你自己因為傲慢而自取滅亡。懺悔吧，在{CITY-0}的link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_TARHUN)奉獻儀式中祈求寬恕，你和你的手下或許還有機會能得救。」</zh-TW>
		<ru>Вы направляетесь в шатер командования на совещание с генералами, когда путь вам преграждает {CHARACTER-2}: «Не думай, {lowercase:link{TITLE-3}}, что ты выше богов. Покайся в неверии, не то навлечешь на воинов своих гнев Тархунта, и {choice_GL:сам:сама} погибнешь не от меча, но от надменности своей. В {CITY-0,5}, на освящении {lowercase:link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_TARHUN,1)} пади ниц и моли об искуплении!»</ru>
		<zh-CN>在你骑马出去和你的将军在原野中会合时，{CHARACTER-2}挡在你的面前。 「噢，{TITLE-3}，你并不比诸神伟大。如果你不想要为你张狂的亵渎赎罪的话，塔尔亨会确保所有效忠你的人都被长矛或闪电击倒，让你自己因为傲慢而自取灭亡。忏悔吧，在{CITY-0}的link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_TARHUN)奉献仪式中祈求宽恕，你和你的手下或许还有机会能得救。」</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Enquanto você se prepara para ir se encontrar com seus generais no campo, {CHARACTER-2} se põe em seu caminho. "Você não tem mais poder que os deuses, {TITLE-3,3}. Se você não buscar se redimir por sua leviana impiedade, Tarhun fará com que, por raio ou por espada, caia todo homem que lhe jurou lealdade, e que sua própria soberba lhe derrube tão certeira como qualquer lâmina. Arrependa-se, suplique na dedicação do link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_TARHUN) em {CITY-0}, e você e seus homens ainda poderão ser salvos."</pt-BR>
		<ko>전장의 장군들과 합류하려고 말에 오른 당신의 길을 {CHARACTER-2}(이)가 가로막습니다. "{TITLE-3}(이)시여, 당신은 신들보다 위대하지 않습니다. 당신의 불경함에 대한 용서를 구하지 않는다면 당신을 받드는 모든 이에게 타르훈의 창과 번개가 필히 내려칠 것이며, 당신의 교만은 칼날이 되어 스스로를 벨 것입니다. 당신과 당신의 부하들이 아직 구원받을 수 있을 때 {CITY-0}의 link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_TARHUN)에 오셔서 의식에 참석해 회개하시고 애원하십시오."</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_BLESSING_OF_KAMRUSEPA</zType>
		<en-US>In the dark nights of winter, dreams had come to you of a season of maladies and illness. Speaking of them to {CHARACTER-2}, you receive the counsel "It is Kamrusepa you must seek, She is the salve against weakening of soul and body. Come with me, attend Her great ceremony at the link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_KAMRUSEPA) of {CITY-0}."</en-US>
		<es>En las oscuras noches invernales te han asaltado los sueños sobre una serie de males y dolencias. Al comunicárselas a {CHARACTER-SHORT-2}, recibes su consejo:

—Debe acudir a Kamrusepa, pues ella es el bálsamo contra la debilidad del alma y el cuerpo. Venga conmigo, asista a la gran ceremonia en el link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_KAMRUSEPA) de {CITY-0}.</es>
		<de>In den dunklen Winternächten träumtet Ihr von einer Zeit der Leiden und der Krankheit. {CHARACTER-2} gibt Euch folgenden Rat, als Ihr darüber mit {G2:ihm:ihr} sprecht: „Es ist Kamrušepa, die Ihr ersuchen müsst. Sie ist das Mittel gegen die Schwächung von Körper und Geist. Kommt mit mir und seid anwesend bei der großen Zeremonie am link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_KAMRUSEPA) von {CITY-0}.“</de>
		<fr>Dans les nuits noires de l'hiver, des rêves vous parviennent d'une saison de maladies. Vous en faites part à {CHARACTER-2} qui vous donne le conseil suivant : « Il vous faut solliciter Kamrusepa, Elle est le remède contre l'affaiblissement de l'âme et du corps. Venez avec moi, assistez à Sa grande cérémonie au link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_KAMRUSEPA) {CITY-0,1}. »</fr>
		<ja>冬の闇夜に恐ろしい夢を見た。その中では、もうすぐ病魔の季節が訪れることが告げられていた。そのことを{CHARACTER-2}に話すと、助言を受けることができた。「あなた様が求めるべきはカムルセパです。彼女は魂や肉体の衰弱を防いでくれます。私と一緒に、{CITY-0}のlink(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_KAMRUSEPA)で行われる偉大な奉献式に参加しましょう」</ja>
		<zh-TW>在冬天的黑夜中，你在夢中看見了一個充滿疾病與病痛的季節。在你和{CHARACTER-2}談論此事時，你得到了勸告：「你必須去向卡姆魯塞帕祈求，她是對抗心靈及身體弊病的良藥。跟我一起走，去參加她在{CITY-0}的link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_KAMRUSEPA)的盛大儀式吧。」</zh-TW>
		<ru>В эти долгие зимние ночи вас мучают беспокойные сны. Сны о наступлении мрачного времени упадка и хвори. «Ищи Камрусепу, — говорит {CHARACTER-2}, когда вы обращаетесь к {G2:нему:ней} за советом, — ибо только Она избавит тело и душу твою от страданий. Пойдем со мной в {CITY-0,3}. На святой церемонии в {lowercase:link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_KAMRUSEPA,5)} обратись к великой богине».</ru>
		<zh-CN>在冬天的黑夜中，你在梦中看见了一个充满疾病与病痛的季节。在你和{CHARACTER-2}谈论此事时，你得到了劝告：「你必须去向卡姆鲁塞帕祈求，她是对抗心灵及身体弊病的良药。跟我一起走，去参加她在{CITY-0}的link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_KAMRUSEPA)的盛大仪式吧。」</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Nas escuras noites de inverno, você sonhou com uma estação de aflições e doenças. Ao falar sobre seu sonho com {CHARACTER-2}, {G2:ele:ela} lhe oferece seu conselho: "Busque Kamrusepa, ela é o bálsamo contra as fraquezas do corpo e da alma. Venha comigo à grande cerimônia no link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_KAMRUSEPA) em {CITY-0}."</pt-BR>
		<ko>겨울의 어두운 밤, 꿈에서 당신은 역병의 계절을 목도했습니다. 이를 {CHARACTER-2}에게 말했더니 이렇게 조언을 들었습니다. "당신은 심신의 쇠약으로부터 구원해 주시는 캄루세파를 찾으셔야 합니다. 저와 함께 {CITY-0}의 link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_KAMRUSEPA)에서 진행하는 그분을 위한 대제에 참석하십시오."</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_DEDICATION_OF_KAMRUSEPA</zType>
		<en-US>It had been a season of maladies and illness, until at the urging of the court, priestesses of Kamrusepa were called upon. They sweep through the palace bearing incense, balms and chants of cleansing. In their wake, the mood lightens and a liveliness returns. {CHARACTER-2}, however, lingers as the priestesses depart. "Take heed, My {TITLE-3}, Kamrusepa demands no payment, but you would do well to honor her at the dedication of her link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_KAMRUSEPA) in {CITY-0}."</en-US>
		<es>Estaba siendo una temporada de dolencias y males hasta que las sacerdotisas de Kamrusepa acudieron al llamado en la corte. Recorrieron el palacio con incienso, bálsamos y cantos curativos. A su paso, el ambiente se aligera y la energía se reaviva. {CHARACTER-2}, no obstante, se para a comunicarte algo cuando las sacerdotisas han partido:

—Escuche mi consejo, mi {TITLE-3}. Kamrusepa no exige pago alguno, pero haría bien en honrarla en la inauguración de su link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_KAMRUSEPA) en {CITY-0}.</es>
		<de>Nach einer Zeit hartnäckiger Krankheiten und Leiden wurden auf Verlangen des Hofes Priesterinnen der Kamrušepa geladen. Nun schreiten sie durch den Palast und läutern ihn mit Räucherwerk und Gesang. Überall, wo sie entlangschreiten, wird die Stimmung wieder heller und lebhafter. Als die Priesterinnen davonziehen, verweilt {CHARACTER-2} noch ein wenig. „Passt auf, {TITLE-3}, Kamrušepa erwartet zwar keine Entlohnung. Doch es wäre nur angemessen, wenn Ihr ihr bei der Weihung link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_KAMRUSEPA,3) in {CITY-0} Respekt zollt.“</de>
		<fr>Une saison de maladies s'éternisait jusqu'à ce que la cour insiste pour recourir aux services des prêtresses de Kamrusepa. Elles parcourent le palais, portant de l'encens et des baumes et récitant des chants. À leur passage, l'humeur s'égaye et la vitalité revient. {CHARACTER-2}, cependant, s'attarde après le départ des prêtresses. « Écoutez attentivement, ô {TITLE-3}, Kamrusepa ne demande aucun paiement, mais vous feriez bien de la gratifier à l'occasion de la consécration de son link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_KAMRUSEPA) à {CITY-0}. »</fr>
		<ja>今季は疫病が流行り、民衆は病魔に悩まされた。やがて宮廷ではカムルスパの巫女たちが呼び出されることとなった。お香や香油を持った巫女たちは、清めの言葉を唱えながら、宮殿の中を歩き回る。そのおかげか、人々の表情は明るくなり、街の活気も戻ってきた。しかし、巫女たちが去った後でも、{CHARACTER-2}は居残り続けた。「{TITLE-3}よ、お気をつけください。カムルセパは捧げ物を要求しません。しかし、{CITY-0}のlink(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_KAMRUSEPA)で行われる奉献式に参加することをお勧めします」</ja>
		<zh-TW>這個季節充滿了疾病與病痛，直到你在朝臣的催促下請來了卡姆魯塞帕的女祭司。她們帶著薰香、香膏及淨化誦詞穿越宮殿。在她們所經之處，氣氛都變得輕鬆，生氣也恢復了。然而，在女祭司離開時，{CHARACTER-2}卻徘徊不去。「請留意，我敬愛的{TITLE-3}，卡姆魯塞帕並不要求回報，不過你可以到{CITY-0}的link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_KAMRUSEPA)參與她的奉獻儀式來榮耀她。」</zh-TW>
		<ru>Болезни и несчастья раздирают наши земли. По совету придворных вы взываете к помощи жриц Камрусепы. Те являются во дворец, неся благовония и целебные мази, напевая молитвы об очищении. С их появлением тьма словно отступает и во дворец возвращается жизнь. Когда жрицы уходят, {CHARACTER-2} задерживается и обращается к вам: «Знай, {choice_GL:царь:царица}, Камрусепа не требует платы. Но скоро в {CITY-0,5} пройдет церемония освящения {lowercase:link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_KAMRUSEPA,1)}. Советую тебе ее посетить». </ru>
		<zh-CN>这个季节充满了疾病与病痛，直到你在朝臣的催促下请来了卡姆鲁塞帕的女祭司。她们带着薰香、香膏及净化诵词穿越宫殿。在她们所经之处，气氛都变得轻松，生气也恢复了。然而，在女祭司离开时，{CHARACTER-2}却徘徊不去。 「请留意，我敬爱的{TITLE-3}，卡姆鲁塞帕并不要求回报，不过你可以到{CITY-0}的link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_KAMRUSEPA)参与她的奉献仪式来荣耀她。」</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Se passou uma estação de aflições e doenças, até que, por insistência da corte, sacerdotisas de Kamrusepa foram chamadas. Elas fazem uma ronda no palácio levando incenso, bálsamos e entoando cantos purificadores. Seguido aos rituais, o clima fica mais leve e uma animação volta aos salões e corredores. {CHARACTER-2}, porém, se demora enquanto as sacerdotisas estão para ir embora. "Fique alerta, {TITLE-3,3}, Kamrusepa não exige qualquer pagamento, mas seria bom que você a homenageasse na dedicação do link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_KAMRUSEPA) em {CITY-0}."</pt-BR>
		<ko>역병의 계절이 도래하자 궁정의 촉구에 따라 캄루세파의 여사제들이 도착했습니다. 이들은 향초와 향유, 정화의 영창으로 궁전을 청소하며, 지나간 자리는 분위기가 밝아지고 생기가 돌아옵니다. 하지만 여사제들이 떠났음에도 {CHARACTER-2}(은)는 머물고 있습니다. "{TITLE-3}(이)시여, 귀를 기울이십시오. 캄루세파께서는 어떠한 보답도 바라지 않으시지만, 당신은 {CITY-0}의 link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_KAMRUSEPA)에 오셔서 여신을 기리는 의식에 참석하시는 것이 바람직합니다."</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_DISPLEASURE_OF_KAMRUSEPA</zType>
		<en-US>It has been a season of maladies and illness, and the mood is somber as {CHARACTER-2} confronts you at court. "You are not mightier than the gods, O {TITLE-3}. The stink of impiety and corruption surrounds us, and if you do not wish to rot in it, you must humble yourself before Kamrusepa. Come in supplication to the first grand ceremony of {CITY-0}'s link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_KAMRUSEPA), and She might yet have mercy." </en-US>
		<es>Ha sido una temporada de males y dolencias, y el ambiente en la corte es lúgubre cuando {CHARACTER-SHORT-2} te hace frente en la corte:

—No tiene más poder que los dioses, oh, {TITLE-3}. La pestilencia impía y corrupta nos rodea, y si no desea pudrirse en ella, haría bien en mostrar humildad ante Kamrusepa. Venga a suplicar a la primera gran ceremonia en el link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_KAMRUSEPA), de {CITY-0}, y puede que Ella tenga piedad.</es>
		<de>Nach einer Zeit hartnäckiger Krankheiten und Leiden ist die Stimmung gedrückt, als {CHARACTER-2} Euch am Hofe zur Rede stellt. „Ihr seid nicht mächtiger als die Götter, o {TITLE-3}. Der Gestank der Gottlosigkeit und des Verderbens erfüllt die Räume und wenn Ihr nicht darin verrotten wollt, müsst Ihr Euch Kamrušepa gegenüber demütig zeigen. Fleht bei der ersten großen Zeremonie link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_KAMRUSEPA,3) von {CITY-0} um Vergebung und sie mag Euch vielleicht noch Gnade erweisen.“ </de>
		<fr>Une saison de maladies s'éternise et l'humeur est maussade quand {CHARACTER-2} vous confronte à la cour. « Vous n'êtes pas plus fort que les dieux, ô {TITLE-3}. La puanteur de l'impiété et de la corruption nous entoure, et si vous ne souhaitez pas pourrir dans cette atmosphère, il vous faut vous présenter avec humilité devant Kamrusepa. Venez prier à l'occasion de la première grande cérémonie du link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_KAMRUSEPA) à {CITY-0}, et Elle prendra peut-être pitié. » </fr>
		<ja>今季は疫病が流行り、民衆は病魔に悩まされた。宮廷では暗い表情をした{CHARACTER-2}があなたの前に現れる。「{TITLE-3}よ、あなた様の力は神々には及びません。不信心と腐敗の悪臭が我々を取り囲んでいます。その中で腐りたくなければ、カムルセパの前に謙虚にならねばなりません。{CITY-0}のlink(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_KAMRUSEPA)で行われる最初の奉献式にご参加ください。女神様はまだ慈悲を授けてくださるかもしれません」 </ja>
		<zh-TW>這個季節充滿了疾病與病痛，在{CHARACTER-2}於宮廷找你對質時，氣氛十分凝重。「噢，{TITLE-3}，你並不比諸神偉大。褻瀆及腐敗的惡臭將我們包圍，如果你不想要在其中腐朽，你必須在卡姆魯塞帕面前保持謙卑。到{CITY-0}的link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_KAMRUSEPA)的第一場盛大儀式上尋求寬恕，她或許就會心懷慈悲。」 </zh-TW>
		<ru>Болезни и несчастья раздирают наши земли. Мрачные взгляды придворных сопровождают {CHARACTER-2,3} на пути к трону. «Зря мнишь ты себя выше богов, о {choice_GL:царь:царица}, — изрекает {G2:он:она} сухо. — Эти стены пропитаны греховным смрадом. Скоро он поглотит и тебя. Явись в {CITY-0,3}, на церемонию освящения {lowercase:link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_KAMRUSEPA,1)}. Пади на колени и моли богиню о прощении, если желаешь жить!» </ru>
		<zh-CN>这个季节充满了疾病与病痛，在{CHARACTER-2}于宫廷找你对质时，气氛十分凝重。 「噢，{TITLE-3}，你并不比诸神伟大。亵渎及腐败的恶臭将我们包围，如果你不想要在其中腐朽，你必须在卡姆鲁塞帕面前保持谦卑。到{CITY-0}的link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_KAMRUSEPA)的第一场盛大仪式上寻求宽恕，她或许就会心怀慈悲。」 </zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Está sendo uma estação de aflições e doenças, e o clima é tenso quando {CHARACTER-2} lhe confronta na corte: "Você não tem mais poder que os deuses, {TITLE-3,3}. O fedor da impiedade e da corrupção nos cerca, e se você não quiser apodrecer nessas condições, deve submeter-se a Kamrusepa. Venha suplicar na primeira grande cerimônia do link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_KAMRUSEPA) em {CITY-0}, e ela pode ainda lhe demonstrar misericórdia."</pt-BR>
		<ko>역병의 계절이 도래한 침울한 분위기 속에서 {CHARACTER-2}(이)가 궁정에서 당신을 알현합니다. "{TITLE-3}(이)시여, 당신은 신들보다 위대하지 않습니다. 우리를 휘감은 불경함과 부패의 악취 속에서 사그라들기를 원치 않으신다면 캄루세파 앞에 몸을 겸허히 낮추셔야 합니다. 여신께서 아직 자비를 베푸시는 동안 {CITY-0}의 link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_KAMRUSEPA)에서 있을 첫 대제에 참석해 애원하십시오." </ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_BLESSING_OF_HALKI</zType>
		<en-US>In the last days of summer, the mood of the city turns to revelry in impatience for the festivals of harvest, and you catch the distant sounds of song and dance filtering through the walls of the palace. {CHARACTER-2} seems to catch your train of thought, and interjects with a knowing smile "My {TITLE-3}, the people already prepare to thank Halki for the bounty of our harvest, will you not join them? You would have a place of great honor at the sanctification of her link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_HALKI) in {CITY-0}."</en-US>
		<es>En los últimos días estivales, el ambiente en la ciudad se torna festivo por la impaciencia ante los festivales de la cosecha. Alcanzas a oír los sonidos distantes de la música y la danza filtrándose a través de los muros de palacio. {CHARACTER-2} parece leerte el pensamiento e interviene sonriente:

—Mi {TITLE-3}, la gente ya está preparándose para dar las gracias a Halki por una cosecha tan abundante, ¿por qué no se une a ellos? Deberías tener un puesto de honor durante la santificación en su link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_HALKI) en {CITY-0}.</es>
		<de>Während der letzten Sommertage wartet die Stadt ganz ungeduldig auf die Erntedankfestlichkeiten. Der ferne Klang von Tanz und Musik dringt durch die Palastmauern. {CHARACTER-2} scheint zu wissen, was Ihr denkt, und wirft mit einem wissendem Lächeln ein: „{choice_GL:Mein:Meine} {TITLE-3}, das Volk bereitet sich bereits darauf vor, Ḫalki für die reiche Ernte zu danken. Werdet Ihr Euch ihnen nicht anschließen? Ihr würdet einen Ehrenplatz bei der Weihung link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_HALKI,3) in {CITY-0} erhalten.“</de>
		<fr>Dans les derniers jours de l'été, l'humeur de la cité s'égaye dans l'impatience de la fête de la récolte et vous entendez le son lointain des chansons et des danses à travers les murs du palais. {CHARACTER-2} semble lire dans vos pensées et vous interrompt avec un sourire complice : « Ô {TITLE-3}, le peuple se prépare déjà à remercier Halki pour nos récoltes généreuses, n'allez-vous pas vous joindre à eux ? Vous nous feriez un grand honneur en assistant à la sanctification du link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_HALKI) à {CITY-0}. »</fr>
		<ja>夏も終わりに近づくと、街は収穫祭を目前に控えて陽気な雰囲気に包まれ、宮殿の壁伝いに遠くから歌声や踊りの音が聞こえてくる。{CHARACTER-2}はあなたの考えを察したようで、事情は分かっているという様子の笑顔を浮かべながらこう切り出した。「{TITLE-3}よ、人々はハルキに収穫の恵みを感謝するため、すでに収穫祭を開く準備を終えています。あなた様も参加しませんか？祭りは{CITY-0}のlink(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_HALKI)で開かれます。民もあなた様を歓迎することでしょう」</ja>
		<zh-TW>在夏季的最後幾日，城市裡的氛圍變得歡騰，人們都等不及要迎接收穫的慶典，你隱約聽見歌唱及舞蹈的聲音從遠方傳到宮殿來。{CHARACTER-2}似乎領會到你的心思，帶著理解的微笑打岔：「我敬愛的{TITLE-3}，人民已經準備好要感謝哈爾基帶來這次的豐收，你何不加入他們呢？在{CITY-0}的link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_HALKI)有一場聖化儀式，你在那裡一定會受到光榮的款待。」</zh-TW>
		<ru>В последние дни лета в городе царит радостный дух. Горожане веселятся, предвкушая праздники урожая, и песни их слышны даже сквозь толстые каменные стены царского дворца. {CHARACTER-2} понимающе смотрит на вас и с улыбкой говорит: «Твоим подданным не терпится отблагодарить Халки за щедрый урожай. Коль угодно тебе к ним присоединиться, лучше места, чем {lowercase:link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_HALKI,3)} в славном городе {CITY-0,5}, не найти!»</ru>
		<zh-CN>在夏季的最后几日，城市里的氛围变得欢腾，人们都等不及要迎接收获的庆典，你隐约听见歌唱及舞蹈的声音从远方传到宫殿来。 {CHARACTER-2}似乎领会到你的心思，带着理解的微笑打岔：「我敬爱的{TITLE-3}，人民已经准备好要感谢哈尔基带来这次的丰收，你何不加入他们呢？在{CITY-0}的link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_HALKI)有一场圣化仪式，你在那里一定会受到光荣的款待。」</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Nos últimos dias do verão, há um clamor alegre na cidade, uma impaciência pelos festivais da colheita, e você percebe os sons distantes de música e dança mesmo pelas paredes do palácio. {CHARACTER-2} parece notar no que você está pensando e lhe fala com um sorriso conhecedor: "{sentencecase:{TITLE-3,3}}, o povo já está se preparando para agradecer a Halki pela fartura de nossas colheitas, você se juntará a eles? Você seria {choice_GL:recebido:recebida} com muitas honras na santificação do link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_HALKI) em {CITY-0}."</pt-BR>
		<ko>여름이 끝나갈 무렵, 도시의 분위기는 수확 철 축제를 기다리는 갈망의 환락으로 넘실대고 궁전 벽 너머에서 노래와 춤의 소리가 들려옵니다. 그런 당신의 생각을 읽듯 {CHARACTER-2}(이)가 알겠다는 미소를 지으며 불쑥 끼어듭니다. "{TITLE-3}(이)시여, 백성들이 벌써 할키에게 풍년에 감사할 준비를 하고 있으니, 당신도 함께하지 않으시겠습니까? {CITY-0}의 link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_HALKI)에서 여신의 축성을 기리는 영예로운 자리에 참석하시지요."</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_DEDICATION_OF_HALKI</zType>
		<en-US>You watch politely as {CHARACTER-2} performs the seventh augury of the season. {G2:He:She} frowns and turns to you. "My {TITLE-3}, the omens remain unclear, but there are those that fear for the upcoming harvest. I would implore you, seek a boon of Halki, let people and gods see your presence at the dedication of the link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_HALKI) at {CITY-0}." </en-US>
		<es>Observas con educación mientras {CHARACTER-SHORT-2} hace el séptimo augurio de la estación. Frunce el ceño y se vuelve hacia ti:

—Mi {TITLE-3}, los presagios no son claros, pero hay quienes teman por la próxima cosecha. Debo implorarle que busque la bendición de Halki y deje que el pueblo y los dioses vean su presencia en la inauguración del link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_HALKI) en {CITY-0}.</es>
		<de>Ihr seht höflich dabei zu, wie {CHARACTER-2} die siebte Weissagung dieser Jahreszeit leitet. {G2:Er:Sie} runzelt die Stirn und wendet sich an Euch. „{choice_GL:Mein:Meine} {TITLE-3}, die Omen bleiben ungewiss, aber einige fürchten um die nächste Ernte. Ich bitte Euch inständig darum, einen Segen von Ḫalki zu erbeten. Lasst die Menschen und Götter sehen, wie Ihr an der Weihung link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_HALKI,3) bei {CITY-0} teilnehmt.“ </de>
		<fr>Vous observez poliment {CHARACTER-2} réaliser le septième augure de la saison. {G2:Il:Elle} fronce les sourcils et se tourne vers vous. « Ô {TITLE-3}, les présages restent flous, mais certains craignent pour la récolte à venir. Je vous supplie de solliciter la bénédiction de Halki, montrez au peuple et aux dieux votre présence lors de la consécration du link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_HALKI) à {CITY-0}. » </fr>
		<ja>{CHARACTER-2}が今季7回目となる占いの儀式を執り行う中、あなたはそれを礼儀正しく見守る。巫女たちは顔をしかめながら、こちらを向く。「{TITLE-3}よ、お告げはまだはっきりしていません。しかし、次の収穫を心配する人々もいます。ハルキのご加護を授かりましょう。どうか、{CITY-0}のlink(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_HALKI)で行われる奉献式に参加し、人々や神々にあなた様の姿をお見せください」 </ja>
		<zh-TW>你禮貌性地看著{CHARACTER-2}執行本季的第七次占卜。對方皺起眉頭轉向你。「我敬愛的{TITLE-3}，預兆仍未明朗，但有些人為即將到來的收成感到擔憂。我懇請你尋求哈爾基的恩惠，在{CITY-0}的link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_HALKI)奉獻儀式上讓人民和諸神看到你的參與吧。」 </zh-TW>
		<ru>Вы молча созерцаете, как {CHARACTER-2} проводит седьмое гадание сезона. Закончив, {G2:он:она} оборачивается к вам и сухо говорит: «Будущее туманно, {lowercase:{TITLE-3}}. Но многие с опаской ждут сбора урожая. Заклинаю тебя, ступай в {CITY-0,3} на освящение {lowercase:link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_HALKI,1)}. Перед лицом людей и богов попроси у Халки благословение». </ru>
		<zh-CN>你礼貌性地看着{CHARACTER-2}执行本季的第七次占卜。对方皱起眉头转向你。 「我敬爱的{TITLE-3}，预兆仍未明朗，但有些人为即将到来的收成感到担忧。我恳请你寻求哈尔基的恩惠，在{CITY-0}的link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_HALKI)奉献仪式上让人民和诸神看到你的参与吧。」 </zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Você assiste educadamente enquanto {CHARACTER-2} realiza o sétimo augúrio da estação. De cenho franzido, {G0:ele:ela} se volta em sua direção: "{sentencecase:{TITLE-3,3}}, os presságios não estão claros, mas há aqueles que temem pelas próximas colheitas. Eu lhe imploro que procure as bênçãos de Halki, deixe que o povo e os deuses vejam a sua presença na dedicação do link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_HALKI) em {CITY-0}."</pt-BR>
		<ko>당신이 지켜보는 앞에서 이번 계절의 일곱 번째 점술을 시행하는 {CHARACTER-2}(이)가 눈썹을 찌푸리며 당신을 돌아봅니다. "{TITLE-3}(이)시여, 분명한 징조는 아닙니다만, 다가오는 수확 철에 우려되는 기운이 있습니다. 할키의 혜택을 구하시는 것을 간청합니다. {CITY-0}의 link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_HALKI)에서 진행하는 의식에 당신이 참여하시는 모습을 백성들과 신들께 보이십시오." </ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_DISPLEASURE_OF_HALKI</zType>
		<en-US>The rains are late, and the palace swelters amid an uncomfortable heat and rumors of a dire harvest season. {CHARACTER-2} confronts you before the court. "You are not mightier than the gods, O {TITLE-3}. The seeds of your reckless impiety have blossomed, and now the whole realm withers under the wrathful gaze of Halki. Beg her forgiveness as we dedicate the link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_HALKI) in {CITY-0}, or she will yet destroy all you hold dear." </en-US>
		<es>Las lluvias llegan tarde y el ambiente en palacio es sofocante por culpa del calor y los rumores de una temporada de cosecha nefasta. {CHARACTER-2} te hace frente ante la corte:

—No tiene más poder que los dioses, oh, {TITLE-3}. Las semillas de tu temeridad impía han dado sus frutos, y ahora todo el reino se marchita ante la mirada iracunda de Halki. Ruega su perdón durante la ceremonia inaugural en el link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_HALKI) en {CITY-0}, o destruirá todo lo que te importa.</es>
		<de>Der Regen kommt nicht und der Palast kämpft mit einer unangenehmen Hitze und Gerüchten über eine spärliche Ernte. {CHARACTER-2} stellt Euch vor dem Hofstaat zur Rede. „Ihr seid nicht mächtiger als die Götter, o {TITLE-3}. Ihr erntet die Früchte Eurer Gottlosigkeit und nun verwelkt das ganze Reich, während Ḫalki wütend auf uns hinabblickt. Fleht um Vergebung bei der Einweihung link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_HALKI,3) in {CITY-0} oder sie wird noch alles zerstören, was Euch lieb ist.“ </de>
		<fr>Les pluies se font attendre et le palais étouffe sous une chaleur inconfortable alors que se répandent des rumeurs d'une mauvaise saison de récoltes. {CHARACTER-2} vous confronte devant la cour. « Vous n'êtes pas plus fort que les dieux, ô {TITLE-3}. Les graines de votre impiété imprudente ont germé et désormais, le royaume tout entier se flétrit sous le regard furieux de Halki. Implorez son pardon pendant que nous consacrons le link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_HALKI) à {CITY-0}, ou elle détruira tout ce qui vous est cher. » </fr>
		<ja>雨がなかなか降らず、不快な暑さで宮廷の中は蒸し風呂のような状態だ。今季は収穫量も少ないとの噂が流れている。宮廷では、{CHARACTER-2}が姿を現す。「{TITLE-3}よ、あなた様の力は神々には及びません。あなた様が神々を敬わず、その不信心な行為を悔い改めなかったため、神々がお怒りになったのです。ハルキの怒りに満ちた眼差しの下で、すべての土地が枯れようとしています。{CITY-0}のlink(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_HALKI)で行われる奉献式で許しを請うのです。さもなければ、女神様はあなた様が愛するものをすべて破壊していまうでしょう。 </ja>
		<zh-TW>雨季晚了，令人不適的高溫和歉收的謠言使整個宮殿煩躁不已。{CHARACTER-2}在朝臣前向你對質。「噢，{TITLE-3}，你並不比諸神偉大。你張狂的褻瀆種下的種子已經開花，現在整個王國都在哈爾基憤怒的注視下逐漸枯萎。在我們於{CITY-0}的link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_HALKI)舉辦奉獻儀式時，你去請求她的原諒吧，不然她會摧毀你珍視的一切。」 </zh-TW>
		<ru>Сезон дождей задерживается, порождая слухи о скудном урожае, распаляющие и без того непереносимый зной. {CHARACTER-2} врывается в тронный зал и в присутствии млеющих придворных и слуг гневно восклицает: «Ты мнишь себя выше богов, {lowercase:{TITLE-3}}! Взросли семена твоей порочности, и теперь все вокруг увядает под палящим взором Халки. Иди в {CITY-0,3}, на освящение {lowercase:link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_HALKI,1)} и проси у богини прощения. Иначе все, что дорого тебе, сгорит в ее праведном пламени!» </ru>
		<zh-CN>雨季晚了，令人不适的高温和歉收的谣言使整个宫殿烦躁不已。 {CHARACTER-2}在朝臣前向你对质。 「噢，{TITLE-3}，你并不比诸神伟大。你张狂的亵渎种下的种子已经开花，现在整个王国都在哈尔基愤怒的注视下逐渐枯萎。在我们于{CITY-0}的link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_HALKI)举办奉献仪式时，你去请求她的原谅吧，不然她会摧毁你珍视的一切。」 </zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>As chuvas estão atrasadas e o palácio está sufocado pelo calor desconfortável e com os rumores de uma terrível estação de colheitas. {CHARACTER-2} lhe confronta perante a corte. "Você não tem mais poder que os deuses, {TITLE-3,3}. A sua heresia imprudente deu frutos e agora todo o reino murcha sob o olhar irado de Halki. Implore pelo perdão dela na dedicação do link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_HALKI) em {CITY-0}, ou ela irá destruir tudo que você preza."</pt-BR>
		<ko>비가 좀체 오지 않자 궁전은 불쾌한 더위로 푹푹 찌고 올해는 흉년이라는 소문이 퍼지고 있습니다. {CHARACTER-2}(이)가 궁정에서 당신을 알현합니다. "{TITLE-3}(이)시여, 당신은 신들보다 위대하지 않습니다. 당신의 무모한 불경함이 싹을 틔웠고, 이제 할키의 분노한 눈빛 아래 온 나라가 시들고 있습니다. 여신께서 당신의 소중한 모든 것을 파괴하기 전에 {CITY-0}의 link(IMPROVEMENT_SHRINE_HALKI)에 봉헌하여 용서를 구하십시오." </ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_THE_SALT_OF_THE_EARTH</zType>
		<en-US>As our first royal caravan makes ready to set out for distant lands, the merchants appointed to lead the expedition insist that link(RESOURCE_SALT), so common around {CITY-0}, is considered a luxury and quite valuable in foreign land. They argue that we should consider it an important trade good.</en-US>
		<es>En lo que nuestra primera caravana real se prepara para partir a tierras lejanas, los mercaderes encargados de liderarla insisten en que la link(RESOURCE_SALT), un recurso tan común en {CITY-0}, es un lujo muy valioso en el extranjero. Te piden que la tengas en cuenta como bien comerciable importante.</es>
		<de>Während sich unsere erste königliche Karawane bereitmacht, in ferne Länder aufzubrechen, beharren die für die Expedition auserkorenen Händler darauf, dass link(RESOURCE_SALT) – eine alltägliche Ware in {CITY-0} – im Ausland ein wertvoller Luxus ist. Ihrer Meinung nach handelt es sich deshalb um ein wichtiges Handelsgut.</de>
		<fr>Alors que notre première caravane royale s'apprête à débuter son voyage vers des terres lointaines, les marchands désignés pour mener l'expédition insistent que le link(RESOURCE_SALT), si commun aux alentours {CITY-0,1}, est considéré comme une ressource de luxe se vendant cher dans les contrées étrangères. Ils sont convaincus que nous devrions le considérer comme une importante ressource d'échanges.</fr>
		<ja>王室が支援する第一キャラバン隊は、遠方へ旅立つための準備を行っていた。遠征隊を率いることになった商人たちによれば、{CITY-0}ではありふれたlink(RESOURCE_SALT)が、異国の地では贅沢品として扱われ、極めて貴重な資源になるという。彼らはそれを貿易資源と見なすべきだと主張している。</ja>
		<zh-TW>在我們的第一支皇家商隊準備前往遙遠的國度時，被指派為遠征隊領袖的商人堅持主張{CITY-0}附近常見的link(RESOURCE_SALT)在異國被視為高價的奢侈品。他們主張我們應該考慮把它當作重要的貿易物品。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Совсем скоро в далекое странствие выйдет первый царский караван. Купцы, ответственные за экспедицию, заверяют вас, что там, куда они направляются, невероятно ценится {lowercase:link(RESOURCE_SALT)}. А поскольку в {CITY-0,3} соли в достатке, она может считаться нашим важнейшим ресурсом.</ru>
		<zh-CN>在我们的第一支皇家商队准备前往遥远的国度时，被指派为远征队领袖的商人坚持主张{CITY-0}附近常见的link(RESOURCE_SALT)在异国被视为高价的奢侈品。他们主张我们应该考虑把它当作重要的贸易物品。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Enquanto preparamos nossa primeira caravana real para partir a terras distantes, os mercadores encarregados de liderar a expedição insistem que o link(RESOURCE_SALT), um produto tão comum perto de {CITY-0}, é considerado um luxo de bastante valor em terras estrangeiras. Eles argumentam que nós devemos considerá-lo um bem importante para o comércio.</pt-BR>
		<ko>첫 왕실 행상단이 머나먼 땅으로 떠날 준비를 하는 동안, 탐사를 이끌 상인들은 {CITY-0} 주변에 흔한 link(RESOURCE_SALT)이 타국의 사치품이자 상당히 가치 있는 물품으로 여겨진다고 역설합니다. 그러면서 우리가 그것을 주요 교역 상품으로 간주해야 한다고 주장합니다.</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_GREATEST_CAVALRY_BATTLE_OF_ALL_TIMES_HITTITES</zType>
		<en-US>Today was a glorious day for the {PLAYER-0,1}!

The accursed {PLAYER-1,3} were marching their innumerable cavalry hosts to threaten our land and our people.
We misled them, lured them close to {CITY-5}, where the {TITLE-4} had mustered our glorious chariotry. Only too late did they realize their mistake!
We struck like thunder and terror filled their hearts. {CHARACTER-4} was like Tarhun before them! We scattered their warriors like chaff in the wind, routed their vaunted army and plundered their camp. Their {TITLE-8} barely escaped with {G8:his:her} life!

Their numberless horde was defeated and they had to retreat. {CITY-5} is safe and we won the largest chariot battle the world has ever seen!</en-US>
		<es>¡Hoy ha sido un día glorioso para los {PLAYER-0,3}!

Los canallas de los {PLAYER-1,3} han estado marchando con su innumerable caballería, amenazando nuestras tierras y a nuestro pueblo. Les tendimos una trampa para atraerlos cerca de {CITY-5}, donde {TITLE-4,1} tiene acuartelados a nuestros gloriosos carros.

¡Cayeron en la cuenta de su error demasiado tarde! Golpeamos raudos como el relámpago y sembramos el terror en sus corazones. ¡{CHARACTER-4} parecía el mismísimo Tarhu! Los guerreros enemigos huyeron como ratas, derrotamos a su ejército y saqueamos su campamento. ¡Su {TITLE-8} escapó con vida por los pelos!

Su horda inconmensurable cayó derrotada y tuvo que huir. ¡{CITY-5} está a salvo y nos hemos alzado con la victoria en la mayor batalla de carros que el mundo haya visto!</es>
		<de>Heute war ein glorreicher Tag für die {PLAYER-0,11}!

Die verhassten {PLAYER-1,11} nahten mit ihrer mächtigen Kavallerie heran, um unser Land und Volk zu bedrohen.
Wir haben sie getäuscht, indem wir sie nach {CITY-5} gelockt haben, wo die herrliche Streitwageneinheit {TITLE-4,1} wartete. Sie bemerkten ihren Fehler zu spät!
Wir schlugen zu wie der Blitz und säten Angst in ihren Herzen. {CHARACTER-4} stand vor ihnen wie Tarḫunna! Wir zerstreuten sie wie die Spreu im Wind, schlugen ihre viel gerühmte Armee und plünderten ihr Lager. {G8:Ihr:Ihre} {TITLE-8} kam nur knapp mit dem Leben davon!

Ihre endlose Horde wurde besiegt und sie mussten sich zurückziehen. {CITY-5} ist sicher und wir haben den größten Streitwagenkampf der Welt gewonnen!</de>
		<fr>Aujourd'hui a été un jour glorieux pour {PLAYER-0}৺ !

Les maudits {PLAYER-1,6} dirigeaient leur armée d'innombrables cavaliers pour menacer notre territoire et notre peuple.
Nous les avons induits en erreur, nous les avons attirés près {CITY-5,1}, où notre {TITLE-4} avait rassemblé nos glorieux chars de guerre. Ils ne se sont rendu compte que bien trop tard de leur erreur !
Nous les avons frappés comme le tonnerre, et avons rempli leurs cœurs de terreur. {CHARACTER-4} était comme Tarhun devant eux ! Nous avons dispersé leurs guerriers comme de la paille au vent, mis leur armée tant vantée en déroute et pillé leur campement. Leur {TITLE-8} a même failli y laisser sa peau !

Leur horde innombrable a été vaincue et ils ont dû battre en retraite. {CITY-5} est sauve et nous avons remporté la plus grande bataille de chars que le monde a connu !</fr>
		<ja>今日は{PLAYER-0,1}にとって輝かしい一日となった。

忌むべき{PLAYER-1,3}は、数え切れないほどの騎馬隊を進軍させ、我が国と我が国民を脅かしていた。
我々は奴らを欺き、{CITY-5}の近郊に誘い込むことに成功した。そこには{TITLE-4}が我々の誇る優秀な戦車を集結させていた。奴らはその間違いに気づくのがあまりにも遅すぎた。
我々は雷のように襲いかかり、奴らの心を恐怖で満たした。{CHARACTER-4}は、まるでタルフンの如く勇敢に戦った。奴らの戦士は風の中の籾殻のように散り散りなって逃げた。我々は奴らの自慢の軍隊を撃退し、駐留地を略奪した。{TITLE-8}も逃げるのがやっとだった。

敵の大群は敗れ、撤退を余儀なくされた。{CITY-5}はもう安全だ。我々は史上最大の戦車戦に勝利したのだ！</ja>
		<zh-TW>今天對{PLAYER-0,1}來說是個光榮的一天！

可惡的{PLAYER-1,3}當時正在帶領無數的騎兵隊來威脅我們的領土及人民。
我們誤導了他們，引誘他們到{CITY-5}附近，而{TITLE-4}已經事先在那裡部署了我們光榮的戰車。他們意識到犯錯時已經太遲了！
我們像雷一樣迅速攻擊，讓恐懼充滿了他們的內心。{CHARACTER-4}在他們面前就像塔爾亨一樣！我們迫使他們的戰士像米糠一樣在風中四散、擊潰了他們自滿的軍隊並掠奪了他們的軍營。他們的{TITLE-8}在逃走前差點連命都丟了！

他們無數的部隊被我們擊敗，最後不得不撤退。{CITY-5}安全了，我們也在史上最大規模的戰車戰役中獲得勝利！</zh-TW>
		<ru>Сегодня знаменательный день в истории {PLAYER-0,1}!

На наши земли посягнули поганые {lowercase:{PLAYER-1,12}}.
Коннице их не было числа, но мы оказались хитрее: заманили супостата к {CITY-5,2}, где уже ждала наша кавалерия под началом {G4:великого:великой} {lowercase:{TITLE-4,1}}. Когда они поняли, что попали в ловушку, было слишком поздно!
Мы обрушились на них с яростью бури. {CHARACTER-4} {G4:был:была} воплощением самого Тархунта! Мы прорвали их строй, обратили воинов в бегство и разграбили вражеский лагерь. {TITLE-8} едва {G8:унес:унесла} ноги!

Мы разбили их несчетную орду, спасли {CITY-5,3} и одержали победу в величайшем конном сражении в истории человечества!</ru>
		<zh-CN>今天对{PLAYER-0,1}来说是个光荣的一天！

可恶的{PLAYER-1,3}当时正在带领无数的骑兵队来威胁我们的领土及人民。
我们误导了他们，引诱他们到{CITY-5}附近，而{TITLE-4}已经事先在那里部署了我们光荣的战车。他们意识到犯错时已经太迟了！
我们像雷一样迅速攻击，让恐惧充满了他们的内心。 {CHARACTER-4}在他们面前就像塔尔亨一样！我们迫使他们的战士像米糠一样在风中四散、击溃了他们自满的军队并掠夺了他们的军营。他们的{TITLE-8}在逃走前差点连命都丢了！

他们无数的部队被我们击败，最后不得不撤退。 {CITY-5}安全了，我们也在史上最大规模的战车战役中获得胜利！</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Hoje foi um dia glorioso para os {PLAYER-0,3}!
 
Os malditos {PLAYER-1,3} estavam marchando com suas infindáveis cavalarias para ameaçar nossas terras e nosso povo.
 Nós os enganamos, os atraímos para perto de {CITY-5}, onde {TITLE-4,1} havia reunido nossas gloriosas bigas. Eles só perceberam que fora um erro tarde demais!
 Nós atacamos como raios e o terror os tomou completamente. {CHARACTER-4} parecia o próprio Tarhun ante eles! Nós espalhamos os guerreiros deles como cinzas ao vento, perseguimos o pomposo exército e saqueamos seus campos. {sentencecase:{TITLE-8,1}} deles mal escapou com vida!
 
A horda incontável foi derrotada e eles tiveram que se retirar. {CITY-5} está segura e nós vencemos a maior batalha entre carros que o mundo já viu!</pt-BR>
		<ko>오늘은 {PLAYER-0,1}에 있어 영광스러운 날입니다!

가증스러운 {PLAYER-1,3} 놈들이 우리 땅과 백성들을 유린하기 위해 셀 수 없이 많은 기병 부대를 이끌고 진군하고 있었습니다.
우리는 그들을 꾀어내어 {TITLE-4}(이)가 우리의 영광스러운 전차 부대를 집결한 {CITY-5}까지 유인했습니다. 적들은 자신의 실수를 너무 늦게 깨달았습니다!
우리는 천둥처럼 공격했고, 저들의 마음에는 공포가 들어찼습니다. {CHARACTER-4}(은)는 놈들에게 타르훈과도 같은 존재였던 것입니다! 우리는 적 전사들을 바람에 날린 겨처럼 흩어 버렸으며, 그들의 군세를 몰아내고 주둔지를 파괴했습니다. {TITLE-8}(은)는 목숨만 겨우 부지했고요!

적의 수많은 병력은 패배와 함께 후퇴해야 했습니다. {CITY-5}(은)는 이제 안전하며, 우리는 지금껏 없었던 역사상 최대 규모의 기병전에서 승리했습니다!</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_GREATEST_CAVALRY_BATTLE_OF_ALL_TIMES_EGYPTIANS</zType>
		<en-US>Today was a glorious day for {PLAYER-0}!
Near {CITY-6} the vile {PLAYER-1,3} and their numberless cavalry ambushed the royal column and tried to take by treachery what they couldn't obtain through valor.
They routed our warriors and isolated our {TITLE-4}, who was deserted and surrounded by enemies. The greedy {PLAYER-1,3} thought they had won and were plundering our camp. They thought they were celebrating victory!

But, at the darkest hour, Amun master of victory came to our {TITLE-4}. {CHARACTER-4} was before them like Set in his moment! The army rallied around {G4:him:her} and charged again!
The {TITLE-4} chased the {PLAYER-1,3} from our camp and slaughtered a great many of them. They scattered before us, abandoning their chariots to flee across rivers, dispersing as fast as swimming crocodiles!

In spite of the {PLAYER-1,3}'s treachery, today we won the largest chariot battle the world has ever seen!</en-US>
		<es>¡Hoy ha sido un día glorioso para {PLAYER-0}!

Cerca de {CITY-6}, los viles {PLAYER-1,3} y su incontable caballería tendieron una emboscada a la columna real e intentaron obtener a traición lo que no pudieron conseguir mediante el valor. Derrotaron a nuestros guerreros y aislaron a {G4:nuestro:nuestra} {TITLE-4}, que había huido y se encontraba {G4:rodeado:rodeada} por el enemigo. Los {PLAYER-1,3}, tan avariciosos como siempre, se pensaban que ya habían ganado y estaban saqueando nuestro campamento. ¡Se atrevían a celebrar la victoria!

Pero, en el momento más crítico, Amón, el maestro de la victoria, acudió a {G4:nuestro:nuestra} {TITLE-4}. ¡{CHARACTER-4} se alzó como Set ante ellos! El ejército se reunió a su alrededor y cargó de vuelta!

{TITLE-4,1} persiguió a los {PLAYER-1,3} en nuestro campamento y masacró a una buena parte de ellos. ¡Huyeron despavoridos, abandonando sus carros para cruzar ríos y dispersándose tan rápido como los cocodrilos!

¡Pese a la traición de {PLAYER-1}, hoy nos hemos alzado con la victoria en la batalla de carros más grande que se haya visto jamás!</es>
		<de>Heute war ein glorreicher Tag für {PLAYER-0,3}!
Die abscheulichen {PLAYER-1,11} und ihre unzähligen berittenen Einheiten überfielen die königliche Kolonne bei {CITY-6} und versuchten, durch einen Hinterhalt zu erreichen, was sie nicht durch Tapferkeit vermochten.
Sie schlugen unsere Krieger in die Flucht, sodass sich {G4:unser:unsere} {TITLE-4} allein und umzingelt von Feinden wiederfand. Die gierigen {PLAYER-1,11} dachten, sie hätten gewonnen und plünderten unser Lager. Sie waren der Meinung, sie feierten einen Triumph!

Doch in dieser dunkelsten Stunde kam Amun, Meister des Sieges, {G4:unserem:unserer} {TITLE-4} zur Hilfe. {CHARACTER-4} stand vor ihnen wie Seth in seinem Augenblick des Erfolgs! Die Soldaten sammelte sich um {G4:ihn:sie} und griffen erneut an!
{G4:Der:Die} {TITLE-4} vertrieb die {PLAYER-1,11} aus unserem Lager und tötete dabei etliche. Sie zerstreuten sich vor uns, ließen ihre Streitwagen zurück, um durch die Flüsse zu flüchten, als wären sie Krokodile!

Trotz der Hinterlist der {PLAYER-1,11} haben wir heute den größten Streitwagenkampf der Welt gewonnen!</de>
		<fr>Aujourd'hui a été un jour glorieux pour {PLAYER-0} !
Près {CITY-6,1} les vils {PLAYER-1,6} et leurs innombrables cavaliers ont tendu une embuscade à notre colonne royale et ont tenté de prendre par la perfidie ce qu'ils ne pouvaient pas obtenir par le courage.
Ils ont mis en déroute nos guerriers et isolé notre {TITLE-4}, qui s'est {G4:retrouvé seul et encerclé:retrouvée seule et encerclée} d'ennemis. Les {PLAYER-1,6} avides ont alors cru qu'ils avaient gagné et se sont mis à piller notre campement. Ils pensaient célébrer la victoire !

Mais, en cette heure sombre, Amon le maître de la victoire est apparu à notre {TITLE-4}. {CHARACTER-4} était comme Seth face à eux en cet instant ! L'armée s'est ralliée à {G4:lui:elle} et a chargé de nouveau !
Notre {TITLE-4} a poursuivi les {PLAYER-1,6} en dehors de notre campement et a massacré une grande partie d'entre eux. Ils se sont dispersés devant nous, abandonnant leur chars de guerre pour prendre la fuite, traversant les rivières aussi vite que des crocodiles !

Malgré la perfidie des {PLAYER-1,6}, nous avons aujourd'hui remporté la plus grande bataille de chars que le monde a connu !</fr>
		<ja>今日は{PLAYER-0}にとって輝かしい一日となった。
卑劣な{PLAYER-1,3}とその無数の騎兵隊は、{CITY-6}近郊で我が王家の隊列を待ち伏せた。武力ではかなわないからといって、卑怯な手段を用い、勝利を得ようとしたのだ。
奴らは我々の戦士を撃退し、孤立した{TITLE-4}を取り囲むことに成功した。強欲な{PLAYER-1,3}は自分たちの勝利を確信し、我々の駐留地を略奪し始めた。奴らとしては勝利を祝っているつもりだった。

しかし最も厳しい状況下で、勝利の主アムンが{TITLE-4}の前に現れた。{CHARACTER-4}はまるでセトのように奴らと戦った。軍隊は{G4:彼:彼女}の周りに結集し、再び突撃した。
{TITLE-4}は{PLAYER-1,3}を駐留地から追い払い、大勢の兵士を虐殺した。奴らは戦車を捨て、川を渡って逃げ去り、まるで泳ぐ鰐のように素早く散っていった。

{PLAYER-1,3}の裏切りにも屈せず、今日我々は史上最大の戦車戦に勝利したのだ！</ja>
		<zh-TW>今天對{PLAYER-0}來說是個光榮的一天！
在{CITY-6}附近，卑鄙的{PLAYER-1,3}和他們無數的騎兵突襲了皇家列隊，試著以狡詐奪取無法用英勇換得的東西。
他們擊敗了我們的戰士並孤立了我們的{TITLE-4}，使其被敵人包圍無援。貪心的{PLAYER-1,3}以為他們已經獲勝，開始掠奪我們的營地。他們還以為自己在慶祝勝利呢！

然而，在情勢最險峻的時刻，勝利之主阿蒙眷顧了我們的{TITLE-4}。{CHARACTER-4}像賽特當年一樣出現在他們面前！軍隊在{G4:他:她}周圍集結然後再次進攻！
{TITLE-4}從我們的軍營追擊{PLAYER-1,3}，並殺死許多敵人。他們在我們眼前四處逃竄，拋下戰車逃過河流，像游泳的鱷魚一般落荒而逃！

雖然{PLAYER-1,3}背叛了我們，但我們今天在史上最大規模的戰車戰役中獲得了勝利！</zh-TW>
		<ru>Сегодня знаменательный день в истории {PLAYER-0,1}!
Вероломные {lowercase:{PLAYER-1,12}}, понимая, что в честном бою им не победить, обрушили всю мощь своей конницы на царский конвой, проходивший возле {CITY-6,1}.
Они прорвали наши ряды, обратили воинов в бегство и окружили {lowercase:{TITLE-4,3}}. Опьяненные алчностью, {lowercase:{PLAYER-1,12}} бросились грабить наш лагерь. Они думали, что победили!

Но в самый темный час несокрушимый Амон пришел на помощь {G4:нашему:нашей} {lowercase:{TITLE-4,2}}. {CHARACTER-4} {G4:был:была} воплощением Сета. {G4:Он сплотил:Она сплотила} павших духом воинов и {G4:повел:повела} их в атаку.
{TITLE-4} {G4:выдворил:выдворила} {lowercase:{PLAYER-1,13}} из нашего лагеря. Эти трусы побросали мечи и колесницы и бросились врассыпную!
Несмотря на предательство {PLAYER-1,1} мы одержали победу в величайшем конном сражении в истории!</ru>
		<zh-CN>今天对{PLAYER-0}来说是个光荣的一天！
在{CITY-6}附近，卑鄙的{PLAYER-1,3}和他们无数的骑兵突袭了皇家列队，试着以狡诈夺取无法用英勇换得的东西。
他们击败了我们的战士并孤立了我们的{TITLE-4}，使其被敌人包围无援。贪心的{PLAYER-1,3}以为他们已经获胜，开始掠夺我们的营地。他们还以为自己在庆祝胜利呢！

然而，在情势最险峻的时刻，胜利之主阿蒙眷顾了我们的{TITLE-4}。 {CHARACTER-4}像赛特当年一样出现在他们面前！军队在{G4:他:她}周围集结然后再次进攻！
{TITLE-4}从我们的军营追击{PLAYER-1,3}，并杀死许多敌人。他们在我们眼前四处逃窜，抛下战车逃过河流，像游泳的鳄鱼一般落荒而逃！

虽然{PLAYER-1,3}背叛了我们，但我们今天在史上最大规模的战车战役中获得了胜利！</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Hoje foi um dia glorioso para os {PLAYER-0,4}!
Perto de {CITY-6}, os terríveis {PLAYER-1,3} e sua cavalaria sem fim emboscaram a coluna real e tentaram tomar com sua perfídia o que não conseguiram vencer com coragem.
 Eles encalçaram nossos guerreiros e isolaram {G4:nosso:nossa} {TITLE-4}, que ficou {G4:ilhado e cercado:ilhada e cercada} de inimigos. Os gananciosos {PLAYER-1,3} pensaram que tinham vencido e já estavam saqueando nossos campos, eles pensaram que iriam celebrar a vitória.
 
Mas, no momento mais desesperador, Ámon, o mestre da vitória interviu junto {G4:ao nosso:à nossa} {TITLE-4}. {CHARACTER-4} se pôs diante deles como Set em sua glória! O exército se reuniu ao seu lado e atacaram novamente! {sentencecase:{TITLE-4,1}} expulsou os {PLAYER-1,3} de nosso campo e matou muitos mais. Eles se espalharam diante de nós, deixando até mesmo seus carros para fugir pelos rios como crocodilos!
 
A despeito de quão traiçoeiros são os {PLAYER-1,3}, hoje nós vencemos a maior batalha entre carros que o mundo já viu!</pt-BR>
		<ko>오늘은 {PLAYER-0}에 있어 영광스러운 날입니다!
{CITY-6} 근처에 사악한 {PLAYER-1,3} 놈들과 그들의 셀 수 없이 많은 기병 부대가 부족한 용기 대신 배신을 통해 이기려고 왕실 행렬을 급습했습니다.
그들은 우리 전사들을 몰아냈고 {TITLE-4}(은)는 적들 사이에 고립되었습니다. 탐욕스러운 {PLAYER-1,3} 놈들은 자신들이 승리했다고 착각하고 우리의 주둔지를 약탈하고 있었습니다. 승리를 축하할 수 있을 줄 알았던 것입니다!

하지만 가장 어두운 때 승리의 주인이신 아문께서 {TITLE-4} 앞에 강림하셨습니다. 그 순간 {CHARACTER-4}(은)는 적들에게 세트와도 같은 존재로 변한 것입니다! 우리의 군대가 그분 주위로 집결해 다시 돌격했으니까요!
{TITLE-4}(은)는 우리 주둔지에서 {PLAYER-1,3}을 몰아내고 그중 상당수를 학살했습니다. 놈들은 우리 앞에서 뿔뿔이 흩어졌으며, 전차를 버리고 강을 건너 도망친 다음 헤엄치는 악어처럼 사라졌습니다!

비록 {PLAYER-1,3}의 배신이 있었지만, 오늘 우리는 지금껏 없었던 역사상 최대 규모의 기병전에서 승리했습니다!</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_WORTHY_OPPONENTS_PEACE_OFFER</zType>
		<en-US>The {PLAYER-0,3} sent us a delegation, offering a particularly favorable peace treaty. They were durably impressed by our military prowess during our great cavalry battle.

They even suggest we exchange combat training techniques as a sign of respect between our nations!</en-US>
		<es>Los {PLAYER-0,3} nos han enviado una oferta por medio de una delegación: un tratado de paz ciertamente favorable. Quedaron impresionados por nuestra destreza militar durante nuestra gran batalla de caballería.

¡Incluso sugieren que intercambiemos técnicas de instrucción de combate como símbolo de respeto entre nuestras naciones!</es>
		<de>Die {PLAYER-0,11} haben eine Delegation entsendet, die uns einen besonders vorteilhaften Friedensvertrag verspricht. Sie waren tief beeindruckt von unserer militärischen Stärke während unseres großen Kavalleriegefechts.

Sie schlagen sogar vor, als Zeichen des Respekts zwischen unseren Nationen Kampftechniken auszutauschen!</de>
		<fr>Les {PLAYER-0,6} nous ont envoyé une délégation, nous offrant un traité de paix particulièrement favorable. Ils ont été durablement impressionnés par nos aptitudes militaires lors de notre grande bataille de cavaleries.

Ils suggèrent même que nous échangions des techniques d'entraînement au combat en signe de respect entre nos nations !</fr>
		<ja>{PLAYER-0,3}が使節団を送り、我々にとって極めて有利な講和条約を申し出てきた。彼らは、騎兵隊同士の大戦闘を通じ、我が国の武勇に強い感銘を受けたのである。

さらに、国家間の信頼関係の証として、戦闘訓練の技術を共有しようという提案まで行ってきた。</ja>
		<zh-TW>{PLAYER-0,3}向我們派出代表，提出一個對我們特別有利的和平條款。在我們大規模的騎兵戰役中，他們對我們的軍事實力印象非常深刻。

他們甚至建議我們交換戰鬥訓練技巧，作為國家之間互相尊敬的象徵！</zh-TW>
		<ru>Во дворец прибывает {lowercase:{PLAYER-0,30}} делегация с весьма выгодным предложением мира. Судя по всему, наши воины произвели сильнейшее впечатление во время большого конного сражения.

{PLAYER-0,12} даже предлагают провести совместные военные учения в знак уважения между нациями.</ru>
		<zh-CN>{PLAYER-0,3}向我们派出代表，提出一个对我们特别有利的和平条款。在我们大规模的骑兵战役中，他们对我们的军事实力印象非常深刻。

他们甚至建议我们交换战斗训练技巧，作为国家之间互相尊敬的象征！</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Os {PLAYER-0,3} enviaram uma delegação para oferecer um tratado de paz particularmente favorável a nós. Eles ficaram devidamente impressionados com nossa destreza militar durante a nossa grande batalha de cavalaria.
 
Eles até mesmo sugeriram que compartilhemos técnicas de treinamento para combate como um sinal de respeito entre nossas nações!</pt-BR>
		<ko>{PLAYER-0,3}이 대표단을 보내 우리에게 훨씬 유리한 평화 조약을 제안했습니다. 이번 기병 부대 간의 대전투에서 우리 군대의 무용에 굉장한 감명을 받은 것입니다.

심지어 그들은 존중의 뜻으로 국가 간에 군사 기술을 교환하자고 제의합니다.</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_WORTHY_OPPONENTS_TRUCE</zType>
		<en-US>The {PLAYER-0,3} sent us a truce parley. Respectful of the military skills we demonstrated, they suggest that our people need not shed any more blood to prove their valor on the field.

They came with gifts as a sign of benevolence and respect.</en-US>
		<es>Los {PLAYER-0,3} nos han enviado una oferta de tregua. Se muestran respetuosos ante nuestra destreza militar y sugieren que nuestros pueblos no deberían derramar más sangre para demostrar su valor.

Han venido con regalos como muestra de su benevolencia y su respeto.</es>
		<de>Die {PLAYER-0,11} wollen mit uns einen Waffenstillstand aushandeln. Sie haben großen Respekt vor dem militärischen Können, das wir demonstriert haben, und meinen, unser Volk müsse kein Blut mehr vergießen, um seine Tapferkeit auf dem Schlachtfeld zu beweisen.

Sie bringen Geschenke als ein Zeichen des Wohlwollens und der Achtung.</de>
		<fr>Les {PLAYER-0,6} ont engagé des négociations de trêve. Respectant les compétences militaires dont nous avons fait preuve, ils suggèrent que notre peuple n'a pas besoin de faire couler davantage de sang sur le champ de bataille pour prouver sa valeur.

Ils sont venus avec des présents en signe de bienfaisance et de respect.</fr>
		<ja>{PLAYER-0,3}から休戦協定の申し出を受けた。彼らは我々が見せた軍事技術に敬意を表し、戦争を終結させて、戦場における我が国の武勇を認めようと申し出ている。

善意と敬意を表すために、彼らは贈り物を用意しているようだ。</ja>
		<zh-TW>{PLAYER-0,3}派人來進行休戰和談。他們對我們展現出的軍事技巧相當敬佩，並建議說，我們的人民不需要再流任何血來證明他們在戰場上的英勇。

他們帶著禮物前來，作為善意及尊重的象徵。</zh-TW>
		<ru>{PLAYER-0,12} прислали делегацию на переговоры о перемирии. Они признают нашу военную мощь и отвагу воинов, проливавших кровь на поле битвы.

В знак добрых намерений они преподносят нам дары.</ru>
		<zh-CN>{PLAYER-0,3}派人来进行休战和谈。他们对我们展现出的军事技巧相当敬佩，并建议说，我们的人民不需要再流任何血来证明他们在战场上的英勇。

他们带着礼物前来，作为善意及尊重的象征。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Os {PLAYER-0,3} nos enviaram uma proposta de trégua. Com respeito pelas habilidades militares que demonstramos, eles sugerem que nosso povo não precisa mais derramar nosso sangue para demonstrar nosso valor em batalha.
 
Eles oferecem presentes como sinal de benevolência e respeito.</pt-BR>
		<ko>{PLAYER-0,3}이 휴전 협상을 제안했습니다. 우리가 보여 준 군사 기술을 존중하며, 우리 백성들이 전장에서 용맹을 증명하기 위해 피를 더 흘릴 필요가 없다는 말을 꺼냅니다.

그들은 자비와 존경의 뜻을 담은 선물도 가져왔습니다.</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_HITTITE_CONTACT_BABYLON_KINGMAKERS</zType>
		<en-US>We've just made contact with the {PLAYER-0,3} again. In times past, a {PLAYER-2} king sacked {CITY-3} and installed the {FAMILY-3,3} as rulers of their capital and kingdom.</en-US>
		<es>Acabamos de contactar con los {PLAYER-0,3} de nuevo. En el pasado, un rey {PLAYER-2,1} saqueó {CITY-3} y puso a los {FAMILY-3,1} a gobernar la capital y el reino.</es>
		<de>Wir sind gerade wieder in Kontakt mit {PLAYER-0,2}. In der Vergangenheit hat ein König {PLAYER-2,1} {CITY-3} geplündert und die {FAMILY-3,1} zu den Herrschern der Hauptstadt und des Reiches gemacht.</de>
		<fr>Nous venons de rétablir le contact avec les {PLAYER-0,6}. Par le passé, un roi {PLAYER-2,3} avait mis à sac {CITY-3} et installé les {FAMILY-3} comme les dirigeants de leur capitale et royaume.</fr>
		<ja>再び{PLAYER-0,3}と接触した。その昔、{PLAYER-2}の王が{CITY-3}を略奪し、{FAMILY-3,3}を首都と王国の支配者として据えたという歴史がある。</ja>
		<zh-TW>我們剛才又再次和{PLAYER-0,3}取得了聯繫。在過去的期間，{PLAYER-2}國王劫掠了{CITY-3}，並指派{FAMILY-3,3}成為他們首都及王國的統治者。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Мы только что снова встретились с {lowercase:{PLAYER-0,16}}. Когда-то в прошлом король {PLAYER-2,1} разграбил {CITY-3,3} и передал столицу и все царство в руки семьи {FAMILY-3,7}.</ru>
		<zh-CN>我们刚才又再次和{PLAYER-0,3}取得了联系。在过去的期间，{PLAYER-2}国王劫掠了{CITY-3}，并指派{FAMILY-3,3}成为他们首都及王国的统治者。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Nós acabamos de fazer contato com os {PLAYER-0,3} novamente. No passado, um rei {PLAYER-0,1} saqueou {PLAYER-2} e instaurou os {FAMILY-3,1} como governantes da capital e do reino.</pt-BR>
		<ko>{PLAYER-0,3}과 다시 만났습니다. 과거에 {PLAYER-2}의 왕이 {CITY-3}(을)를 약탈하고 {FAMILY-4,3} 가문을 수도와 왕국의 통치자로 옹립했습니다.</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_HITTITE_CONTACT_BABYLON_WOULDBE_KINGMAKERS</zType>
		<en-US>We've just made contact with the {PLAYER-0,3} again. In times past, a {PLAYER-2} king sacked {CITY-3} and tried to install the {FAMILY-4,1} as rulers of their capital and kingdom.

However the {FAMILY-4,1} have since been ousted from power and {CHARACTER-5} doesn't have very fond memories of our people.</en-US>
		<es>Acabamos de contactar otra vez con los {PLAYER-0,3}. En el pasado, un rey {PLAYER-2,1} saqueó {CITY-3} e intentó poner a los {FAMILY-4,1} a las riendas de su capital y su reino.

Sin embargo, los han echado del poder y nuestro pueblo no tiene buenos recuerdos de {CHARACTER-SHORT-5}.</es>
		<de>Wir sind gerade wieder in Kontakt mit {PLAYER-0,2}. In der Vergangenheit hat ein König {PLAYER-2,1} {CITY-3} geplündert und versucht, die {FAMILY-4,1} zu den Herrschern der Hauptstadt und des Reiches auszurufen.

Die {FAMILY-4,1} wurden seitdem jedoch aus ihrer Stellung verdrängt und {CHARACTER-5} hat nicht gerade die besten Erinnerungen an unser Volk.</de>
		<fr>Nous venons de rétablir le contact avec les {PLAYER-0,6}. Par le passé, un roi {PLAYER-2,3} avait mis à sac {CITY-3} et installé les {FAMILY-4} comme les dirigeants de leur capitale et royaume.

Cependant, les {FAMILY-4} ont été depuis évincés du pouvoir et {CHARACTER-5} n'a pas de très bons souvenirs de notre peuple.</fr>
		<ja>再び{PLAYER-0,3}と接触した。その昔、{PLAYER-2}の王は{CITY-3}を略奪し、{FAMILY-4,1}を首都と王国の支配者として据えようとした。

しかし、{FAMILY-4,1}はその後支配権を奪われた。{CHARACTER-5}は我が国民にあまり良い印象を持っていない。</ja>
		<zh-TW>我們剛才又再次和{PLAYER-0,3}取得了聯繫。在過去的期間，{PLAYER-2}國王劫掠了{CITY-3}，並試著指派{FAMILY-4,3}成為他們首都及王國的統治者。

然而，在那之後，{FAMILY-4,1}已經被趕下台，而{CHARACTER-5}對我們的人民沒有什麼太好的觀感。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Мы только что снова встретились с {lowercase:{PLAYER-0,16}}. Когда-то в прошлом король {PLAYER-2,1} разграбил {CITY-3,3} и намеревался передать столицу и все царство в руки семьи {FAMILY-4,7}.

Однако {lowercase:{PLAYER-0,6}} народ изгнал {FAMILY-4,7} со своей земли, а у {CHARACTER-5,1} о нас, разумеется, остались не лучшие воспоминания.</ru>
		<zh-CN>我们刚才又再次和{PLAYER-0,3}取得了联系。在过去的期间，{PLAYER-2}国王劫掠了{CITY-3}，并试着指派{FAMILY-4,3}成为他们首都及王国的统治者。

然而，在那之后，{FAMILY-4,1}已经被赶下台，而{CHARACTER-5}对我们的人民没有什么太好的好感度。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Nós acabamos de fazer contato com os {PLAYER-0,3} novamente. No passado, um rei {PLAYER-0,1} saqueou {PLAYER-2} e tentou instaura os {FAMILY-4,1} como governantes da capital e do reino.
 
Porém, desde então os {FAMILY-4,1} foram removidos do poder e {CHARACTER-5} não tem memórias muito agradáveis de nosso povo.</pt-BR>
		<ko>{PLAYER-0,3}과 다시 만났습니다. 과거에 {PLAYER-2}의 왕이 {CITY-3}(을)를 약탈하고 {FAMILY-4,1} 가문을 수도와 왕국의 통치자로 옹립하려 했습니다.

하지만 그 후에 {FAMILY-4,1} 가문은 축출되었고, {CHARACTER-5}(은)는 우리 나라를 썩 좋게 보고 있지 않습니다.</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_STUDY_EDUCATION_AT_THE_PANKUS</zType>
		<en-US>The Pankus is {PLAYER-0}'s general assembly and high court, ruling on constitutional matters. Even kings may be answerable before it!
As part of their upbringing, it is occasionally permitted for {PLAYER-1,1} children to attend the deliberations.</en-US>
		<es>El Panku es la asamblea general y el juzgado supremo de {PLAYER-0}, encargado de asuntos constitucionales. ¡Incluso los reyes responden ante él!

Como parte de su educación, se permite a veces que los niños {PLAYER-1,3} asistan a las deliberaciones.</es>
		<de>Beim Pankuš handelt es sich um die Volksversammlung und das oberste Gericht, das über Verfassungsangelegenheiten {PLAYER-0,1} entscheidet. Selbst Könige müssen sich vor ihm verantworten!
Manchmal können die Kinder der {PLAYER-1,11} als Teil ihrer Erziehung den Beratungen beiwohnen.</de>
		<fr>Le Pankus est à la fois l'assemblée générale et la cour suprême {PLAYER-0,2}, se prononçant sur les affaires constitutionnelles. Même les rois peuvent être amenés à rendre des comptes devant le Pankus !
Dans le contexte de leur éducation, il est parfois permis aux enfants {PLAYER-1,4} d'assister aux délibérations.</fr>
		<ja>パンクスは、{PLAYER-0}の立法機関であり、憲法に関する事項を決定する最高法院である。王でさえも、この場所では釈明義務を負う場合がある。
また、教育の一環として、{PLAYER-1,3}の子供たちが審議に参加することも認められている。</ja>
		<zh-TW>武士會議是{PLAYER-0}的統治機關及高等法院，負責對憲法事務作出裁決。就連國王在其面前也得為自己責任！
作為{PLAYER-1,3}孩童教養的一部分，他們偶爾可以出席這樣的審議。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Панкус — это народное собрание и высший судебный орган {PLAYER-0,1}, решающий конституционные споры. На нем несут ответ даже цари!
Время от времени на заседания в образовательных целях допускают детей.</ru>
		<zh-CN>武士会议是{PLAYER-0}的统治机关及高等法院，负责对宪法事务作出裁决。就连国王在其面前也得为自己责任！
作为{PLAYER-1,3}孩童教养的一部分，他们偶尔可以出席这样的审议。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>O Pankus é a assembleia geral e tribunal superior {PLAYER-0,6}, que delibera sobre assuntos constitucionais. Mesmo os rei podem ter que responder a ele!
Como parte de sua educação, ocasionalmente é permitido que as crianças {PLAYER_F-1,3} estejam presentes nas deliberações.</pt-BR>
		<ko>판쿠스는 {PLAYER-0}의 총회이자 헌법 문제를 판단하는 최고 법원입니다. 심지어는 왕도 이들 앞에서 해명해야 합니다!
교육의 일환으로 {PLAYER-1,3}의 아이들이 심의회를 참관하는 것을 허용하기도 합니다.</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_BABYLON_CONTACT_HITTITE_ANCIENT_SACK</zType>
		<en-US>We have met the {PLAYER-1,3} again. 
In times long past, their armies sacked {CITY-3}... It was at this occasion that the {FAMILY-4,3} rose to power there.</en-US>
		<es>Hemos vuelto a encontrarnos con los {PLAYER-1,3}. En el pasado, sus ejércitos saquearon {CITY-3}. Fue entonces cuando la familia {FAMILY-4} se alzó con el poder.</es>
		<de>Wir haben die {PLAYER-1,11} wieder einmal getroffen. 
Vor langer Zeit plünderten ihre Soldaten {CITY-3} … Die {FAMILY-4,1} kamen bei dieser Gelegenheit dort an die Macht.</de>
		<fr>Nous avons à nouveau rencontré les {PLAYER-1,6}. 
Par le passé, leurs armées avaient mis à sac {CITY-3}… C'était en cette occasion que les {FAMILY-4} y avaient été propulsés au pouvoir.</fr>
		<ja>再び{PLAYER-1,3}と接触した。
遠い昔、奴らの軍隊が{CITY-3}を略奪したという歴史がある…。{FAMILY-4,3}が勢力を伸ばしたのは、そのときだった。</ja>
		<zh-TW>我們再次與{PLAYER-1,3}進行會面。
在很久以前，他們的軍隊洗劫了{CITY-3}…而那就是{FAMILY-4,3}在該地崛起的契機。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Мы снова повстречали {lowercase:{PLAYER-1,13}}.
Когда-то в прошлом их войско разорило {CITY-3}… Именно тогда {FAMILY-4,6} и пришли к власти.</ru>
		<zh-CN>我们再次与{PLAYER-1,3}进行会面。
在很久以前，他们的军队洗劫了{CITY-3}…而那就是{FAMILY-4,3}在该地崛起的契机。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Nós nos encontramos com os {PLAYER-1,3} novamente.
No passado distante, os exércitos deles saquearam {CITY-3}... Foi nesta ocasião que os {FAMILY-4,1} chegaram ao poder.</pt-BR>
		<ko>{PLAYER-1,3}과 다시 만났습니다.
오래전 그들의 군대가 {CITY-3}(을)를 약탈했습니다... {FAMILY-4,3} 가문이 득세한 것은 그때부터였습니다.</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_UNIQUE_UNIT_SALE_HITTITE</zType>
		<en-US>A messenger has arrived from {PLAYER-0} with an intriguing offer. {CHARACTER-0} finds {G0:himself:herself} with a strong military, but a shortage of resources. And, {G0:his:her} message suggests, “perhaps we can both benefit from this situation”.

For a modest fee you can acquire the services of a powerful link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_1), a rare sight outside the forces of {PLAYER-0}. “Of course”, the message concludes, “if you refuse I will need to find some other use for my excess forces. They may end up in {CITY-1} regardless”.

Shall we accept?</en-US>
		<es>Ha llegado un mensajero desde {PLAYER-0} con una oferta interesante. {CHARACTER-0} tiene un ejército bastante poderoso, pero también hay un gran desabastecimiento de recursos. Y su mensaje sugiere que, a lo mejor, ambos podríamos «beneficiarnos» de esta situación.

Por una pequeña cuota podrías disponer de los servicios de un poderoso link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_1), algo raro de ver fuera de las tropas de {PLAYER-0}. «No obstante, —lees al final del mensaje—, si no aceptas, tendré que buscarle otro uso al resto de mis tropas. Aunque seguramente acaben en {CITY-1}».

¿Deberíamos aceptar la oferta?</es>
		<de>Ein Bote {PLAYER-0,8} überbringt uns ein verlockendes Angebot. {CHARACTER-0} verfügt über eine starke Armee, ist jedoch knapp an Rohstoffen. {G0:Er:Sie} denkt, dass wir vielleicht beide von dieser Situation profitieren könnten.

Für ein bescheidenes Entgelt könnt Ihr eine mächtige Einheit link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_1,5) erwerben, ein seltener Anblick außerhalb der Streitkräfte von {PLAYER-0,2}. Die Nachricht schließt mit folgenden Worten: „Wenn Ihr Euch weigert, werde ich eine andere Verwendung für meine überschüssigen Kräfte finden müssen. Sie können dennoch in {CITY-1} enden.“

Sollen wir akzeptieren?</de>
		<fr>Un messager est arrivé {PLAYER-0,2} avec une offre intrigante. {CHARACTER-0} se retrouve avec une imposante armée, mais un manque de ressources. Son message suggère : « peut-être pourrions-nous tous les deux tirer parti de cette situation ».

Pour une modeste somme, vous pouvez acquérir les services d'un puissant link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_1), une rareté en dehors des forces {PLAYER-0,8}. « Bien entendu », conclut le message, « si vous refusez, je devrai alors trouver une autre utilité à mes excédents militaires. Ils pourraient malgré tout se retrouver à {CITY-1} ».

Allons-nous accepter ?</fr>
		<ja>{PLAYER-0}から魅力的な提案を携えた使者がやってきた。{CHARACTER-0}は、{G0:彼自身:彼女自身}、強力な軍事力を装備したが、資源が不足していた。また、{G0:彼:彼女}の書状は、「もしかしたら、我々は双方とも、この状況から利益を得ることができるかもしれない」ということを示唆している。

手頃な料金で、強力なlink(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_1)の支援を受けることができるのだ。これは、{PLAYER-0}の勢力の外では珍しい光景である。「無論」、書状は次のように締めくくられている。「貴殿が拒否するならば、私は私の余剰戦力の他の使い道を見つける必要があるだろう。{CITY-1}に行くことになるかもしれないな」

受け入れるべきだろうか？</ja>
		<zh-TW>來自{PLAYER-0}的信使帶來了一項誘人的提議。{CHARACTER-0}發現他們雖然擁有強大的軍隊，但缺乏資源。此外，{G0:他:她}還在訊息中暗示道：「或許我們雙方都能從這個情況中獲益。」

只要提供一小筆款項，你就能得到強大的link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_1)為你效勞，這在{PLAYER-0}領土之外可是相當罕見。信函的結尾寫道：「當然，如果你拒絕，我將需要為我多餘的軍力尋找其他用途。無論如何，他們最終可能會出現在{CITY-1}。」

我們是否要接受？</zh-TW>
		<ru>Из {PLAYER-0,1} прибывает гонец с заманчивым предложением. {CHARACTER-0} командует сильной армией, однако {G0:его:ее} нация испытывает нехватку ресурсов. В своем послании {G0:он:она} заявляет: «Возможно, обе наши нации смогут извлечь выгоду из ситуации».

За скромную плату вы сможете пополнить войско могучей {lowercase:link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_1,4)}, которая весьма редко встречаются где-либо кроме {lowercase:{PLAYER-0,31}} армии. «Конечно, — говорится в послании, — если ты откажешься от моего предложения, мне придется найти другой способ выгодно распорядиться военной мощью. Возможно, мои воины так или иначе окажутся в {CITY-1,5}, но уже в несколько иной ипостаси».

Принимаете ли вы это предложение?</ru>
		<zh-CN>来自{PLAYER-0}的信使带来了一项诱人的提议。 {CHARACTER-0}发现他们虽然拥有强大的军队，但缺乏资源。此外，{G0:他:她}还在讯息中暗示道：「或许我们双方都能从这个情况中获益。」

只要提供一小笔款项，你就能得到强大的link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_1)为你效劳，这在{PLAYER-0}领土之外可是相当罕见。信函的结尾写道：「当然，如果你拒绝，我将需要为我多余的军力寻找其他用途。无论如何，他们最终可能会出现在{CITY-1}。」

我们是否要接受？</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Um mensageiro {PLAYER-0,1} chega com uma proposta intrigante. {CHARACTER-0} tem tropas poderosas, mas lhe faltam recursos. O mensageiro sugere que "talvez ambas as nações possam se beneficiar desta situação".
 
Por uma pequena taxa você pode adquirir os serviços de um poderoso link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_1), algo que seria raro de ver fora das tropas {PLAYER_F-0,3}. "É claro", o mensageiro continua, "que se você recusar nós teremos que encontrar algum outro uso para nossas forças. Elas podem, inclusive, acabar em {CITY-1} de qualquer forma."
 
Devemos aceitar?</pt-BR>
		<ko>{PLAYER-0}에서 온 전령이 흥미로운 제안을 가지고 도착했습니다. {CHARACTER-0}(은)는 강력한 군대를 거느리고 있지만 자원이 부족합니다. {G0:그:그녀}는 전갈을 통해 양측에 이익이 될 수 있는 제안을 합니다.

우리가 적당한 값을 지불하면 {PLAYER-0}에서만 볼 수 있는 막강한 link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_1)을 이용하게 해 준다는 것입니다. 전갈은 다음과 같이 말을 맺습니다. "만약 거절하신다면, 남아도는 저의 병력을 다른 곳에 활용해야 할 것입니다. 결국은 그 병력이 {CITY-1}(으)로 향하겠죠."

제안을 받아들일까요?</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_NAMED_UNIT_MESEDI</zType>
		<en-US>The {UNIT-0,2} led by {CHARACTER-1} have proven their military skill and above all, their unconditional loyalty to your person.
You have taken to relying on them as bodyguards and leading them is a great honor, which {CHARACTER-1} clearly enjoys.
		
{G1:He:She} suggests that their excellence might be further encouraged if you gave them the honor of an official name.
		</en-US>
		<es>Los {UNIT-0,2} bajo el mando de {CHARACTER-1} han demostrado sus dotes militares y, sobre todo, la lealtad incondicional que te profesan. Has depositado tu confianza en ellos como tu escolta y liderarlos es un auténtico honor que {CHARACTER-SHORT-1} disfruta sin tapujos. Sugiere que podríamos animarlos a redoblar esfuerzos honrándolos con un nombre oficial.</es>
		<de>Die {UNIT-0,5}, die {CHARACTER-1} anführt, haben ihr militärisches Können und ihre bedingungslose Treue zu Euch bewiesen.
Ihr nutzt sie nun als Leibwache und es ist eine große Ehre, an ihrer Spitze zu stehen, was {CHARACTER-SHORT-1} sichtlich genießt.
		
{G1:Er:Sie} schlägt vor, sie zu noch größerer Exzellenz anzutreiben, indem Ihr ihnen mit einem offiziellen Namen Anerkennung zollt.
		</de>
		<fr>Les {UNIT-0,2} avec {CHARACTER-1} à leur tête ont prouvé leurs compétences militaires et par dessus tout, leur loyauté inconditionnelle envers votre personne.
Vous comptez maintenant sur eux en tant que gardes du corps et les mener est un grand honneur dont {CHARACTER-1} jouit.
		
{G1:Il:Elle} suggère que leur excellence pourrait être davantage encouragée si vous leur accordiez la distinction d'un nom officiel.
		</fr>
		<ja>{CHARACTER-1}の率いる{UNIT-0,2}は、その軍事技術の高さ、そして何よりあなたに対する絶対的な忠誠心に定評がある。
あなたは彼らを護衛隊として頼るようになった。隊長の{CHARACTER-1}は明らかにその任務を楽しんでいるように見える。
		
{G1:彼:彼女}は、正式名称を授かることができれば、部隊としての能力をさらに高めることができるかもしれないと主張している。
		</ja>
		<zh-TW>{CHARACTER-1}帶領的{UNIT-0,2}已經證明了他們的軍事能力還有更重要的——對你個人的無條件忠誠。
你開始任用他們為私人護衛，而帶領他們是一個極大的榮耀，顯然{CHARACTER-1}很享受這個職責。
		
{G1:他:她}建議你給他們一個正式的名稱，認為這項榮耀能夠進一步鼓勵他們的優秀表現。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Отряд {lowercase:{UNIT-0,7}} под началом {CHARACTER-1,1} продемонстрировал выдающееся мастерство, а главное — безоговорочную преданность {choice_GL:царю:царице}.
Часто они выступают в роли ваших личных телохранителей, а их лидер {CHARACTER-1} — {G1:мужчина:женщина} выдающейся чести и доблести.
		По {G1:его:ее} словам, официальное название поднимет боевой дух воинов и поможет им достичь еще больших высот великолепия.
		
</ru>
		<zh-CN>{CHARACTER-1}带领的{UNIT-0,2}已经证明了他们的军事能力还有更重要的——对你个人的无条件忠诚。
你开始任用他们为私人护卫，而带领他们是一个极大的荣耀，显然{CHARACTER-1}很享受这个职责。
		
{G1:他:她}建议你给他们一个正式的名称，认为这项荣耀能够进一步鼓励他们的优秀表现。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>A {UNIT-0,3} liderada por {CHARACTER-1} provou sua proeza militar e, acima de tudo, sua lealdade incondicional a você.
Você passou a confiar neles como guarda-costas e liderá-los é uma grande honra, a qual {CHARACTER-1} claramente aprecia e faz jus.
 
{G1:Ele:Ela} sugere que a excelência da unidade poderia ser ainda mais encorajada se você lhes desse a honra de um nome oficial.</pt-BR>
		<ko>{CHARACTER-1}(이)가 지휘하는 {UNIT-0,2}는 뛰어난 군사 기술과 무엇보다도 당신을 향한 무조건적인 충성심을 입증했습니다.
당신이 그들을 경호원으로 두고 이끄는 것은 그들에게 아주 큰 영광이며, {CHARACTER-1} 역시 이를 즐기고 있습니다.
		
{G1:그:그녀}가 제안하기를 정식 칭호라는 영광을 부여한다면 그들의 우수성을 더욱 고취할 것이라고 합니다.
		</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_NAMED_UNIT_GOLDEN_SPEARMEN</zType>
		<en-US>The {UNIT-0,2} you lead guard your side at all hours and monitor all other units assigned as bodyguards. Their absolute loyalty is of course paramount to their role and as a sign of honor they are equipped with the most resplendent of our arms and armors.

People have taken to calling them "The Golden Spearmen".

Shall we recognize this name as an additional honor?</en-US>
		<es>Los {UNIT-0,2} que diriges hacen guardia a tu lado a todas horas y vigilan al resto de unidades asignadas como escolta. Su lealtad absoluta es vital para su función, claro, y como muestra de honor, portan las armas y armaduras más resplandecientes.

La gente ha empezado a llamarlos «los lanceros dorados». ¿Deberíamos reconocer este nombre como una muestra adicional de honor?</es>
		<de>Die von Euch geführten {UNIT-0,5} schützen Euch zu jeglicher Stunde und überwachen alle anderen Einheiten, die als Leibwachen dienen. Ihre vollkommene Treue ist ein Akt der Selbstverständlichkeit und unerlässlich für ihre Rolle. Als Zeichen der Anerkennung tragen sie die prachtvollsten Waffen und Rüstungen.

Die Menschen haben daher begonnen, sie „Die Goldlanzenträger“ zu nennen.

Sollen wir diesen Namen offiziell anerkennen, um sie zu ehren?</de>
		<fr>Les {UNIT-0,2} que vous menez gardent vos arrières à toute heure et surveillent toutes les autres unités désignées comme gardes du corps. Leur loyauté absolue est évidemment primordiale à leur rôle et en signe d'honneur, ils sont équipés des armes et armures les plus resplendissantes.

Les gens ont pris l'habitude de les appeler les « Les lanciers dorés ».

Allons-nous reconnaître le nom comme une distinction supplémentaire ?</fr>
		<ja>{UNIT-0,2}は一日中あなたを護衛しながら、護衛兵として配属された他の全ユニットの管理まで担当している。言うまでもなく、護衛を行うには、彼らの持つような絶対的な忠誠心が欠かせない。彼らには名誉の印として、特別派手な武具を装備することが認められている。

人々はこの部隊のことを「黄金の槍兵」と呼ぶようになった。

この名前を、正式名称として認めるべきだろうか？</ja>
		<zh-TW>你帶領的{UNIT-0,2}隨時在你的左右進行護衛，並監管被指派為私人護衛的其他所有單位。對他們的職責來說，他們絕對的忠誠當然至關重要，這也是一項榮耀，象徵他們裝備的是最體面的武器及護甲。

人們已經開始用「黃金矛兵」來稱呼他們。

我們應該承認這個名稱，作為額外的榮耀嗎？</zh-TW>
		<ru>Верные {lowercase:{UNIT-0,6}} всегда готовы заслонить вас от опасности и служат ярчайшим примером для других отрядов царской стражи. Безоговорчной преданностью, столь важной для их роли, они заслужили право носить элитное обмундирование.

В народе их уже прозвали Золотыми копьями.

Возможно, стоит придать этому благородному имени официальный статус?</ru>
		<zh-CN>你带领的{UNIT-0,2}随时在你的左右进行护卫，并监管被指派为私人护卫的其他所有单位。对他们的职责来说，他们绝对的忠诚当然至关重要，这也是一项荣耀，象征他们装备的是最体面的武器及护甲。

人们已经开始用「黄金矛兵」来称呼他们。

我们应该承认这个名称，作为额外的荣耀吗？</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>A {UNIT-0,3} que você lidera lhe guarda a todo instante e monitora todas as outras unidades nomeadas como guarda-costas. A lealdade absoluta que lhe têm é, obviamente, imprescindível para o papel que cumprem e como sinal dessa honra eles têm as armas e armaduras mais resplandecentes de nosso exército.
 
O povo começou a chamá-los de "Lanceiros Dourados".
 
Devemos reconhecer este título como uma honraria adicional?</pt-BR>
		<ko>당신이 지휘하는 {UNIT-0,2}은 당신을 호위하며, 경호원으로 배정된 다른 부대를 총괄합니다. 물론 이들의 역할에서 가장 중요한 것은 절대적인 충성심이며, 이들은 영광의 표시로 매우 찬란한 무구를 장비하고 있습니다.

사람들은 그런 이들을 '황금 창병'이라 부르고는 합니다.

영광을 더할 수 있도록 이 명칭을 정식으로 수여할까요?</ko>
	</Entry>
</Root>