<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--This file is generated by the LocalizationEditor!-->
<Root>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_OCCURRENCELEVEL_CALAMITIES_NONE</zType>
		<en-US>None</en-US>
		<es>Ninguno</es>
		<de>Keine</de>
		<fr>Aucune</fr>
		<ja>なし</ja>
		<zh-TW>無</zh-TW>
		<ru>Нет</ru>
		<zh-CN>无</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Nenhuma</pt-BR>
		<ko>발생하지 않음</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_OCCURRENCELEVEL_CALAMITIES_VERY_LOW</zType>
		<en-US>Very Rare</en-US>
		<es>Muy raro</es>
		<de>Sehr selten</de>
		<fr>Très rares</fr>
		<ja>非常に少ない</ja>
		<zh-TW>極罕見</zh-TW>
		<ru>Очень редко</ru>
		<zh-CN>极罕见</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Muito Rara</pt-BR>
		<ko>매우 낮은 빈도</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_OCCURRENCELEVEL_CALAMITIES_VERY_LOW_HELP</zType>
		<en-US>Calamities will occur much later in the game and much less frequently</en-US>
		<es>Las calamidades tendrán lugar cuando la partida esté más avanzada y serán mucho menos frecuentes.</es>
		<de>Katastrophen ereignen sich erst später im Spiel und wesentlich seltener.</de>
		<fr>Les calamités s'abattront sur vous bien plus tard dans le jeu et beaucoup plus rarement.</fr>
		<ja>自然災害はゲームの最終盤に発生し、その頻度は非常に低い</ja>
		<zh-TW>自然災害會在遊戲更後期發生，而且發生的頻率也會大大降低</zh-TW>
		<ru>Бедствия случаются очень редко и только на самых поздних этапах игры</ru>
		<zh-CN>自然灾害会在游戏大后期发生，而且发生的频率也会大大降低</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>As calamidades acontecerão muito tardiamente em jogo e com frequência muito menor</pt-BR>
		<ko>재난이 게임 극후반에 발생하며 빈도가 매우 낮음</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_OCCURRENCELEVEL_CALAMITIES_LOW</zType>
		<en-US>Rare</en-US>
		<es>Raro</es>
		<de>Selten</de>
		<fr>Rares</fr>
		<ja>少ない</ja>
		<zh-TW>罕見</zh-TW>
		<ru>Редко</ru>
		<zh-CN>罕见</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Rara</pt-BR>
		<ko>낮은 빈도</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_OCCURRENCELEVEL_CALAMITIES_LOW_HELP</zType>
		<en-US>Calamities will occur later in the game and less frequently</en-US>
		<es>Las calamidades tendrán lugar cuando la partida esté avanzada y serán menos frecuentes.</es>
		<de>Katastrophen ereignen sich erst später im Spiel und seltener.</de>
		<fr>Les calamités s'abattront sur vous plus tard dans le jeu et plus rarement.</fr>
		<ja>自然災害はゲームの後半に発生し、その頻度は低い</ja>
		<zh-TW>自然災害會在遊戲後期發生，而且發生的頻率也會降低</zh-TW>
		<ru>Бедствия случаются реже и на более поздних этапах игры</ru>
		<zh-CN>自然灾害会在游戏后期发生，而且发生的频率也会降低</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>As calamidades acontecerão tardiamente e com menos frequência</pt-BR>
		<ko>재난이 게임 후반에 발생하며 빈도가 낮음</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_OCCURRENCELEVEL_CALAMITIES_NORMAL</zType>
		<en-US>Default</en-US>
		<es>Por defecto</es>
		<de>Standard</de>
		<fr>Par défaut</fr>
		<ja>標準</ja>
		<zh-TW>預設</zh-TW>
		<ru>По умолчанию</ru>
		<zh-CN>预设</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Padrão</pt-BR>
		<ko>기본값</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_OCCURRENCELEVEL_CALAMITIES_NORMAL_HELP</zType>
		<en-US>There will be a balanced level of Calamities</en-US>
		<es>El nivel de calamidades será equilibrado.</es>
		<de>Die Ereigniswahrscheinlichkeit von Katastrophen ist ausgewogen.</de>
		<fr>Les calamités s'abattront sur vous de manière équilibrée.</fr>
		<ja>自然災害はゲーム全体を通してバランスよく発生する</ja>
		<zh-TW>自然災害的情況較為平衡。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Сбалансированная частота бедствий</ru>
		<zh-CN>自然灾害的情况较为平衡。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>A quantidade de calamidades será equilibrada</pt-BR>
		<ko>균형 있는 수준의 재난이 발생함</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_OCCURRENCELEVEL_CALAMITIES_HIGH</zType>
		<en-US>Common</en-US>
		<es>Común</es>
		<de>Häufig</de>
		<fr>Fréquentes</fr>
		<ja>多い</ja>
		<zh-TW>普遍</zh-TW>
		<ru>Часто</ru>
		<zh-CN>普遍</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Comum</pt-BR>
		<ko>흔한 빈도</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_OCCURRENCELEVEL_CALAMITIES_HIGH_HELP</zType>
		<en-US>Calamities will occur earlier in the game and more frequently</en-US>
		<es>Las calamidades tendrán lugar en un punto temprano de la partida y serán más frecuentes.</es>
		<de>Katastrophen ereignen sich früher im Spiel und häufiger.</de>
		<fr>Les calamités s'abattront sur vous plus tôt dans le jeu et plus fréquemment.</fr>
		<ja>自然災害は序盤より発生し、頻度は高い</ja>
		<zh-TW>自然災害會在遊戲前期發生，而且發生的頻率也會提高</zh-TW>
		<ru>Бедствия случаются чаще и на более ранних этапах игры</ru>
		<zh-CN>自然灾害会在游戏前期发生，而且发生的频率也会提高</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>As calamidades acontecerão logo em jogo e com mais frequência</pt-BR>
		<ko>재난이 게임 초반에 발생하며 빈도가 높음</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_OCCURRENCELEVEL_CALAMITIES_VERY_HIGH</zType>
		<en-US>Very Common</en-US>
		<es>Muy común</es>
		<de>Sehr häufig</de>
		<fr>Très fréquentes</fr>
		<ja>非常に多い</ja>
		<zh-TW>極普遍</zh-TW>
		<ru>Очень часто</ru>
		<zh-CN>极普遍</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Muito Comum</pt-BR>
		<ko>매우 흔한 빈도</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_OCCURRENCELEVEL_CALAMITIES_VERY_HIGH_HELP</zType>
		<en-US>Calamities will occur much earlier in the game and much more frequently</en-US>
		<es>Las calamidades tendrán lugar en un punto más temprano de la partida y serán mucho más frecuentes.</es>
		<de>Katastrophen ereignen sich früher im Spiel und wesentlich häufiger.</de>
		<fr>Les calamités s'abattront sur vous bien plus tôt dans le jeu et beaucoup plus fréquemment.</fr>
		<ja>災害は最序盤より発生し、その頻度は非常に高い</ja>
		<zh-TW>自然災害會在遊戲更前期發生，而且發生的頻率也會大大提高</zh-TW>
		<ru>Бедствия случаются очень часто и практически с самого начала игры</ru>
		<zh-CN>自然灾害会在游戏大前期发生，而且发生的频率也会大大提高</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>As calamidades acontecerão prontamente em jogo e com muito mais frequência</pt-BR>
		<ko>재난이 게임 극초반에 발생하며 빈도가 매우 높음</ko>
	</Entry>
</Root>