<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--This file is generated by the LocalizationEditor!-->
<Root>
	<Entry>
		<zType />
		<en-US />
		<es />
		<de />
		<fr />
		<ja />
		<zh-TW />
		<ru />
		<zh-CN />
		<pt-BR />
		<ko />
	</Entry>
	<!-- Wizard: Event Story Helper -->
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTEDITOR_STORY_NAME_BASE_DESC</zType>
		<en-US>A unique name base for this event story, such as FAMILY_SQUABBLE. Do not include EVENTSTORY_ in this string.

The name base will be automatically appended to generic prefixes like EVENTSTORY_ and EVENTOPTION_ to create zTypes.</en-US>
		<es>Un nombre original único para este evento de historia, como FAMILY_SQUABBLE. No incluyas EVENTSTORY_ en esta cadena.

Al nombre original se le adjuntará prefijos como EVENTSTORY_ y EVENTOPTION_ de forma automática para crear zTypes.</es>
		<de>Einen einzigartigen Basisnamen für diese Ereignisgeschichte, etwa FAMILY_SQUABBLE. Du darfst EVENTSTORY_ nicht in diesen String einbeziehen.

Der Basisname wird automatisch an generische Präfixe wie EVENTSTORY_ und EVENTOPTION_ angehängt, um zTypes zu erstellen.</de>
		<fr>Un nom original unique pour cet événement historique, tel que FAMILY_SQUABBLE. Ne pas inclure EVENTSTORY_ dans cette suite.

Le nom unique sera automatiquement précédé de préfixes tels que EVENTSTORY_ et EVENTOPTION_ pour créer des zTypes.</fr>
		<ja>「FAMILY_SQUABBLE」のような、このイベントストーリーの一意のネームベースとなるものです。この文字列に「EVENTSTORY_」を含めないようにしてください。

ネームベースは、「EVENTSTORY_」や「EVENTOPTION_」などの一般的なプレフィックスに自動的に追加され、zTypeを作成します。</ja>
		<zh-TW>事件故事的專屬名稱庫，如FAMILY_SQUABBLE。請勿在此字串中加入EVENTSTORY_。

名稱庫將自動添加到縮寫中，如EVENTSTORY_和EVENTOPTION_中，建立 Z 型字串。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Уникальная база названий для этой истории события, например, FAMILY_SQUABBLE. Не включайте EVENTSTORY_ в эту строку.

База названия будет автоматически добавляться к общим префиксам, таким как EVENTSTORY_ и EVENTOPTION_, чтобы создать переменные zType.</ru>
		<zh-CN>事件故事的专属名称库，如FAMILY_SQUABBLE。请勿在此字串中加入EVENTSTORY_。

名称库将自动添加到缩写中，如EVENTSTORY_和EVENTOPTION_中，建立 Z 型字串。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Um nome principal único para a história deste evento, como por exemplo FAMILY_SQUABBLE. Não inclua EVENTSTORY_ na sequência do nome.

Prefixos genéricos como EVENTSTORY_ e EVENTOPTION_ serão automaticamente adicionados ao nome principal para criar zTypes.</pt-BR>
		<ko>FAMILY_SQUABBLE처럼 이 사건에 사용되는 고유한 베이스입니다. 이 스트링에는 EVENTSTORY_ 를 포함하지 않도록 하십시오.

이름 베이스는 EVENTSTORY_ 나 EVENTOPTION_ 같은 일반 접두사에 자동으로 붙어 zType을 생성합니다.</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTEDITOR_OPTION_NAME_BASES_DESC</zType>
		<en-US>The name bases for this story’s options. These will be appended to the option zTypes after the story name base.
		
If you intend to add existing options or options whose name is not calculated by the same nature, just add blank items here.</en-US>
		<es>Los nombres originales para las opciones de esta historia. Se adjuntarán a las opciones zTypes según el nombre original.

Si intentas usar opciones existentes u opciones cuyo nombre no se calcula del mismo modo, añade ítems en blanco aquí.</es>
		<de>Die Basisnamen für die Optionen dieser Geschichte. Diese werden nach dem Basisnamen der Geschichte an die Optionen-zTypes angefügt.
		
Wenn du bestehende Optionen oder Optionen, deren Namen nicht auf dieselbe Art und Weise berechnet wird, hinzufügen möchtest, kannst du hier ganz einfach leere Objekte einfügen.</de>
		<fr>Les bases de noms pour les options de cette histoire. Elles seront ajoutées à l'option zTypes après la base de nom de l'histoire.
		
Si vous comptez ajouter des options existantes ou des options dont le nom n'est pas calculé de la même manière, ajoutez simplement des éléments vides ici.</fr>
		<ja>このストーリーのオプションのネームベース。これらは、ストーリーネームベースの後のオプションzTypeに追加されます。
		
既存のオプションや、同じ属性で名前が定義されないオプションを追加する場合は、ここに空白の項目を追加します。</ja>
		<zh-TW>故事選項的名稱庫。這些將在故事名稱庫後添加至 Z 型字串中。
		
若你打算加入既有的選項或名稱並非由同樣方式計算的選項，只要在此加入空白物件即可。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Базы названий для параметров истории. Они будут добавляться к переменным zType для настроек после баз названий историй.
		
Если вы собираетесь добавить существующие параметры или параметры, названия которых не рассчитываются таким же образом, вставьте сюда пустые названия.</ru>
		<zh-CN>故事选项的名称库。这些将在故事名称库后添加至 Z 型字串中。
		
若你打算加入既有的选项或名称并非由同样方式计算的选项，只要在此加入空白物件即可。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Os nomes principais para as opções desta história. Eles serão adicionados às opções zTypes depois do nome da história.

Caso você queria utilizar opções já existentes ou opções cujo nome não segue esta mesma lógica, basta colocar itens em branco aqui.</pt-BR>
		<ko>이 스토리의 선택지에 사용될 이름 베이스로, 스토리 이름 베이스 다음 오는 선택지 zType에 붙습니다.



이미 존재하는 선택지나 다른 방식으로 계산되는 선택지를 넣으려면 이곳에 공백을 추가하십시오.</ko>
	</Entry>
	<!-- Other -->
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTEDITOR_GROUP_DESC</zType>
		<en-US>The group that this entry belongs to. This is for sorting purposes in the browser/xml.</en-US>
		<es>El grupo al que pertenece esta entrada. Se usa para ordenar en el buscador/xml.</es>
		<de>Die Gruppe, in die dieser Eintrag gehört. Dient zu Sortierungszwecken in Browser/xml.</de>
		<fr>Le groupe auquel fait partie cette entrée. Cela sert à trier dans le navigateur/xml.</fr>
		<ja>このエントリが属するグループ。これは、ブラウザー/xmlでソートするためのものです。</ja>
		<zh-TW>此筆輸入條目所屬的群組。這是為了用於在瀏覽器/xml 中分類。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Группа, к которой принадлежит этот пункт. Для сортировки в браузере/xml.</ru>
		<zh-CN>此笔输入条目所属的群组。这是为了用于在浏览器/xml 中分类。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>O grupo ao qual esta entrada pertence. Será usado para organização no navegador/xml.</pt-BR>
		<ko>이 항목이 속하는 그룹입니다. 탐색기/xml에서 분류할 때 사용됩니다.</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTEDITOR_SHOW_REFERENCES_DESC</zType>
		<en-US>Displays a list of info tags that directly reference this entry.</en-US>
		<es>Muestra una lista de etiquetas informativas que se refieren directamente a esta entrada.</es>
		<de>Eine Liste von Info-Schlagwörtern, die direkt auf diesen Eintrag verweisen.</de>
		<fr>Affiche une liste des informations qui font directement référence à cette entrée.</fr>
		<ja>このエントリを直接参照する情報タグのリストを表示します。</ja>
		<zh-TW>顯示直接提及此筆輸入條目的資訊標籤清單。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Отображает список информационных тегов, напрямую ссылающихся на эту запись.</ru>
		<zh-CN>显示直接提及此笔输入条目的资讯标签清单。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Mostra uma lista de etiquetas informativas que fazem referência direta à esta entrada.</pt-BR>
		<ko>이 항목을 직접 참조하는 정보 태그 목록을 표시합니다.</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTEDITOR_SHOW_EVENT_ROOTS_DESC</zType>
		<en-US>Displays a list of events that reference this entry somewhere in the hierarchy.</en-US>
		<es>Muestra una lista de eventos que se refieren a esta entrada en algún lugar de la jerarquía.</es>
		<de>Eine Liste von Ereignissen, die irgendwo in der Hierarchie auf diesen Eintrag verweisen.</de>
		<fr>Affiche une liste des événements qui font référence à cette entrée à un moment donné.</fr>
		<ja>階層内のどこかでこのエントリを参照するイベントのリストを表示します。</ja>
		<zh-TW>顯示在階層中某處提及此筆輸入條目的事件清單。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Отображает список событий, ссылающихся на эту запись где-то в иерархии.</ru>
		<zh-CN>显示在阶层中某处提及此笔输入条目的事件清单。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Mostra uma lista de eventos que fazem referência à esta entrada em algum lugar da hierarquia.</pt-BR>
		<ko>같은 계층에서 이 항목을 참조하는 모든 이벤트를 표시합니다.</ko>
	</Entry>
</Root>