<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--This file is generated by the LocalizationEditor!-->
<Root>
	<Entry>
		<zType />
		<en-US />
		<es />
		<de />
		<fr />
		<ja />
		<zh-TW />
		<ru />
		<zh-CN />
		<pt-BR />
		<ko />
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_STUDY_CHARIOT_COMBAT_OPTION_0</zType>
		<en-US>{G1:He:She} should prepare {G1:himself:herself} to lead our cavalry to glorious victories!</en-US>
		<es>¡Debería prepararse personalmente para dirigir a nuestra caballería a la victoria!</es>
		<de>{G1:Er:Sie} sollte darauf vorbereitet werden, unsere Kavallerie zu glorreichen Siegen zu führen!</de>
		<fr>{G1:Il:Elle} devrait se préparer à mener notre cavalerie vers de glorieuses victoires !</fr>
		<ja>我が騎兵隊を率いて輝かしい勝利を収めるべく、戦う覚悟を決めるべきだ。</ja>
		<zh-TW>{G1:他:她}應該要做好準備，引領我們的騎兵迎向光榮的勝利！</zh-TW>
		<ru>{G1:Ему:Ей} предстоит вести нашу кавалерию в бой!</ru>
		<zh-CN>{G1:他:她}应该要做好准备，引领我们的骑兵迎向光荣的胜利！</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>{G1:Ele:Ela} deveria se preparar para levar nossa cavalaria a vitórias gloriosas!</pt-BR>
		<ko>{G1:그:그녀}는 우리 기병 부대를 이끌고 찬란한 승리를 거두도록 싸울 채비를 해야 한다!</ko>
		<fixja>我が騎兵隊を率いて輝かしい勝利を収めるべく、戦う覚悟を決めるべきだ。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_STUDY_CHARIOT_COMBAT_OPTION_1</zType>
		<en-US>{G1:He:She} should master effective tactics to defeat our enemy's cavalry.</en-US>
		<es>Debería dominar las tácticas efectivas para derrotar a la caballería enemiga.</es>
		<de>{G1:Er:Sie} soll effektive Taktiken erlernen, um die feindliche Kavallerie zu schlagen.</de>
		<fr>{G1:Il:Elle} devrait maîtriser des tactiques efficaces pour vaincre la cavalerie ennemie.</fr>
		<ja>敵の騎兵隊を撃退するべく、有効な戦術を身につけるべきだ。</ja>
		<zh-TW>{G1:他:她}應該精通有效的戰略，來擊敗敵人的騎兵。</zh-TW>
		<ru>{G1:Он должен:Она должна} познать тонкости стратегии и стать грозой вражеской кавалерии.</ru>
		<zh-CN>{G1:他:她}应该精通有效的战略，来击败敌人的骑兵。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>{G1:Ele:Ela} deveria dominar estratégias eficientes para derrotar a cavalaria de nossos inimigos.</pt-BR>
		<ko>{G1:그:그녀}는 적 기병 부대를 효과적으로 물리칠 전략에 통달해야 한다.</ko>
		<fixja>敵の騎兵隊を撃退するべく、有効な戦術を身につけるべきだ。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_STUDY_RICHES_OF_THE_HILLS_OPTION_0</zType>
		<en-US>I shall find the iron and the stone!</en-US>
		<es>¡Encontraré el hierro y la piedra!</es>
		<de>„Ich werde das Eisen und den Stein finden!“</de>
		<fr>Je trouverai le fer et la pierre !</fr>
		<ja>鉄と石を見つけよう！</ja>
		<zh-TW>我要找出鐵礦及石材！</zh-TW>
		<ru>Я отыщу железо и камень!</ru>
		<zh-CN>我要找出铁矿及石材！</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Encontrarei o ferro e a pedra!</pt-BR>
		<ko>나는 철과 석재를 찾을 것이다!</ko>
		<fixja>鉄と石を見つけよう！</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_STUDY_RICHES_OF_THE_HILLS_OPTION_1</zType>
		<en-US>No enemy will ever dare set foot in our country!</en-US>
		<es>¡Ningún enemigo pondrá un pie en nuestro país!</es>
		<de>„Kein Feind wird es jemals wagen, einen Fuß in unser Land zu setzen!“</de>
		<fr>Aucun ennemi n'osera jamais fouler le sol de notre pays !</fr>
		<ja>敵を我が領土に入れてはならない！</ja>
		<zh-TW>任何敵人都不會有膽踏上我們的領土！</zh-TW>
		<ru>Никто не дерзнет посягнуть на наши богатства!</ru>
		<zh-CN>任何敌人都不会有胆踏上我们的领土！</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Nenhum inimigo ousará pisar em nosso país!</pt-BR>
		<ko>그 어떤 적도 우리의 영토에 감히 발을 들이지 못한다!</ko>
		<fixja>敵を我が領土に入れてはならない！</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_STUDY_THE_FAIREST_OF_LAWS_OPTION_0</zType>
		<en-US>Because our laws protect even the humblest of the king's subjects.</en-US>
		<es>Porque nuestras leyes protegen incluso al súbdito más humilde.</es>
		<de>Unsere Gesetze schützen selbst die einfachsten königlichen Untergebenen.</de>
		<fr>Car nos lois protègent même le plus humble des sujets du roi.</fr>
		<ja>我々の法律は、臣下の中でも特に身分の低い者まで保護するものだからである。</ja>
		<zh-TW>因為我們的法律就連國王最卑微的臣民都予以保護。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Потому что они защищают всех — от царя до последнего подданного.</ru>
		<zh-CN>因为我们的法律就连国王最卑微的臣民都予以保护。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Porque nossas leis protegem até o mais humilde dos súditos do rei.</pt-BR>
		<ko>우리의 법률은 왕의 백성 중 가장 미천한 자까지도 보호하기 때문입니다.</ko>
		<fixja>我々の法律は、臣下の中でも特に身分の低い者まで保護するものだからである。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_STUDY_THE_FAIREST_OF_LAWS_OPTION_1</zType>
		<en-US>Because our laws avoid punishment by death whenever possible.</en-US>
		<es>Porque nuestras leyes evitan la pena de muerte en la medida de lo posible.</es>
		<de>Unsere Gesetze vermeiden die Todesstrafe, wann immer es möglich ist.</de>
		<fr>Car nos lois évitent les condamnations à mort quand cela est possible.</fr>
		<ja>我々の法律は、可能な限り死刑を避けているからである。</ja>
		<zh-TW>因為我們的法路在許可的情況下都避免死刑的懲罰。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Потому что по нашим законам смерть — последнее из наказаний.</ru>
		<zh-CN>因为我们的法路在许可的情况下都避免死刑的惩罚。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Porque nossas leis evitam penas de morte sempre que possível.</pt-BR>
		<ko>우리의 법률은 죽음으로 죄를 다스리는 것을 최대한 피하려고 하기 때문입니다.</ko>
		<fixja>我々の法律は、可能な限り死刑を避けているからである。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_STUDY_A_THOUSAND_GODS_OPTION_0</zType>
		<en-US>We should strive to never offend any of the gods, for they hold our fate in their hands.</en-US>
		<es>Deberíamos esforzarnos por no ofender a ningún dios, ya que tienen nuestro destino en sus manos.</es>
		<de>Wir sollten uns bemühen, niemals eine der Gottheiten zu beleidigen, denn unser Schicksal liegt in ihren Händen.</de>
		<fr>Nous devrions nous évertuer de ne jamais offenser aucun des dieux, car ils ont notre destin entre leurs mains.</fr>
		<ja>いかなる神々も、決して怒らせてはならない。彼らは我々の運命を握っている。</ja>
		<zh-TW>我們應該努力不要冒犯任何神祈，因為我們的命運就掌握在祂們手中。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Мы должны делать все возможное, чтобы снискать их благословение. Ибо наша судьба — в их руках.</ru>
		<zh-CN>我们应该努力不要冒犯任何神祈，因为我们的命运就掌握在祂们手中。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Nós devemos tentar jamais ofender qualquer um dos deuses, pois eles têm nossos destinos em suas mãos.</pt-BR>
		<ko>"신들은 우리의 운명을 손에 쥐고 있기에 그 어떤 신에게도 거슬러서는 안 됩니다."</ko>
		<fixja>いかなる神々も、決して怒らせてはならない。彼らは我々の運命を握っている。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_STUDY_A_THOUSAND_GODS_OPTION_1</zType>
		<en-US>We must respect the faith of each of our people, for their strength is our strength.</en-US>
		<es>Debemos respetar la fe de cada uno de los nuestros, pues su fortaleza es nuestra fortaleza.</es>
		<de>Wir müssen den Glauben eines jeden in unserem Volk respektieren, denn ihre Stärke ist die unsere.</de>
		<fr>Nous devons respecter la foi de chacun de nos compatriotes, car leur force fait notre propre force.</fr>
		<ja>我々は各国民が敬う信仰を尊重しなければならない。彼らの強さが我々の強さになる。</ja>
		<zh-TW>我們必須尊重所有人民的信仰，因為他們的力量就是我們的力量。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Мы должны уважать веру каждого человека, ибо наша сила — в единстве.</ru>
		<zh-CN>我们必须尊重所有人民的信仰，因为他们的力量就是我们的力量。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Nós devemos respeitar as fés de cada um de nossos povos, a força deles é nossa força.</pt-BR>
		<ko>"백성들의 힘이 곧 이 나라의 힘이므로 개개인의 믿음을 존중해야 합니다."</ko>
		<fixja>我々は各国民が敬う信仰を尊重しなければならない。彼らの強さが我々の強さになる。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_STUDY_THE_CITY_GATES_OPTION_0</zType>
		<en-US>The Lions Gate, stressing the courage of our warriors.</en-US>
		<es>La puerta del león, que muestra el valor de nuestros guerreros.</es>
		<de>Mit dem Löwentor, um den Mut unserer Krieger zu betonen.</de>
		<fr>La Porte des Lions, soulignant le courage de nos guerriers.</fr>
		<ja>獅子の門。戦士の勇気を強調している。</ja>
		<zh-TW>獅之門，強調我們戰士的勇氣。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Врата Льва демонстрируют отвагу наших воинов.</ru>
		<zh-CN>狮之门，强调我们战士的勇气。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>A Porta do Leão, para enfatizar a coragem de nossos guerreiros.</pt-BR>
		<ko>우리 전사들의 용기를 역설하는 사자의 문.</ko>
		<fixja>獅子の門。戦士の勇気を強調している。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_STUDY_THE_CITY_GATES_OPTION_1</zType>
		<en-US>The Sphinx Gate, emphasizing vigilance and the long sight of our people.</en-US>
		<es>La puerta de la esfinge, que enfatiza la cautela y la mirada atenta de nuestro pueblo.</es>
		<de>Mit dem Sphinxtor, um die Wachsamkeit und Weitsicht unseres Volkes zu unterstreichen.</de>
		<fr>La Porte des Sphinx, insistant sur la vigilance et la prévoyance de notre peuple.</fr>
		<ja>スフィンクスの門。我が民族の用心深さと先見の明を強調している。</ja>
		<zh-TW>斯芬克斯之門，強調我們人民的警覺及長遠的眼光。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Врата Сфинкса олицетворяют бдительность и дальновидность нашего народа.</ru>
		<zh-CN>斯芬克斯之门，强调我们人民的警觉及长远的眼光。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>A Porta da Esfinge, para enfatizar a atenção e a prudência de nosso povo.</pt-BR>
		<ko>우리 민족의 조심성과 선견지명을 강조하는 스핑크스의 문.</ko>
		<fixja>スフィンクスの門。我が民族の用心深さと先見の明を強調している。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_STUDY_THE_CITY_GATES_OPTION_2</zType>
		<en-US>The King's Gate, drawing attention to the resilience of our leaders.</en-US>
		<es>La puerta del rey, que saca a la luz la resistencia de nuestros líderes.</es>
		<de>Mit dem Königstor, um auf die Unverwüstlichkeit unserer Herrscher zu verweisen.</de>
		<fr>La Porte du Roi, attirant l'attention sur la ténacité de nos dirigeants.</fr>
		<ja>王の門。指導者たちの強靭さを強調している。</ja>
		<zh-TW>國王之門，把焦點放在我們的領導人的堅毅。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Врата Царей подчеркивают стойкость наших предводителей.</ru>
		<zh-CN>国王之门，把焦点放在我们的领导人的坚毅。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>A Porta do Rei, para enfatizar a resiliência de nossos líderes.</pt-BR>
		<ko>우리 지도자들의 끈기를 강조하는 왕의 문.</ko>
		<fixja>王の門。指導者たちの強靭さを強調している。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_BLESSING_OF_ARINNITTI_OPTION_0</zType>
		<en-US>So it shall be!</en-US>
		<es>¡Así sea!</es>
		<de>So sei es!</de>
		<fr>Il en sera ainsi !</fr>
		<ja>よかろう。</ja>
		<zh-TW>就這樣吧！</zh-TW>
		<ru>Да будет так!</ru>
		<zh-CN>就这样吧！</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Então que seja!</pt-BR>
		<ko>그렇다면 그리하겠다!</ko>
		<fixja>よかろう。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_BLESSING_OF_ARINNITTI_OPTION_1</zType>
		<en-US>Alas, I must honor Arinnitti from afar, the affairs of state demand every minute of daylight.</en-US>
		<es>Por desgracia, debo honrar a Arinnitti desde lejos, pues los asuntos del estado exigen hasta el último minuto de cada día.</es>
		<de>Ach! Leider muss ich Arinnitti aus der Ferne die Ehre erweisen, denn die Staatsangelegenheiten bedürfen jeder Minute meines Tages.</de>
		<fr>Hélas, il me faut honorer Arinnitti à distance, les affaires de l'État nécessitent ma présence toute la journée.</fr>
		<ja>残念だが、私は遠方からアリンニティを称える。国務以外の問題に割く時間がなくてね。</ja>
		<zh-TW>哎呀，我必須從遠方榮耀阿麗寧提，國家的事務佔據了我所有的辦公時間。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Я преклонюсь пред Ариннити, но здесь, не на ступенях святилища ее: царские дела не терпят отлагательств.</ru>
		<zh-CN>哎呀，我必须从远方荣耀阿丽宁提，国家的事务占据了我所有的办公时间。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Infelizmente, eu honrarei Arinnitti de longe, as questões do estado exigem cada minuto do meu dia.</pt-BR>
		<ko>애석하게도 나는 아린니티를 멀리서 기려야 한다. 국정을 잠시라도 놓을 수는 없다.</ko>
		<fixja>残念だが、私は遠方からアリンニティを称える。国務以外の問題に割く時間がなくてね。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_DEDICATION_OF_ARINNITTI_OPTION_0</zType>
		<en-US>Of course, it shall be my honor.</en-US>
		<es>Por supuesto, será un honor.</es>
		<de>Natürlich, es wird mir eine Ehre sein.</de>
		<fr>Bien sûr, ce sera un honneur pour moi.</fr>
		<ja>もちろん、参加させていただこう。</ja>
		<zh-TW>當然，那會是我的榮幸。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Разумеется, почту за честь.</ru>
		<zh-CN>当然，那会是我的荣幸。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>É claro, será uma honra.</pt-BR>
		<ko>물론이다. 오히려 내가 영광이다.</ko>
		<fixja>もちろん、参加させていただこう。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_DEDICATION_OF_ARINNITTI_OPTION_1</zType>
		<en-US>I fear I must decline, men as well as gods demand my attention.</en-US>
		<es>Me temo que debo rechazar, tanto los hombres como los dioses reclaman mi atención.</es>
		<de>Ich fürchte, ich muss ablehnen. Nicht nur die Götter, sondern auch die Menschen benötigen meine Aufmerksamkeit.</de>
		<fr>Je crains de devoir décliner, les hommes autant que les dieux demandent mon attention.</fr>
		<ja>残念ながら、断らねばならない。神々だけではなく、人々も私の関心を必要としているのだ。</ja>
		<zh-TW>我恐怕必須拒絕，人民和眾神一樣需要我的關注。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Боюсь, я {choice_GL:вынужден:вынуждена} отказать: моего внимания требуют как боги, так и люди.</ru>
		<zh-CN>我恐怕必须拒绝，人民和众神一样需要我的关注。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Infelizmente eu terei que recusar, os homens precisam da minha atenção tanto quanto os deuses.</pt-BR>
		<ko>안타깝게도 거절해야 한다. 신들 못지않게 백성들에게도 나의 관심이 필요하다.</ko>
		<fixja>残念ながら、断らねばならない。神々だけではなく、人々も私の関心を必要としているのだ。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_DISPLEASURE_OF_ARINNITTI_OPTION_0</zType>
		<en-US>I have been remiss. Please, accept my attendance and these sacrifices for the ceremony.</en-US>
		<es>Me he descuidado. Por favor, acepte mi asistencia y estos sacrificios para la ceremonia.</es>
		<de>Ich war nachlässig. Bitte akzeptiert meine Teilnahme und diese Opfer für die Zeremonie.</de>
		<fr>J'ai été {choice_GL:négligent:négligente}. Je vous prie d'accepter ma présence ainsi que ces sacrifices pour la cérémonie.</fr>
		<ja>私は神への努めを怠っていた。式典に参加する。どうか、捧げ物を受け取ってくれ。</ja>
		<zh-TW>是我疏忽了。請接受我的出席和儀式用的祭品。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Я {choice_GL:сбился:сбилась} с пути праведного. Прошу, прими мое согласие и эти дары для церемонии.</ru>
		<zh-CN>是我疏忽了。请接受我的出席和仪式用的祭品。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Eu tenho sido negligente. Por favor, aceite a minha presença e estes sacrifícios para a cerimônia.</pt-BR>
		<ko>내가 그동안 소홀했었다. 부디 나의 참석과 의식을 위한 제물을 받아 주게.</ko>
		<fixja>私は神への努めを怠っていた。式典に参加する。どうか、捧げ物を受け取ってくれ。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_DISPLEASURE_OF_ARINNITTI_OPTION_1</zType>
		<en-US>You presume too much. Be glad I yet suffer you to live, with such traitorous words in your mouth. Begone!</en-US>
		<es>Presumes demasiado. Da gracias a que te perdono la vida y dejo que sigas incordiándome, incluso tras escupir unas palabras tan traicioneras. ¡Largo!</es>
		<de>Ihr seid zu anmaßend. Seid froh, dass ich Euch trotz solch schändlicher Worte aus Eurem Mund noch leben lasse. Hinfort!</de>
		<fr>Vous supposez trop. Réjouissez-vous que je continue de tolérer votre existence, avec de tels mots perfides habitant votre bouche. Hors de ma vue !</fr>
		<ja>思い込みが激しすぎる。そのように反逆者のような言葉を並べるお前のことを、私はまだ生かしておいてやろう。嬉しく思うことだ。今すぐ、立ち去れ！</ja>
		<zh-TW>你的臆測太超過了。你的嘴竟然說出這種背叛之言，為我饒你一命感到慶幸吧。走開！</zh-TW>
		<ru>Не тебе судить {choice_GL:царя:царицу}. Стоило бы казнить тебя за такие речи, но я {choice_GL:милостив:милостива}. Прочь с глаз моих!</ru>
		<zh-CN>你的臆测太超过了。你的嘴竟然说出这种背叛之言，为我饶你一命感到庆幸吧。走开！</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Você assume demais. Contente-se que eu ainda permito que você viva, mesmo com essas palavras traidoras saindo de sua boca. Suma daqui!</pt-BR>
		<ko>과장이 심하군. 그런 반역적인 말을 입에 올리고도 목숨이 아직 붙어 있음에 감사하도록. 물러가라!</ko>
		<fixja>思い込みが激しすぎる。そのように反逆者のような言葉を並べるお前のことを、私はまだ生かしておいてやろう。嬉しく思うことだ。今すぐ、立ち去れ！</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_DISPLEASURE_OF_TARHUN_OPTION_0</zType>
		<en-US>I have been remiss. Please, accept my attendance and these sacrifices for the ceremony.</en-US>
		<es>Me he descuidado. Por favor, acepte mi asistencia y estos sacrificios para la ceremonia.</es>
		<de>Ich war nachlässig. Bitte akzeptiert meine Teilnahme und diese Opfer für die Zeremonie.</de>
		<fr>J'ai été {choice_GL:négligent:négligente}. Je vous prie d'accepter ma présence ainsi que ces sacrifices pour la cérémonie.</fr>
		<ja>私は神への努めを怠っていた。式典に参加する。どうか、捧げ物を受け取ってくれ。</ja>
		<zh-TW>是我疏忽了。請接受我的出席和儀式用的祭品。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Я {choice_GL:сбился:сбилась} с пути праведного. Прошу, прими мое согласие и эти дары для церемонии.</ru>
		<zh-CN>是我疏忽了。请接受我的出席和仪式用的祭品。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Eu tenho sido negligente. Por favor, aceite a minha presença e estes sacrifícios para a cerimônia.</pt-BR>
		<ko>내가 그동안 소홀했었다. 부디 나의 참석과 의식을 위한 제물을 받아 주게.</ko>
		<fixja>私は神への努めを怠っていた。式典に参加する。どうか、捧げ物を受け取ってくれ。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_DISPLEASURE_OF_TARHUN_OPTION_1</zType>
		<en-US>You cut close to the talk of traitors. Now let me pass, or we shall see who is to be slain by their own hubris.</en-US>
		<es>Tus palabras se asemejan demasiado a la de los traidores. Ahora, déjame pasar o veremos quién muere por su propia soberbia.</es>
		<de>Eure Worte gehen nur haarscharf am Verrat vorbei. Nun lasst mich gehen oder wir werden sehen, wen die Überheblichkeit zu Fall bringt.</de>
		<fr>Vous vous rapprochez dangereusement d'un discours de traître. Maintenant, laissez-moi passer, ou nous verrons qui mourra de son propre orgueil.</fr>
		<ja>まるで反逆者のような口の利き方だな。さあ、そこをどくのだ。さもなくば、己の驕りに身を滅ぼすことになるのは貴様のほうだぞ。</ja>
		<zh-TW>你說的話和叛徒沒兩樣。現在就讓我通過，不然我們就來看看是誰被自己的傲慢害死吧。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Подобные речи наводят на мысли об измене. С дороги, пока надменность и правда не стала чьей-то кончиной!</ru>
		<zh-CN>你说的话和叛徒没两样。现在就让我通过，不然我们就来看看是谁被自己的傲慢害死吧。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Suas palavras se parecem muito com as de traidores. Agora me deixe passar, ou veremos quem será morto por sua própria arrogância.</pt-BR>
		<ko>흡사 반역자 같은 말을 내뱉는군. 지금은 내버려두겠으나, 그 교만이 누구를 해칠지는 지켜볼 것이다.</ko>
		<fixja>まるで反逆者のような口の利き方だな。さあ、そこをどくのだ。さもなくば、己の驕りに身を滅ぼすことになるのは貴様のほうだぞ。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_DISPLEASURE_OF_KAMRUSEPA_OPTION_0</zType>
		<en-US>I shall seek forgiveness. Please, accept my attendance and these sacrifices for the ceremony.</en-US>
		<es>Buscaré el perdón. Por favor, acepte mi asistencia y estos sacrificios para la ceremonia.</es>
		<de>Ich werde um Vergebung bitten. Bitte akzeptiert meine Teilnahme und diese Opfer für die Zeremonie.</de>
		<fr>Je vais demander pardon. Je vous prie d'accepter ma présence ainsi que ces sacrifices pour la cérémonie.</fr>
		<ja>許しを請わなければ。式典に参加する。どうか、捧げ物を受け取ってくれ。</ja>
		<zh-TW>我應該祈求原諒。請接受我的出席和儀式用的祭品。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Я буду молить об искуплении. Прошу, прими мое согласие и эти дары для церемонии.</ru>
		<zh-CN>我应该祈求原谅。请接受我的出席和仪式用的祭品。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Eu buscarei o perdão. Por favor, aceite a minha presença e estes sacrifícios para a cerimônia.</pt-BR>
		<ko>용서를 구하겠다. 부디 나의 참석과 의식을 위한 제물을 받아 주게.</ko>
		<fixja>許しを請わなければ。式典に参加する。どうか、捧げ物を受け取ってくれ。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_DISPLEASURE_OF_KAMRUSEPA_OPTION_1</zType>
		<en-US>I too smell the stench of rot in this court, and it billows out from priestly robes. Now begone!</en-US>
		<es>Yo también huelo la podredumbre nauseabunda en esta corte, y procede de los hábitos sacerdotales. ¡Ahora largo!</es>
		<de>Ich rieche ebenfalls diesen Gestank am Hofe und er entweicht den Priesterroben. Und nun hinfort!</de>
		<fr>Je sens moi aussi l'odeur nauséabonde de la pourriture dans cette cour et elle s'échappe des robes liturgiques. Maintenant, disparaissez !</fr>
		<ja>確かに私も宮廷で腐臭を感じていたところだ。どうやら、その匂いの発生源は司祭どものローブのようだな。さあ今すぐ、立ち去れ！</ja>
		<zh-TW>我也在這個宮廷中聞到了腐朽的臭味，它就來自於祭司的長袍。現在就給我離開！</zh-TW>
		<ru>Я тоже чувствую запах гнили. И исходит он от жреческих ряс. Поди прочь!</ru>
		<zh-CN>我也在这个宫廷中闻到了腐朽的臭味，它就来自于祭司的长袍。现在就给我离开！</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Eu também sinto o cheiro da podridão nesta corte, e ele vem de trajes sacerdotais. Agora suma!</pt-BR>
		<ko>저 사제복에 깃든 악취가 궁정에 짙게 감도는군. 당장 물러가라!</ko>
		<fixja>確かに私も宮廷で腐臭を感じていたところだ。どうやら、その匂いの発生源は司祭どものローブのようだな。さあ今すぐ、立ち去れ！</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_DISPLEASURE_OF_HALKI_OPTION_0</zType>
		<en-US>I shall seek forgiveness. Please, accept my attendance and these sacrifices for the ceremony.</en-US>
		<es>Buscaré el perdón. Por favor, acepte mi asistencia y estos sacrificios para la ceremonia.</es>
		<de>Ich werde um Vergebung bitten. Bitte akzeptiert meine Teilnahme und diese Opfer für die Zeremonie.</de>
		<fr>Je vais demander pardon. Je vous prie d'accepter ma présence ainsi que ces sacrifices pour la cérémonie.</fr>
		<ja>許しを請わなければ。式典に参加する。どうか、捧げ物を受け取ってくれ。</ja>
		<zh-TW>我應該祈求原諒。請接受我的出席和儀式用的祭品。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Я буду молить об искуплении. Прошу, прими мое согласие и эти дары для церемонии.</ru>
		<zh-CN>我应该祈求原谅。请接受我的出席和仪式用的祭品。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Eu buscarei o perdão. Por favor, aceite a minha presença e estes sacrifícios para a cerimônia.</pt-BR>
		<ko>용서를 구하겠다. 부디 나의 참석과 의식을 위한 제물을 받아 주게.</ko>
		<fixja>許しを請わなければ。式典に参加する。どうか、捧げ物を受け取ってくれ。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_DISPLEASURE_OF_HALKI_OPTION_1</zType>
		<en-US>The gods may be mighty, but you are but an inflated blowfly. Begone!</en-US>
		<es>Puede que los dioses sean poderosos, pero tú no eres más que un moscardón pomposo. ¡Largo de aquí!</es>
		<de>Die Götter mögen mächtig sein, doch Ihr seid nicht mehr als eine fette Schmeißfliege. Hinfort!</de>
		<fr>Les dieux sont peut-être puissants, mais vous n'êtes qu'une mouche à viande gonflée. Hors de ma vue !</fr>
		<ja>確かに神々は強大な存在だ。だが、貴様は思い上がったウジ虫に過ぎない。今すぐ、立ち去れ！</ja>
		<zh-TW>諸神或許強大，但你只不過是隻自我膨脹的蒼蠅。走開！</zh-TW>
		<ru>Боги могущественны, это так. А вот ты — лишь жалкая жирная муха. Исчезни с глаз моих!</ru>
		<zh-CN>诸神或许强大，但你只不过是只自我膨胀的苍蝇。走开！</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Os deuses podem ser poderosos, mas você não passa de uma mosca soberba. Suma!</pt-BR>
		<ko>신들이 위대할지는 몰라도, 네놈은 살찐 쉬파리에 불과하다. 물러가라!</ko>
		<fixja>確かに神々は強大な存在だ。だが、貴様は思い上がったウジ虫に過ぎない。今すぐ、立ち去れ！</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_DEDICATION_OF_TARHUN_OPTION_0</zType>
		<en-US>The gods must be respected, we shall attend.</en-US>
		<es>Hay que respetar a los dioses; acudiremos.</es>
		<de>Den Göttern muss Respekt gezollt werden. Wir werden anwesend sein.</de>
		<fr>Les dieux doivent être respectés, nous serons présents.</fr>
		<ja>神々は尊重されなければならない。出席しよう。</ja>
		<zh-TW>我們必須尊敬眾神，我們會參加的。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Воля богов — закон. Я явлюсь на церемонию.</ru>
		<zh-CN>我们必须尊敬众神，我们会参加的。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Os deuses devem ser respeitados, nós iremos.</pt-BR>
		<ko>신들은 존경을 받아야 마땅하니 참석하는 것이 옳다.</ko>
		<fixja>神々は尊重されなければならない。出席しよう。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_DEDICATION_OF_TARHUN_OPTION_1</zType>
		<en-US>I fear I must decline, men as well as gods demand my attention.</en-US>
		<es>Me temo que debo rechazar, tanto los hombres como los dioses reclaman mi atención.</es>
		<de>Ich fürchte, ich muss ablehnen. Nicht nur die Götter, sondern auch die Menschen benötigen meine Aufmerksamkeit.</de>
		<fr>Je crains de devoir décliner, les hommes autant que les dieux demandent mon attention.</fr>
		<ja>残念ながら、断らねばならない。神々だけではなく、人々も私の関心を必要としているのだ。</ja>
		<zh-TW>我恐怕必須拒絕，人民和眾神一樣需要我的關注。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Боюсь, я {choice_GL:вынужден:вынуждена} отказать: моего внимания требуют как боги, так и люди.</ru>
		<zh-CN>我恐怕必须拒绝，人民和众神一样需要我的关注。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Infelizmente eu terei que recusar, os homens precisam da minha atenção tanto quanto os deuses.</pt-BR>
		<ko>안타깝게도 거절해야 한다. 신들 못지않게 백성들에게도 나의 관심이 필요하다.</ko>
		<fixja>残念ながら、断らねばならない。神々だけではなく、人々も私の関心を必要としているのだ。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_DEDICATION_OF_KAMRUSEPA_OPTION_0</zType>
		<en-US>The gods must be respected, we shall attend.</en-US>
		<es>Hay que respetar a los dioses; acudiremos.</es>
		<de>Den Göttern muss Respekt gezollt werden. Wir werden anwesend sein.</de>
		<fr>Les dieux doivent être respectés, nous serons présents.</fr>
		<ja>神々は尊重されなければならない。出席しよう。</ja>
		<zh-TW>我們必須尊敬眾神，我們會參加的。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Воля богов — закон. Я явлюсь на церемонию.</ru>
		<zh-CN>我们必须尊敬众神，我们会参加的。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Os deuses devem ser respeitados, nós iremos.</pt-BR>
		<ko>신들은 존경을 받아야 마땅하니 참석하는 것이 옳다.</ko>
		<fixja>神々は尊重されなければならない。出席しよう。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_DEDICATION_OF_KAMRUSEPA_OPTION_1</zType>
		<en-US>I fear I must decline, men as well as gods demand my attention.</en-US>
		<es>Me temo que debo rechazar, tanto los hombres como los dioses reclaman mi atención.</es>
		<de>Ich fürchte, ich muss ablehnen. Nicht nur die Götter, sondern auch die Menschen benötigen meine Aufmerksamkeit.</de>
		<fr>Je crains de devoir décliner, les hommes autant que les dieux demandent mon attention.</fr>
		<ja>残念ながら、断らねばならない。神々だけではなく、人々も私の関心を必要としているのだ。</ja>
		<zh-TW>我恐怕必須拒絕，人民和眾神一樣需要我的關注。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Боюсь, я {choice_GL:вынужден:вынуждена} отказать: моего внимания требуют как боги, так и люди.</ru>
		<zh-CN>我恐怕必须拒绝，人民和众神一样需要我的关注。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Infelizmente eu terei que recusar, os homens precisam da minha atenção tanto quanto os deuses.</pt-BR>
		<ko>안타깝게도 거절해야 한다. 신들 못지않게 백성들에게도 나의 관심이 필요하다.</ko>
		<fixja>残念ながら、断らねばならない。神々だけではなく、人々も私の関心を必要としているのだ。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_DEDICATION_OF_HALKI_OPTION_0</zType>
		<en-US>The gods must be respected, we shall attend.</en-US>
		<es>Hay que respetar a los dioses; acudiremos.</es>
		<de>Den Göttern muss Respekt gezollt werden. Wir werden anwesend sein.</de>
		<fr>Les dieux doivent être respectés, nous serons présents.</fr>
		<ja>神々は尊重されなければならない。出席しよう。</ja>
		<zh-TW>我們必須尊敬眾神，我們會參加的。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Воля богов — закон. Я явлюсь на церемонию.</ru>
		<zh-CN>我们必须尊敬众神，我们会参加的。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Os deuses devem ser respeitados, nós iremos.</pt-BR>
		<ko>신들은 존경을 받아야 마땅하니 참석하는 것이 옳다.</ko>
		<fixja>神々は尊重されなければならない。出席しよう。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_DEDICATION_OF_HALKI_OPTION_1</zType>
		<en-US>I fear I must decline, men as well as gods demand my attention.</en-US>
		<es>Me temo que debo rechazar, tanto los hombres como los dioses reclaman mi atención.</es>
		<de>Ich fürchte, ich muss ablehnen. Nicht nur die Götter, sondern auch die Menschen benötigen meine Aufmerksamkeit.</de>
		<fr>Je crains de devoir décliner, les hommes autant que les dieux demandent mon attention.</fr>
		<ja>残念ながら、断らねばならない。神々だけではなく、人々も私の関心を必要としているのだ。</ja>
		<zh-TW>我恐怕必須拒絕，人民和眾神一樣需要我的關注。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Боюсь, я {choice_GL:вынужден:вынуждена} отказать: моего внимания требуют как боги, так и люди.</ru>
		<zh-CN>我恐怕必须拒绝，人民和众神一样需要我的关注。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Infelizmente eu terei que recusar, os homens precisam da minha atenção tanto quanto os deuses.</pt-BR>
		<ko>안타깝게도 거절해야 한다. 신들 못지않게 백성들에게도 나의 관심이 필요하다.</ko>
		<fixja>残念ながら、断らねばならない。神々だけではなく、人々も私の関心を必要としているのだ。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_BLESSING_OF_TARHUN_OPTION_0</zType>
		<en-US>So it shall be!</en-US>
		<es>¡Así sea!</es>
		<de>So sei es!</de>
		<fr>Il en sera ainsi !</fr>
		<ja>参加しよう。</ja>
		<zh-TW>就這樣吧！</zh-TW>
		<ru>Да будет так!</ru>
		<zh-CN>就这样吧！</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Então que seja!</pt-BR>
		<ko>그렇다면 그리하겠다!</ko>
		<fixja>参加しよう。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_BLESSING_OF_TARHUN_OPTION_1</zType>
		<en-US>Alas, I must beg Tarhun's patience. There is much else to be done.</en-US>
		<es>Por desgracia, debo rogar paciencia a Tarhu. Hay mucho por hacer.</es>
		<de>Leider muss ich Tarḫunna um Geduld bitten. Es gibt so viel anderes zu tun.</de>
		<fr>Hélas, il me faut implorer la patience de Tarhun. J'ai beaucoup à faire.</fr>
		<ja>残念だが、タルフンには我慢してもらわなければならない。他にもやるべきことはたくさんある。</ja>
		<zh-TW>哎呀，我必須請求塔爾亨耐心以對。還有好多其他事情要做。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Да простит меня великий Тархунт, но я не могу покинуть дворец.</ru>
		<zh-CN>哎呀，我必须请求塔尔亨耐心以对。还有好多其他事情要做。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Infelizmente, eu devo pedir paciência a Tarhun. Há muito o que ser feito.</pt-BR>
		<ko>애석하게도 타르훈의 인내에 간청해야겠구나. 해야만 하는 일이 많다.</ko>
		<fixja>残念だが、タルフンには我慢してもらわなければならない。他にもやるべきことはたくさんある。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_BLESSING_OF_KAMRUSEPA_OPTION_0</zType>
		<en-US>This is wise counsel.</en-US>
		<es>Un consejo muy sabio.</es>
		<de>Das ist ein weiser Rat.</de>
		<fr>Voici un sage conseil.</fr>
		<ja>賢明な助言だ。</ja>
		<zh-TW>這是一個睿智的建議。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Спасибо за мудрый совет.</ru>
		<zh-CN>这是一个睿智的建议。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Este é um sábio conselho.</pt-BR>
		<ko>현명한 조언이다.</ko>
		<fixja>賢明な助言だ。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_BLESSING_OF_KAMRUSEPA_OPTION_1</zType>
		<en-US>Alas, a dream is but a dream and there is much else to be done.</en-US>
		<es>Por desgracia, un sueño no es más que eso, y hay mucho más que hacer.</es>
		<de>Ach, ein Traum ist bloß ein Traum und es gibt noch so viel anderes zu tun.</de>
		<fr>Hélas, un rêve n'est qu'un rêve et j'ai beaucoup à faire.</fr>
		<ja>夢は夢に過ぎない。他にやるべきことが山ほどある。</ja>
		<zh-TW>哎呀，夢不過就是夢，而且我還有好多其他事情要做。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Видится мне, то был всего лишь дурной сон.</ru>
		<zh-CN>哎呀，梦不过就是梦，而且我还有好多其他事情要做。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Infelizmente, um sonho é um sonho e há muito o que ser feito.</pt-BR>
		<ko>애석하게도 꿈은 꿈에 불과하며, 해야만 하는 일은 많구나.</ko>
		<fixja>夢は夢に過ぎない。他にやるべきことが山ほどある。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_BLESSING_OF_HALKI_OPTION_0</zType>
		<en-US>I shall attend, let us drink to the greatness of Halki!</en-US>
		<es>Asistiré, ¡bebamos por la grandeza de Halki!</es>
		<de>Ich werde dabei sein, lasst uns auf die Herrlichkeit von Ḫalki trinken!</de>
		<fr>J'assisterai à la cérémonie, buvons à la grandeur d'Halki !</fr>
		<ja>参加する。ハルキの偉大さを祝して乾杯しよう。</ja>
		<zh-TW>我會參加的，讓我們為哈爾基的偉大舉杯吧！</zh-TW>
		<ru>Разумеется! Выпьем же за великую Халки!</ru>
		<zh-CN>我会参加的，让我们为哈尔基的伟大举杯吧！</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Estarei presente, vamos beber à grandeza de Halki!</pt-BR>
		<ko>참석해서 할키의 위대함을 위해 건배하리라!</ko>
		<fixja>参加する。ハルキの偉大さを祝して乾杯しよう。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_BLESSING_OF_HALKI_OPTION_1</zType>
		<en-US>Alas, other matters are most pressing.</en-US>
		<es>Lamentablemente, hay otros asuntos más apremiantes.</es>
		<de>Leider muss ich meine Aufmerksamkeit dringlicheren Angelegenheiten schenken.</de>
		<fr>Hélas, il y a des affaires plus urgentes.</fr>
		<ja>残念ながら、他に優先すべきことがある。</ja>
		<zh-TW>哎呀，其他事情是最緊迫的。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Увы, дела нации не терпят отлагательств.</ru>
		<zh-CN>哎呀，其他事情是最紧迫的。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Infelizmente, outros assuntos são mais urgentes.</pt-BR>
		<ko>애석하게도 다른 문제가 산적해 있다.</ko>
		<fixja>残念ながら、他に優先すべきことがある。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_THE_SALT_OF_THE_EARTH_OPTION_0</zType>
		<en-US>Well in that case, we should certainly keep a closer eye on its exploitation.</en-US>
		<es>Bueno, en ese caso, deberíamos vigilar de cerca su explotación.</es>
		<de>Wenn dem so ist, sollten wir ein genaues Auge auf seine Nutzung haben.</de>
		<fr>Dans ce cas, nous devrions surveiller de plus près son exploitation.</fr>
		<ja>そういうことであれば、その貿易について注視していく必要がある。</ja>
		<zh-TW>嗯，這樣的話，我們一定得密切注意它的開採。</zh-TW>
		<ru>В таком случае мы будем следить за тем, куда она уходит.</ru>
		<zh-CN>嗯，这样的话，我们一定得密切注意它的开采。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Bem, neste caso, devemos ficar de olho em sua exploração.</pt-BR>
		<ko>그렇다면 이번 개척을 엄중히 주시해야 한다.</ko>
		<fixja>そういうことであれば、その貿易について注視していく必要がある。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_THE_SALT_OF_THE_EARTH_OPTION_1</zType>
		<en-US>By royal charter the {FAMILY-3} will have the exclusivity of link(RESOURCE_SALT) trade!</en-US>
		<es>¡Por privilegio real, la exclusividad del comercio de la link(RESOURCE_SALT) pertenece a la familia {FAMILY-3}!</es>
		<de>Der königliche Charta nach haben die {FAMILY-3,1} ein exklusives Recht auf den link(RESOURCE_SALT)handel!</de>
		<fr>Par charte royale, la famille des {FAMILY-3} jouira du monopole du commerce de link(RESOURCE_SALT) !</fr>
		<ja>王室が許可し、{FAMILY-3}にlink(RESOURCE_SALT)の貿易事業を独占させる。</ja>
		<zh-TW>根據皇家特許，{FAMILY-3}將擁有link(RESOURCE_SALT)的獨家貿易權！</zh-TW>
		<ru>Этим царским указом я наделяю {FAMILY-3,3} исключительным правом на торговлю {lowercase:link(RESOURCE_SALT,4)}!</ru>
		<zh-CN>根据皇家特许，{FAMILY-3}将拥有link(RESOURCE_SALT)的独家贸易权！</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>A família {FAMILY-3} terá a exclusividade para o comércio de link(RESOURCE_SALT), com uma licença real!</pt-BR>
		<ko>왕실이 {FAMILY-3} 가문의 link(RESOURCE_SALT) 교역 독점권을 인가하겠다!</ko>
		<fixja>王室が許可し、{FAMILY-3}にlink(RESOURCE_SALT)の貿易事業を独占させる。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_THE_SALT_OF_THE_EARTH_OPTION_2</zType>
		<en-US>Is that so? Benefits from the trade of link(RESOURCE_SALT) shall go to the royal coffers!</en-US>
		<es>¿Ah, sí? ¡Pues los beneficios del comercio de link(RESOURCE_SALT) irán directos a las arcas reales!</es>
		<de>Ist dem so? Dann sollen die Gewinne beim Handel des link(RESOURCE_SALT,2) den königlichen Schatzkammern zugutekommen!</de>
		<fr>C'est le cas ? Alors les bénéfices du commerce de link(RESOURCE_SALT) iront dans les caisses royales !</fr>
		<ja>それは良いことを聞いた。link(RESOURCE_SALT)の貿易事業による利益は、王室の宝物庫に入ることになる。</ja>
		<zh-TW>是這樣嗎？link(RESOURCE_SALT)貿易的獲利應該進到國庫！</zh-TW>
		<ru>Вот как? Что ж, прибыль от торговли {lowercase:link(RESOURCE_SALT,4)} пойдет прямиком в казну!</ru>
		<zh-CN>是这样吗？ link(RESOURCE_SALT)贸易的获利应该进到国库！</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>É mesmo? Os benefícios do comércio de link(RESOURCE_SALT) irão para os cofres reais!</pt-BR>
		<ko>그렇단 말이지? link(RESOURCE_SALT)의 교역으로 발생하는 수익은 왕실 재정에 귀속될 것이다!</ko>
		<fixja>それは良いことを聞いた。link(RESOURCE_SALT)の貿易事業による利益は、王室の宝物庫に入ることになる。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_GREATEST_CAVALRY_BATTLE_OF_ALL_TIMES_WINNER_LEADER</zType>
		<en-US>I found the mass of chariots in whose midst I was, scattering them before my horses!</en-US>
		<es>¡Me rodeaban carros y caballos mientras los dispersábamos!</es>
		<de>Ich fand die vielen Streitwagen, die mich umringten, und trieb sie vor meinen Pferden auseinander!</de>
		<fr>Je me retrouvai au milieu d'une masse de chars, les dispersant devant mes chevaux !</fr>
		<ja>戦車の大群を見つけ、我が騎兵隊を率いて敵を蹴散らしてやった。</ja>
		<zh-TW>我站在大批的戰車之中，看著他們在我的馬匹前倉皇四散！</zh-TW>
		<ru>Сквозь вражеское полчище {choice_GL:прорвался:прорвалась} я на могучем скакуне!</ru>
		<zh-CN>我站在大批的战车之中，看着他们在我的马匹前仓皇四散！</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Eu dissipei a massa de carros que me cercava e os dispersei ante meus cavalos!</pt-BR>
		<ko>나는 전차의 군세 속에서 적들이 내 말 앞에서 흩어지는 광경을 지켜보았다!</ko>
		<fixja>戦車の大群を見つけ、我が騎兵隊を率いて敵を蹴散らしてやった。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_WORTHY_OPPONENTS_PEACE_OFFER_GRANTED</zType>
		<en-US>We welcome peace with {PLAYER-0}.</en-US>
		<es>Aceptamos la paz con {PLAYER-0}.</es>
		<de>Wir begrüßen den Frieden mit {PLAYER-0,2}.</de>
		<fr>Nous accueillons la paix avec {PLAYER-0}.</fr>
		<ja>{PLAYER-0}との和平を歓迎する。</ja>
		<zh-TW>我們歡迎和{PLAYER-0}之間的和平。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Мы рады миру с {PLAYER-0,4}.</ru>
		<zh-CN>我们欢迎和{PLAYER-0}之间的和平。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Nós aceitamos a paz com {PLAYER-0,4}.</pt-BR>
		<ko>기쁘게 {PLAYER-0}(과)와 평화를 체결하겠다.</ko>
		<fixja>{PLAYER-0}との和平を歓迎する。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_WORTHY_OPPONENTS_PEACE_OFFER_DENIED</zType>
		<en-US>We beat them. We don't need treaties!</en-US>
		<es>Ya los vencimos. ¡No necesitamos tratados!</es>
		<de>Wir haben sie besiegt. Wir brauchen keine Verträge!</de>
		<fr>Nous les avons battus. Nous n'avons pas besoin de traités !</fr>
		<ja>いや、最後まで戦おう。和平など必要ない！</ja>
		<zh-TW>我們打敗了他們。我們不需要協議！</zh-TW>
		<ru>С чего бы нам заключать мир с теми, кого мы сокрушили?!</ru>
		<zh-CN>我们打败了他们。我们不需要协议！</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Nós vencemos. Não precisamos de tratados!</pt-BR>
		<ko>우리는 놈들을 무찔렀다. 조약 따위는 필요 없다!</ko>
		<fixja>いや、最後まで戦おう。和平など必要ない！</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_WORTHY_OPPONENTS_TRUCE_GRANTED</zType>
		<en-US>Agreed! Let us put an end to the fighting for now.</en-US>
		<es>¡Concuerdo! Pongámosle fin a la lucha por ahora.</es>
		<de>Einverstanden, lasst uns dem Krieg für Erste ein Ende bereiten.</de>
		<fr>Entendu ! Mettons fin aux hostilités pour le moment.</fr>
		<ja>同意見だ。ひとまず、戦いは終わりにしよう。</ja>
		<zh-TW>我同意！讓我們暫且把戰爭拋諸腦後吧。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Да будет так! Положим конец войне.</ru>
		<zh-CN>我同意！让我们暂且把战争抛诸脑后吧。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>De acordo! Vamos dar fim às lutas por enquanto.</pt-BR>
		<ko>동의한다! 일단은 이 싸움을 끝내자.</ko>
		<fixja>同意見だ。ひとまず、戦いは終わりにしよう。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_WORTHY_OPPONENTS_TRUCE_DENIED</zType>
		<en-US>No.</en-US>
		<es>No.</es>
		<de>Nein.</de>
		<fr>Non.</fr>
		<ja>拒絶する。</ja>
		<zh-TW>否。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Нет.</ru>
		<zh-CN>否。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Não.</pt-BR>
		<ko>거절한다.</ko>
		<fixja>拒絶する。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_HITTITE_CONTACT_BABYLON_KINGMAKERS_OPTION_0</zType>
		<en-US>Let them remember: They owe us!</en-US>
		<es>¡Que recuerden lo que nos deben!</es>
		<de>An eins sollen sie sich erinnern: Sie schulden uns etwas!</de>
		<fr>Qu'ils s'en souviennent : ils ont une dette envers nous !</fr>
		<ja>思い出させてやらねばならぬ。奴らは我々に借りがあるのだ。</ja>
		<zh-TW>讓他們記得：是他們欠我們人情！</zh-TW>
		<ru>Напомните им, по чьей милости они у власти!</ru>
		<zh-CN>让他们记得：是他们欠我们人情！</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Que eles se lembrem que estão em dívida conosco!</pt-BR>
		<ko>그들은 우리에게 진 빚이 있음을 기억해야 한다!</ko>
		<fixja>思い出させてやらねばならぬ。奴らは我々に借りがあるのだ。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_HITTITE_CONTACT_BABYLON_KINGMAKERS_OPTION_1</zType>
		<en-US>Actually, if they could pay back the favor now...</en-US>
		<es>La verdad es que podrían devolverme el favor ahora...</es>
		<de>Nun, wenn sie den Gefallen jetzt erwidern könnten …</de>
		<fr>En fait, s'ils pouvaient plutôt nous rendre la pareille maintenant…</fr>
		<ja>もし、今奴らが恩返しをしてくれるのであれば…。</ja>
		<zh-TW>老實說，如果他們現在可以還這個人情的話…</zh-TW>
		<ru>Думаю, им пора отплатить за такую услугу…</ru>
		<zh-CN>老实说，如果他们现在可以还这个人情的话…</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Na verdade, se eles pudessem pagar o favor agora...</pt-BR>
		<ko>그들이 지금이라도 은혜를 갚을지 궁금하군...</ko>
		<fixja>もし、今奴らが恩返しをしてくれるのであれば…。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_HITTITE_CONTACT_BABYLON_WOULDBE_KINGMAKERS_OPTION_0</zType>
		<en-US>I'm sure they'll forgive our intervention, in time...</en-US>
		<es>Tengo la certeza de que perdonarán nuestra intervención con el tiempo...</es>
		<de>Sicherlich werden sie uns dafür mit der Zeit vergeben …</de>
		<fr>Je suis {choice_GL:sûr:sûre} qu'ils oublieront notre intervention, avec le temps…</fr>
		<ja>そのうち、我々の干渉を許してくれるだろう…。</ja>
		<zh-TW>他們一定會原諒我們的干預的，總有一天會…</zh-TW>
		<ru>Не могут же они вечно на нас злиться…</ru>
		<zh-CN>他们一定会原谅我们的干预的，总有一天会…</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Tenho certeza que eles perdoarão nossa interferência, com o tempo...</pt-BR>
		<ko>언젠가 저들은 우리의 개입을 용서할 것이다...</ko>
		<fixja>そのうち、我々の干渉を許してくれるだろう…。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_HITTITE_CONTACT_BABYLON_WOULDBE_KINGMAKERS_OPTION_1</zType>
		<en-US>Let us bring gifts, to salve old grudges.</en-US>
		<es>Llevemos regalos para calmar estas disputas antiguas.</es>
		<de>Bringen wir Geschenke, um diesen Groll zu besänftigen.</de>
		<fr>Amenons des cadeaux, pour apaiser les vieilles rancunes.</fr>
		<ja>昔のわだかまりを解消するために、贈り物を持参しよう。</ja>
		<zh-TW>讓我們帶禮物去，來解開過去的恩怨。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Щедрое подношение поможет унять боль старых ран.</ru>
		<zh-CN>让我们带礼物去，来解开过去的恩怨。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Vamos levar presentes, para apaziguar disputas antigas.</pt-BR>
		<ko>오랜 원한을 풀도록 선물을 보내자.</ko>
		<fixja>昔のわだかまりを解消するために、贈り物を持参しよう。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_EVENTSTORY_BABYLON_CONTACT_HITTITE_ANCIENT_SACK_OPTION_0</zType>
		<en-US>And the {FAMILY-4,3} have ruled the city wisely ever since.</en-US>
		<es>Y la familia {FAMILY-4} ha gobernado la ciudad con sabiduría desde entonces.</es>
		<de>Und die {FAMILY-4,1} haben die Stadt seit jenem Tage klug verwaltet.</de>
		<fr>Et depuis ce temps, les {FAMILY-4} ont régné sur la cité avec sagesse.</fr>
		<ja>それ以来、{FAMILY-4,3}は賢く都市を支配してきた。</ja>
		<zh-TW>而在那之後，{FAMILY-4,3}明理地統治著城市。</zh-TW>
		<ru>И {FAMILY-4,6} мудро правили городом все это время.</ru>
		<zh-CN>而在那之后，{FAMILY-4,3}明理地统治着城市。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>E os {FAMILY-4,1} governam a cidade sabiamente desde então.</pt-BR>
		<ko>그때부터 {FAMILY-4,3} 가문이 도시를 현명하게 지배해 왔다.</ko>
		<fixja>それ以来、{FAMILY-4,3}は賢く都市を支配してきた。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_EVENTSTORY_BABYLON_CONTACT_HITTITE_ANCIENT_SACK_OPTION_1</zType>
		<en-US>We will not easily forget this agression!</en-US>
		<es>¡No olvidaremos esta agresión tan fácilmente!</es>
		<de>Wir werden diesen Schlag nicht so schnell vergessen!</de>
		<fr>Nous n'oublierons pas facilement cette agression !</fr>
		<ja>あの侵略行為を簡単に忘れることはできない。</ja>
		<zh-TW>我們不會輕易忘記這個侵略行為！</zh-TW>
		<ru>Мы этого не забудем!</ru>
		<zh-CN>我们不会轻易忘记这个侵略行为！</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Não vamos esquecer essa agressão facilmente!</pt-BR>
		<ko>그 만행을 간단히 잊을쏘냐!</ko>
		<fixja>あの侵略行為を簡単に忘れることはできない。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_EVENTSTORY_BABYLON_CONTACT_HITTITE_ANCIENT_SACK_OPTION_2</zType>
		<en-US>This is ancient history now.</en-US>
		<es>Eso ya es cosa del pasado.</es>
		<de>Das liegt nun alles in der Vergangenheit.</de>
		<fr>C'est désormais de l'histoire ancienne.</fr>
		<ja>それはもう昔の話だ。</ja>
		<zh-TW>那已經是久遠的歷史了。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Кто старое помянет, тому глаз вон!</ru>
		<zh-CN>那已经是久远的历史了。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Isso já é história antiga agora.</pt-BR>
		<ko>이제는 고대 역사에 불과하다.</ko>
		<fixja>それはもう昔の話だ。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_STUDY_EDUCATION_AT_THE_PANKUS_OPTION_0</zType>
		<en-US>There is no better school of eloquence.</en-US>
		<es>No hay mejor sitio para aprender elocuencia.</es>
		<de>Es gibt keine bessere Rednerschule.</de>
		<fr>Il n'y a pas de meilleure école d'éloquence.</fr>
		<ja>雄弁を育むには最高の教育組織だ。</ja>
		<zh-TW>沒什麼比這更能訓練口才了。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Нету лучше школы красноречия.</ru>
		<zh-CN>没什么比这更能训练口才了。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Não há melhor escola de eloquência.</pt-BR>
		<ko>웅변을 배우기에 여기보다 나은 학교는 없다.</ko>
		<fixja>雄弁を育むには最高の教育組織だ。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_STUDY_EDUCATION_AT_THE_PANKUS_OPTION_1</zType>
		<en-US>Respect of the law is crucial to the education of all!</en-US>
		<es>¡El respeto a la ley es crucial para la educación de todos!</es>
		<de>Die Achtung des Rechts ist für alle eine wichtige Lektion!</de>
		<fr>Le respect de la loi est crucial à l'éducation de tous !</fr>
		<ja>法律を尊重することは、すべての者の教育に不可欠だ。</ja>
		<zh-TW>尊重法律對所有人的教育來說都至關重要！</zh-TW>
		<ru>Дети должны научиться чтить законы с ранних лет.</ru>
		<zh-CN>尊重法律对所有人的教育来说都至关重要！</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>O respeito às leis é fundamental para a educação de todos!</pt-BR>
		<ko>법의 존중은 모두에게 필수적인 교육이다!</ko>
		<fixja>法律を尊重することは、すべての者の教育に不可欠だ。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_HITTITE_UNIT_YES</zType>
		<en-US>{TEXT_EVENTOPTION_GREEK_UNIT_YES}</en-US>
		<es>{TEXT_EVENTOPTION_GREEK_UNIT_YES}</es>
		<de>{TEXT_EVENTOPTION_GREEK_UNIT_YES}</de>
		<fr>{TEXT_EVENTOPTION_GREEK_UNIT_YES}</fr>
		<ja>{TEXT_EVENTOPTION_GREEK_UNIT_YES}</ja>
		<zh-TW>{TEXT_EVENTOPTION_GREEK_UNIT_YES}</zh-TW>
		<ru>{TEXT_EVENTOPTION_GREEK_UNIT_YES}</ru>
		<zh-CN>{TEXT_EVENTOPTION_GREEK_UNIT_YES}</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>{TEXT_EVENTOPTION_GREEK_UNIT_YES}</pt-BR>
		<ko>{TEXT_EVENTOPTION_GREEK_UNIT_YES}</ko>
		<fixja>{TEXT_EVENTOPTION_GREEK_UNIT_YES}</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_NAMED_UNIT_MESEDI</zType>
		<en-US>And their leader should be honored too!</en-US>
		<es>¡Y habría que honrar a su líder también!</es>
		<de>Und {G1:ihr Anführer:ihre Anführerin} sollte ebenfalls gewürdigt werden!</de>
		<fr>Et leur chef devrait aussi recevoir les honneurs !</fr>
		<ja>喜んでそうしよう。団長も称えられるべきだ。</ja>
		<zh-TW>而他們的領袖也應該接受榮耀！</zh-TW>
		<ru>Не будем забывать и про их лидера!</ru>
		<zh-CN>而他们的领袖也应该接受荣耀！</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Seu líder deve receber homenagens também!</pt-BR>
		<ko>그들의 지휘자에게도 영광을 부여하리라!</ko>
		<fixja>喜んでそうしよう。団長も称えられるべきだ。</fixja>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTOPTION_NAMED_UNIT_GOLDEN_SPEARMEN</zType>
		<en-US>Let them shine in our name!</en-US>
		<es>¡Que brillen por nosotros!</es>
		<de>Sie sollen in unserem Namen glänzen!</de>
		<fr>Qu'ils rayonnent en notre nom !</fr>
		<ja>我が名のもとに、彼らにはさらに輝いてもらおう。</ja>
		<zh-TW>讓他們以我們之名閃耀吧！</zh-TW>
		<ru>Да воссияют они нашим именем!</ru>
		<zh-CN>让他们以我们之名闪耀吧！</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Que eles brilhem por nós!</pt-BR>
		<ko>우리의 이름으로 그들을 빛나게 하라!</ko>
		<fixja>我が名のもとに、彼らにはさらに輝いてもらおう。</fixja>
	</Entry>
</Root>