<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--This file is generated by the LocalizationEditor!-->
<Root>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_DYNASTY_AMANIRENA</zType>
		<en-US>Amanirenas</en-US>
		<es>Amanirenas</es>
		<de>Amanirenas</de>
		<fr>Amanirenas</fr>
		<ja>アマニレナス</ja>
		<zh-TW>阿瑪尼蕾娜斯</zh-TW>
		<ru>Аманирена</ru>
		<zh-CN>阿马尼蕾娜斯</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Amanirenas</pt-BR>
		<ko>아마니레나스</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_DYNASTY_AMANIRENA_DESCRIPTION</zType>
		<en-US>The Warrior Queen who led Kush against the Romans, attacking Roman-occupied Egypt and then defending Kush until Rome agreed to peace.</en-US>
		<es>La reina guerrera que lideró Kush contra los romanos. Amanirenas atacó a una Roma que ocupaba Egipto y defendió a Kush hasta que Roma accedió a un acuerdo de paz.</es>
		<de>Die Kriegerkönigin, die Kusch gegen die Römer anführte, das von den Römern besetzte Ägypten angriff und Kusch anschließend verteidigte, bis Rom einem Frieden zustimmte.</de>
		<fr>La reine guerrière qui a mené le royaume de Koush dans la guerre contre les Romains. Elle a attaqué l'Égypte, alors contrôlée par les Romains, puis a défendu son royaume jusqu'à ce que Rome accepte de conclure un accord de paix.</fr>
		<ja>クシュを率いてローマと戦い、ローマ配下のエジプトを攻撃し、ローマが和平に応じるまでクシュを守り抜いた戦士たる女王。</ja>
		<zh-TW>這位勇敢的女王領導庫什人對抗羅馬人，攻下了被羅馬佔領的埃及，誓死保衛庫什，直到羅馬同意談和。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Царица-воительница, возглавившая поход Куша против римлян. Она напала на захваченный римлянами Египет, а затем защищала Куш, пока Рим не согласился на мир.</ru>
		<zh-CN>这位勇武的女王领导库什人对抗罗马人，攻下了被罗马占领的埃及，并誓死保卫库什，直到罗马同意缔结合约。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>A rainha guerreira que liderou Cuxe contra os romanos em um ataque contra a ocupação romana do Egito e defendeu Cuxe até que Roma aceitasse um acordo de paz.</pt-BR>
		<ko>쿠시 왕국을 이끈 전사 여왕입니다. 로마가 평화 협정에 동의할 때까지 로마 치하의 이집트를 공격해 쿠시 왕국을 지켜 냈습니다.</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_DYNASTY_AMANITORE</zType>
		<en-US>Amanitore</en-US>
		<es>Amanitore</es>
		<de>Amanitore</de>
		<fr>Amanitore</fr>
		<ja>アマニトレ</ja>
		<zh-TW>阿瑪尼托蕾</zh-TW>
		<ru>Аманиторе</ru>
		<zh-CN>阿马尼托蕾</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Amanitore</pt-BR>
		<ko>아마니토레</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_DYNASTY_AMANITORE_DESCRIPTION</zType>
		<en-US>Amanitore is an unsurpassed builder, able to lead Kush into an age of prosperity. Her bonus orders mean that there is always time to be building.</en-US>
		<es>Una constructora sin igual, Amanitore llevó a Kush a una era de prosperidad. Sus órdenes adicionales son el modo de decir que siempre hay tiempo para construir algo.</es>
		<de>Amanitore ist eine meisterhaffe Baumeisterin, die Kusch in ein Zeitalter des Wohlstandes führen kann. Ihre Zusatzaufträge sorgen dafür, dass immer Zeit zum Bauen ist.</de>
		<fr>Amanitore était une bâtisseuse sans égale qui fit entrer le royaume de Koush dans une période de prospérité. Ses ordres bonus permettent de construire sans relâche.</fr>
		<ja>クシュを繁栄の時代へと導くことができる、比類なき建設者。彼女のボーナス付き命令書は、建設の時間的猶予が約束されていることを意味する。</ja>
		<zh-TW>阿瑪尼托蕾是一位卓越的城市規劃師，她帶領庫什進入了繁榮的時代。她可以下達額外命令，代表始終都有時間進行建設。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Аманиторе — непревзойденная зодчая, способная привести Куш к процветанию. Благодаря бонусным приказам у Куша всегда найдется время на большую стройку.</ru>
		<zh-CN>阿马尼托蕾是一位无与伦比的城市规划师，她带领库什进入了一个繁荣的时代。她可以下达额外命令，意味着始终有充裕的建城时间。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Amanitore é uma construtora insuperável, capaz de levar Cuxe a uma era de prosperidade. As ordens bônus dela garantem que sempre haja tempo para construir.</pt-BR>
		<ko>아마니토레는 쿠시를 번영의 시대로 이끈 걸출한 건축가입니다. 추가 명령권이 주어지므로 더욱 여유롭게 시설을 건축할 수 있습니다.</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_DYNASTY_AMANITORE_STORY</zType>
		<en-US>    I am Amanitore, Kandake and Queen of Meroe.

    My reign was a prosperous age for Kush, and I used this to lead an age of building across the nation. The temples of Napata were restored after their pillaging at the hands of the Romans and mortuary pyramids covered the land.

    Amani blessed us, and I built temples to honor him in cities across Kush. Although Meroe continued as capital, I ruled from my palace among the temples of Jebel Barkal.

    The name Amanitore will be remembered as the greatest of builders, my monuments and temples leaving a legacy for my nation.</en-US>
		<es>Soy Amanitore, candace y reina de Meroe.

Mi reino fue una época muy próspera para Kush en la que la nación vivió una etapa de desarrollo de construcciones. Los templos de Napata se restauraron tras sufrir saqueos por parte de los romanos y las pirámides mortuorias cubrieran el terreno.

Amani nos ofreció su bendición y construí templos en su honor en todas las ciudades de Kush. Aunque Meroe conservaba su estado de capital, goberné desde mi palacio y los templos de Gebel Barkal.

Mi nombre será recordado como la reina constructora y mis monumentos y templos serán el legado de mi nación.</es>
		<de>      Ich bin Amanitore, Kandake und Königin von Meroe.

      Meine Herrschaft bescherte Kusch eine Blütezeit, die ich dafür nutzte, um in der ganzen Nation Bauwerke zu errichten. Die Tempel von Nap wurden nach ihrer Plünderung durch die Römer wieder aufgebaut, und heute ist das ganze Land von Begräbnispyramiden bedeckt.

      Amani hat uns gesegnet, also habe ich in seinem Namen in den Städten in Kusch Tempel errichtet, um ihn zu ehren. Obwohl Meroe noch immer als Hauptstadt fungierte, regierte ich von meinem Palast aus, der sich bei den Tempeln des Berges Jebel Barkal befindet.

      Der Name Amanitore wird auf ewig im selben Atemzug mit den größten Erbauern der Welt genannt werden – und meine Monumente und Tempel werden meiner Nation ein beispielhaftes Erbe hinterlassen.</de>
		<fr>      Je suis Amanitore, Kandake et Reine de Méroé.

      Mon règne fut une période prospère pour Koush, et je m’en suis servie pour mener une ère de constructions dans l’ensemble de la nation. Les temples de Napata furent restaurés après leur pillage par les Romains et le pays fut couvert de pyramides mortuaires.

      Amani nous a bénis et j’ai construit des temples pour l’honorer dans les cités à travers Koush. Bien que Méroé reste la capitale, j’ai régné depuis mon palais parmi les temples de Jebel Barkal.

      On se souviendra du nom d’Amanitore comme de celui d’une grande bâtisseuse, qui laissa ses monuments et ses temples en héritage à sa nation.</fr>
		<ja>      私はアマニトレ。カンダケ、そしてメロエの女王。

      私の治世はクシュにとって繁栄の時代であり、この機会を利用して国を建設の時代へと導いた。ローマ人の手によって略奪された後、ナパタの神殿は復元され、その土地は墓所であるピラミッドで埋め尽くされた。

      アマニは私たちを祝福している。そのため、私はクシュの全都市にアマニを祀る神殿を建てた。首都としてメロエは存続していた。だが、私はゲベル・バルカルの神殿の中にある宮殿から統治した。

      アマニトレの名は偉大なる建築者として人々の記憶に刻まれ、我が記念碑や神殿は遺産として祖国に残るだろう。</ja>
		<zh-TW>      我是阿馬尼托蕾，麥羅埃的坎達克和女王。

      我的統治時期正是庫什的繁榮時期，我利用這段繁榮引領全國走進了建設的時代。納帕塔的神殿在被羅馬人掠奪後被重新修復，祭殿金字塔在這片土地上舉目皆是。

      阿馬尼向我們賜下了福蔭，我在庫什的各個城市都為他建造了神殿。雖然麥羅埃依然是首都，但我選擇在博爾戈爾山神殿中的宮殿裡實行統治。

      阿馬尼托蕾這個名字將會以「最偉大的建築者」身份被歷史銘記，我的紀念碑和神殿為我的國家留下了遺產。</zh-TW>
		<ru>      Я Аманиторе, кандакия и царица Мероэ.

      Мое правление стало эпохой расцвета Куша, и я воспользовалась этим, чтобы начать строительство в державе. Храмы Напаты, разграбленные римлянами, были восстановлены, и по всей стране были возведены погребальные пирамиды.

      Амани благоволит нам, и я построила в городах Куша храмы в его честь. Мероэ считался столицей, но я правила из своего дворца среди храмов Джебель-Баркала.

      Аманиторе будут помнить как великую строительницу. Мои монументы и храмы станут наследием моего народа.</ru>
		<zh-CN>      我是阿马尼托蕾，麦罗埃的坎达克和女王。

      我的统治时期正是库什的繁荣时期，我利用这段繁荣引领全国走进了建设的时代。纳帕塔的神殿在被罗马人掠夺后得到了修复，祭殿金字塔在这片土地上举目皆是。

      阿马尼向我们赐下了福荫，我在库什的各个城市都为他建造了神殿。虽然麦罗埃依然是首都，但我选择在博尔戈尔山神殿中的宫殿里实行统治。

      阿马尼托蕾这个名字将会以“最伟大的建筑者”身份被历史铭记，我的纪念碑和神殿为我的国家留下了传承。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Eu sou Amanitore, candace e rainha de Meroé.

Meu reinado foi uma época de prosperidade para Cuxe, e eu usei esse tempo para inaugurar uma era de construções por toda a nação. Os templos de Napata foram restaurados após terem sido saqueados pelos romanos e pirâmides mortuárias cobriram a terra.

Amani nos abençoou, e eu construí templos para homenageá-lo em cidades por todo Cuxe. Embora Meroé permanecera sendo a capital, eu governei de meu palácio entre os templos de Jebel Barcal.

O nome Amanitore será lembrado como o da maior das construtoras, meus monumentos e templos serão o legado da minha nação.</pt-BR>
		<ko>      나는 아마니토레, 칸다케이자 메로에의 여왕이다.

      나의 통치는 쿠시가 번영했던 시대였고, 이를 이용하여 국가 전역의 건축기를 이끌었다. 나파타의 사원들은 로마인들에 의해 약탈된 이후로 재건되었고, 장례용 피라미드가 땅을 뒤덮었다.

      아마니는 우리를 축복했고, 나는 쿠시 전역의 도시에서 그를 기렸다. 비록 메레오가 수도로 남았지만, 나는 게벨 바르칼의 사원에 있는 내 궁전에서 통치했다.

      아마니토레라는 이름은 위대한 건축가로 기억될 것이며, 나의 기념비와 사원들은 우리 국가에 유산을 남겼다.</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_DYNASTY_PIYE</zType>
		<en-US>Piye</en-US>
		<es>Piye</es>
		<de>Piye</de>
		<fr>Piânkhy</fr>
		<ja>ピイ</ja>
		<zh-TW>皮耶</zh-TW>
		<ru>Пианхи</ru>
		<zh-CN>皮耶</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Piiê</pt-BR>
		<ko>피예</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_DYNASTY_PIYE_DESCRIPTION</zType>
		<en-US>The zealous Piye, the Pharaoh who conquered Egypt, leads Kush in a holy war under the banner of the god Amani (known in Egypt as Amun). He gains new troops for spreading a pagan religion.</en-US>
		<es>Piye fue el faraón fanático que conquistó Egipto y lideró a Kush en una guerra santa bajo el pendón del dios Amani (conocido en Egipto como Amón). Obtiene tropas nuevas para difundir la religión pagana.</es>
		<de>Der fromme Piye, der Pharao, der Ägypten erobert hat, führt Kusch in einen heiligen Krieg unter dem Banner des Gottes Amani (in Ägypten als Amun bekannt). Er rekrutiert neue Truppen, um diese heidnische Religion zu verbreiten.</de>
		<fr>Le pieux Piânkhy, le pharaon qui conquit l'Égypte, a mené le royaume de Koush dans une guerre sainte au nom du dieu Amani (appelé « Amon » en Égypte). Il gagne de nouvelles unités lorsqu'il diffuse une religion païenne.</fr>
		<ja>エジプトを征服したファラオである、熱意溢れるピイは、クシュを率いてアマニ神（エジプトではアメン神）の旗の下で聖戦を繰り広げる。彼は異教を布教するため新たな部隊を手に入れる。</ja>
		<zh-TW>征服埃及的法老皮耶率領庫什人以阿瑪尼神（埃及人稱阿蒙神）之名發動了一場聖戰。他因傳播異教而獲得新的軍隊。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Истово верующий Пианхи — это фараон, захвативший Египет, который втравил Куш в священную войну под знаменем бога Амани, известного также под именем Амона. Он получает новые войска, распространяя свою языческую веру.</ru>
		<zh-CN>征服埃及的法老皮耶率领库什人以阿马尼神（埃及人称阿蒙神）之名发动了一场圣战。他因传播异教而获得了新的军队。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>O zeloso Piiê, o faraó que conquistou o Egito, lidera Cuxe em uma guerra santa sob a bandeira do deus Amani (conhecido no Egito como Ámon). Ele ganha novas tropas ao difundir sua religião pagã.</pt-BR>
		<ko>열성적인 피예는 이집트를 정복했던 파라오입니다. 피예 치하의 쿠시 왕국은 아마니(이집트의 아문)의 이름으로 성전을 벌였습니다. 피예에게는 다신교를 전파할 때 필요한 부대가 제공됩니다.</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_DYNASTY_PIYE_STORY</zType>
		<en-US>    I am Piye, Usimare and Sneferre, Pharaoh and conqueror of Egypt and devotee of Amani.

    Born to the throne of Kush and Upper Egypt, I watched as Lower Egypt fractured into infighting and dynastic squabbles. Following the call of Amani, the god the Egyptians call Amun, I sought to unite the lands under my rule. Despite the best efforts of the local kings to turn me back through coalitions, diplomacy, and warfare, Amani’s will could not be stopped.

    As Pharaoh I installed my family into roles of honor. The last hold-outs of resistance would be defeated by my son, who would inherit the lands of Kush and Egypt.

    My name will be remembered as the first of a Pharaonic dynasty of Egypt, ruler at the height of Kushite power and influence.</en-US>
		<es>Soy Piye, Usimare y Sneferre, faraón y conquistador de Egipto y adepto de Amani.

Mientras gobernaba Kush y el Alto Egipto fui testigo de cómo el Bajo Egipto se hacía añicos entre luchas internas y las riñas dinásticas. Desde mi puesto de poder intenté unir los territorios, de acuerdo con el llamado de Amani, el dios al que los egipcios llaman a Amón. Su voluntad se llevará a término a pesar de que los reyes locales se esfuerzan para acabar conmigo mediante coaliciones entre ellos, intercambios diplomáticos y guerras.

Como faraón, situé a miembros de mi familia en posiciones de alto rango. Mi hijo derrotará los últimos reductos de resistencia y heredará las tierras de Kush y Egipto.

Mi nombre pasará a la historia como el primero de una dinastía faraónica en Egipto, gobernante a la altura del poder y la influencia kushita.</es>
		<de>      Ich bin Piye, habe die Thronnamen Usimare und Sneferre adoptiert, und bin Pharao und Eroberer Ägyptens – und hingebungsvoller Diener Amanis.

      Als Kind der Königsfamilie von Kusch und Oberägyptens musste ich zusehen, wie Unterägypten mehr und mehr in sich gegenseitig bekriegende Gefilde zerbrach. Doch ich folgte dem Ruf Amanis – des Gottes, den die Ägypter als Amun verehren – und versuchte, das Land unter meiner Herrschaft zu einen. Obwohl die lokalen Könige versuchten, mich durch Koalitionen, Diplomatie und Kriege zu behindern, konnten sie Amanis Willen nicht aufhalten.

      Als Pharao hievte ich meine Familie in Ehrenämter. Mein Sohn besiegte die letzten Widerstandsnester und wird einst die Länder Kuschs und Ägyptens regieren.

      Man wird sich meines Namens stets erinnern: als Erster einer pharaonischen Dynastie Ägyptens und als Herrscher über Kusch während einer Zeit, in der diese Nation in Macht und Einfluss alle anderen überstrahlt.</de>
		<fr>      Je suis Piânkhy, Usimare et Sneferre, pharaon et conquérant de l’Égypte et vénérateur d’Amani.

      Né du trône de Koush et de la Haute Égypte, j’ai vu la Basse Égypte se fracturer en raison de luttes intestines et de querelles dynastiques. Suivant l’appel d’Amani, le dieu que les Égyptiens appellent Amon, j’ai cherché à unir ces pays sous mon règne. Malgré les plus grands efforts des rois locaux pour me repousser au moyen de coalitions, de diplomatie et de guerre, la volonté d’Amani n’a pu être arrêtée.

      En tant que pharaon, j’ai donné aux membres de ma famille des rôles honorables. Les derniers bastions de résistance seront vaincus par mon fils, qui héritera des pays de Koush et d’Égypte.

      On se souviendra de mon nom comme de celui de la première dynastie pharaonique d’Égypte, et d’un roi au pinacle de la puissance et de l’influence koushite.</fr>
		<ja>      私はピイ。ウシマレ、スネフェル、そしてエジプトのファラオであり、征服者であり、アマニの信奉者である。

      クシュと上エジプトの王位に生まれた私は、下エジプトが内紛と王朝の争いで分裂していくのを目にしていた。エジプト人がアムンと称する神、アマニの呼びかけに応じて、私は自らの支配下で土地を統合することを目指した。地元の王たちが連合、外交、戦争を通じて私を退けようと死力を尽くしたが、アマニの意志は止められなかった。

      ファラオとして、私は氏族を名誉ある役職に就けた。最後の抵抗勢力は私の息子によって打ち破られる。そして息子は、クシュとエジプトの地を受け継ぐこととなるのだ。

      私の名はファラオによる王朝、その初代王として、またクシュ人の権力と影響力の絶頂期を築いた支配者として記憶されるだろう。</ja>
		<zh-TW>      我是皮耶，烏斯瑪律，也是斯尼非利，法老、埃及的征服者、虔誠的阿馬尼信徒。

      我出生在庫什和上埃及的王位上，眼看著下埃及四分五裂，陷入內訌和王朝爭端。我遵循了阿馬尼的召喚（埃及人將阿馬尼稱為阿蒙神），試圖讓自己統治下的土地回歸統一。儘管當地的國王們盡了最大的努力，想要通過聯盟、外交和戰爭來阻止我，阿馬尼的意志也勢不可擋。

      我是法老，讓自己的家族登上了令人尊敬的地位。頑固分子的最後抵抗將會被我的兒子擊敗，他會繼承庫什和埃及的土地。

      作為埃及法老王朝的第一人，讓庫什特的權力和影響力達到頂峰的統治者，我的名字將被永遠銘記。</zh-TW>
		<ru>      Я Пианхи, Усимаре и Снеферре, фараон и завоеватель Египта, почитатель Амани.

      Рожденный стать царем Куша и Верхнего Египта, я наблюдал, как Нижний Египет был расколот междоусобицей и династическими распрями. Следуя зову бога Амани, которого египтяне зовут Амон, я стремился объединить земли под своим началом. Местные цари пытались противостоять мне с помощью союзов, дипломатии и войн. Но воля Амани непреклонна, несмотря ни на что.

      Став фараоном, я назначил членов своей семьи на почетные должности. Мой сын покончил с оставшимися очагами сопротивления, унаследовав земли Куша и Египта.

      Меня запомнят как основателя династии фараонов Египта, при котором Куш достиг пика влияния и могущества.</ru>
		<zh-CN>      我是皮耶，乌斯马尔，也是斯尼非利，法老、埃及的征服者、阿马尼的信徒。

      我出生在库什和上埃及的王位上，眼看着下埃及四分五裂，陷入内讧和王朝争端。我遵循了阿马尼的召唤（埃及人将阿马尼称为阿蒙神），试图让自己统治下的土地回归统一。尽管当地的国王们尽了最大的努力，想要通过联盟、外交和战争来阻止我，阿马尼的意志也势不可挡。

      我是法老，让自己的家族登上了令人尊敬的地位。顽固分子的最后抵抗将会被我的儿子击败，他会继承库什和埃及的土地。

      作为埃及法老王朝的第一人，让库希特的权力和影响力达到顶峰的统治者，我的名字将被永远铭记。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Eu sou Piiê, Usimare e Seneferre, faraó e conquistador do Egito e devoto de Amani.

Nascido para o trono de Cuxe e do Alto Egito, eu vi o Baixo Egito se fragmentar em lutas e disputas dinásticas. Seguindo o chamado de Amani, o deus que os egípcios chamam de Ámon, eu busquei unir as terras sob meu governo. Apesar dos esforços dos reis locais em me rejeitar com coalisões, diplomacia e guerra, a vontade de Amani não pode ser detida.

Como faraó, eu posicionei minha família em cargos de honra. Os últimos esforços de resistência seria derrotados por meu filho, que viria a herdar as terras de Cuxe e do Egito.

Meu nome será lembrado como o primeiro de uma dinastia de faraós do Egito, um governante no ápice do poder e da influência cuxita.</pt-BR>
		<ko>      나는 피예, 우시마레이자 스네페레이며 파라오이자 이집트의 정복자이고 아마니의 신봉자이다.

      쿠시와 상이집트의 왕좌에서 태어났으며 하이집트가 내전과 왕조의 다툼으로 분열되는 것을 지켜보았다. 이집트인들이 아문이라고 부르는 신 아마니의 부름을 받은 나는 나의 통치 하에 땅을 연합하고자 했다. 지역의 왕들이 연합, 외교와 전쟁을 통해 나의 뜻을 되돌리려고 최선을 다했지만, 아마니의 의지를 멈출 순 없었다.

    나는 파라오로서 명예로운 직책에 나의 가족을 임명했다. 끝까지 저항한 자들은 쿠시와 이집트의 땅을 물려받을 나의 아들이 물리칠 것이다.

      내 이름은 이집트 파라오 왕조의 처음이자, 쿠시 왕국의 권력과 영향력의 절정에 달했던 통치자로 기억될 것이다.</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_DYNASTY_ALARA</zType>
		<en-US>Alara</en-US>
		<es>Alara</es>
		<de>Alara</de>
		<fr>Alara</fr>
		<ja>アララ</ja>
		<zh-TW>阿拉拉</zh-TW>
		<ru>Алара</ru>
		<zh-CN>阿拉拉</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Alara</pt-BR>
		<ko>알라라</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_DYNASTY_ALARA_DESCRIPTION</zType>
		<en-US>Alara is the revered founder of Nepatan Kush, who united the tribes together into a nation. As Leader, Cities founded under Alara start with a bonus to Culture.</en-US>
		<es>Alara fue el venerado fundador del Kush de Napata y logró unir a las tribus en una sola nación. Como líder, las ciudades que funda comienzan con una bonificación de cultura.</es>
		<de>Alara vereinte die Stämme unter einer Nation und gilt als Gründer des nepatanischen Kusch. Wenn er als Anführer eingesetzt wird, beginnen Städte, die unter der Führung von Alara gegründet wurden, mit einem Bonus auf die Kultur.</de>
		<fr>Alara était le fondateur vénéré du royaume napatéen de Koush qui réussit à unir plusieurs tribus en une seule nation. Les villes fondées sous son règne commencent avec un bonus de culture.</fr>
		<ja>ネパタン・クシュの崇敬の対象である創始者。部族をひとつにまとめ建国した。指導者であるアララのもとで建設された都市は、文化にボーナスがついた状態で始まる。</ja>
		<zh-TW>阿拉拉是一位受人尊敬的元老，他建立了納帕塔庫什政權，使部落聯合成一個國家。受阿拉拉的領袖風範影響，在其領導下建立的城市一開始就有文化紅利。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Алара — это основатель напатской династии царей Куша, объединивший разрозненные племена в единое государство. Основанные им города начинают с бонусом к культуре.</ru>
		<zh-CN>阿拉拉是一位受人尊敬的缔造者，建立了纳帕塔库什政权，并使部落联合成一个国家。受阿拉拉的领袖气质影响，在其领导下建立的城市一开始就有文化红利。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Alara é o reverenciado fundador da dinastia Napata de Cuxe, aquele que uniu as tribos em uma só nação. Enquanto líder, as cidades fundadas no governo de Alara começam com um bônus em cultura.</pt-BR>
		<ko>알라라는 나파타 시대 쿠시 왕조의 존경받는 설립자입니다. 그는 여러 부족을 통합해 하나의 국가로 묶었습니다. 알라라가 지도자일 때 설립한 도시에는 문화 보정이 적용됩니다.</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_DYNASTY_ALARA_STORY</zType>
		<en-US>    I am Alara, the revered King of Kush and founder of the Napatan dynasty.

    Although our lands were conquered by the Pharaohs of Egypt, their influence has receded with time and Kush is once again free. I fought to unite the disparate tribes into a single nation, bringing the lands of Nubia together into the Kingdom of Kush.

    Under my rule I founded the city of Napata as the administrative and religious center of the nation. The priesthood of Amani, with their temples around Jebel Barkal, already wields considerable power.

    My name will be remembered throughout the dynasty as one to be revered, and my children and my children’s children will reverse our fortunes to conquer Egypt. The future rulers of Kush will pray for a rule as long and as stable as mine.</en-US>
		<es>Soy Alara, el rey venerado de Kush y fundador de la dinastía Napata.

Aunque los faraones de Egipto conquistaron nuestras tierras, su influencia ha menguado con el paso del tiempo y Kush ha recuperado su libertad. Luché para conseguir la unión de diversas tribus con las que formar una única nación unida que acogió todo el territorio de Nubia en el reino de Kush.

Bajo mi mandato fundé la ciudad de Napata como centro administrativo y religioso de la nación. La actividad sacerdotal de Amani, acogida en los templos de Gebel Barkal, ya ejerce un poder considerable.

El eco de mi nombre retumbará a lo largo de la dinastía como alguien a quien idolatrar. Mis hijos y los hijos de mis hijos invertirán las tornas y conquistarán Egipto. Los próximos gobernantes de Kush rezarán por un gobierno tan extenso y estable como el mio.</es>
		<de>      Ich bin Alara, der verehrte König von Kusch und Begründer der Napata-Dynastie.

      Obgleich unsere Länder von den Pharaonen Ägyptens erobert wurden, nahm ihr Einfluss im Laufe der Zeit ab und Kusch ist erneut frei. Ich kämpfte, um die verstreuten Stämme zu einer einzelnen Nation zu vereinen, und überführte die Länder Nubiens ins Königreich Kusch.

      Unter meiner Herrschaft wurde die Stadt Napata als administratives und religiöses Zentrum der Nation gegründet. Das Priestertum der Amani, mit all ihren um den Berg Jebel Barkal gelegenen Tempeln, besitzt bereits eine erkleckliche Menge Macht.

      Die Dynastie wird auf ewig mit meinem geschätzten Namen in Verbindung gebracht werden. Die Kinder und die Kinder meiner Kinder werden unser Schicksal wenden und Ägypten erobern. Die zukünftigen Herrscher Kuschs werden noch lange für eine Herrschaft beten, die so lang und so stabil wie die meine ist.</de>
		<fr>      Je suis Alara, roi vénéré de Koush et fondateur de la dynastie Napatan.

      Bien que nos terres aient été conquises par les pharaons d’Égypte, leur influence s’est amenuisée au fil du temps et Koush est de nouveau libre. Je me suis battu pour unir les tribus disparates en une seule nation et rassembler les terres de Nubie dans le royaume de Koush.

      Lors de mon règne, j’ai fondé la cité de Napata, qui est le centre administratif et religieux de la nation. Les prêtres d’Amani, avec leurs temples autour de Jebel Barkal, détiennent déjà un pouvoir considérable.

      On se souviendra de mon nom tout au long de la dynastie comme d’un nom admirable, et mes enfants et les enfants de mes enfants feront tourner la roue de la fortune pour conquérir l’Égypte. Les futurs dirigeants de Koush prieront pour avoir un règne aussi long et stable que le mien.</fr>
		<ja>      私はアララ。クシュの尊ぶべき王であり、ナパタ王朝の創始者である。

      一時、私たちの土地はエジプトのファラオに征服されたが、その影響力は時代とともに後退し、クシュは再び自由となった。私はバラバラだった部族をひとつの国にまとめるために戦った。そうして、ヌビアの地をクシュ王国へとまとめ上げたのだ。

      我が統治下に、国の行政と宗教の中心地としてナパタという都市を建設した。ゲベル・バルカル周辺にいるアマニの神官たちは、すでにかなりの権力を握っている。

      私の名は、王朝全体で敬われるものとして記憶されるだろう。そして、子孫たちがこの運命を逆転し、エジプトを制覇するのだ。クシュの未来の支配者たちは、私のように長く安定した統治をと祈ることだろう。</ja>
		<zh-TW>      我是阿拉拉，受人敬仰的庫什國王和納巴塔王朝的創始人，

      雖然我們的土地曾被埃及法老征服，但他們的影響力隨著時間的推移而減弱，庫什再次獲得了自由。我努力將各個部落統一為一個國家，將努比亞的土地統一為庫什王國。

      在我的統治下，我建立了納帕塔城，作為全國的行政和宗教中心。在博爾戈爾山周圍擁有神殿的阿馬尼祭司已經擁有了相當大的權力。

     我是受人敬仰的國王，我的名字將被整個王朝銘記，我的子子孫孫將會扭轉我們的命運，最終征服埃及。庫什未來的統治者都會祈禱自己的統治能像我這樣長久而穩定。</zh-TW>
		<ru>      Я Алара, досточтимый царь Куша и основатель династии царей Напаты.

      Наши земли были завоеваны египетскими фараонами, но со временем их влияние ослабло, и Куш снова стал свободным. Я стремился объединить разрозненные племена в единый народ, а земли Нубии — в одно царство Куш.

      Во время своего правления я основал город Напату — управленческий и религиозный центр моей державы. Жрецы Амани, чьи храмы возведены вокруг Джебель-Баркала, уже обладают значительной властью.

      Мое имя будут помнить и чтить, пока жива моя династия, а мои дети и дети моих детей обратят судьбу вспять и завоюют Египет. Будущие цари Куша будут молиться о столь же долгом и стабильном правлении, как мое.</ru>
		<zh-CN>      我是阿拉拉，受人敬仰的库什国王和纳巴塔王朝的创始人，

      虽然我们的土地曾被埃及法老征服，但他们的影响力随着时间的推移而减弱，库什再次获得了自由。我努力将各个部落统一为一个国家，将努比亚的土地统一为库什王国。

      在我的统治下，我建立了纳帕塔城，作为全国的行政和宗教中心。在博尔戈尔山周围拥有神殿的阿马尼祭司已经拥有了相当大的权力。

     我是受人敬仰的国王，我的名字将被整个王朝铭记，我的子子孙孙将会扭转我们的命运，最终征服埃及。库什未来的统治者都会祈祷自己的统治能像我这样长久而又稳定。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Eu sou Alara, o reverenciado rei de Cuxe e fundador da dinastia napata.

Embora nossas terras tivessem sido conquistadas pelos faraós do Egito, a influência deles retrocedeu com o tempo e Cuxe é livre mais uma vez. Eu lutei para unir as tribos desunidas em uma única nação, juntando assim as terras da Núbia para formar o reino de Cuxe.

Sob meu governo, eu fundei a cidade de Napata para ser o centro administrativo e religioso da nação. Os sacerdotes de Amani, com seus templos em volta do Jebel Barcal, já têm um considerável poder.

Meu nome será lembrado pelas dinastias como o de alguém a ser reverenciado. Meus filhos, e os filhos de meus filhos, irão inverter o destino para conquistar o Egito. Os futuros governantes de Cuxe rezarão para ter um reinado tão duradouro e estável quanto o meu.</pt-BR>
		<ko>      나는 알라라, 존경받는 쿠시의 왕이자 나파탄 왕조를 설립하였다.

      비록 우리의 땅은 이집트의 파라오가 점령했지만, 그들의 영향력은 시간이 갈수록 줄어들었고 쿠시는 다시 한번 자유로워졌다. 나는 서로 다른 부족들을 하나의 국가로 통합하기 위해 싸웠고, 누비아의 땅을 합쳐 쿠시 왕국으로 만들었다.

      내가 통치하는 동안 국가의 행정 및 종교 중심 도시인 나파타를 설립하였다. 아마니의 사제단은 게벨 바르칼 주변의 사원을 통해 엄청난 권력을 행사하고 있다.

      내 이름은 왕조 내내 존경받는 인물로 기억될 것이며 나의 자식과 자식의 자식들은 우리의 운명을 바꿔 이집트를 정복할 것이다. 쿠시의 미래 지도자들은 나처럼 오랫동안 안정적으로 통치하길 바랄 것이다.</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_DYNASTY_SHANAKDAKHETE</zType>
		<en-US>Shanakdakhete</en-US>
		<es>Shanakdakhete</es>
		<de>Shanakdakheto</de>
		<fr>Shanakdakhete</fr>
		<ja>シャナクダケテ</ja>
		<zh-TW>莎娜卡達科特</zh-TW>
		<ru>Шанакдакете</ru>
		<zh-CN>莎娜卡达科特</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Shanakdakhete</pt-BR>
		<ko>샤나크다케테</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_DYNASTY_SHANAKDAKHETE_DESCRIPTION</zType>
		<en-US>Shanakdakhete is the first of the Queens of Kush, who helped to turn Meroë into a capital of culture and trade. She starts with the Literature resource and gets access to Caravans through meeting new Nations.</en-US>
		<es>Shanakdakhete fue la primera de las reinas de Kush, la que ayudó a convertir Meroe en una capital cultural y comercial. Comienza con el recurso de literatura y obtiene acceso a las caravanas al encontrarse con nuevas naciones.</es>
		<de>Shanakdakheto ist die erste Königin von Kusch, die dazu beigetragen hat, Meroe zu einer Hauptstadt für Kultur und Handel zu machen. Shanakdakheto beginnt mit der Ressource Literatur und erhält durch die Begegnung mit neuen Völkern Zugang zu Karawanen.</de>
		<fr>Shanakdakhete était la première reine du royaume de Koush. Elle a contribué à transformer Méroé en une capitale de la culture et du commerce. Elle commence avec la ressource Littérature et a accès aux caravanes lorsqu'elle rencontre de nouvelles nations.</fr>
		<ja>クシュの初代女王。メロエを文化と交易の中心的地へと変えた立役者。彼女は文学資源から開始し、新しい国家との出会いを通じて貿易商人にアクセスできるようになる。</ja>
		<zh-TW>莎娜卡達科特是第一任庫什女王，她將麥羅埃打造成文化和貿易之都。她引導下建立的城市在起始時具有文化資源，而且可以透過與新國家接觸組建商隊。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Шанакдакете — первая царица Куша, которая превратила Мероэ в культурную и торговую столицу. Она начинает с литературным ресурсом и получает доступ к караванам, встречая новые народы.</ru>
		<zh-CN>莎娜卡达科特是第一任库什女王，她将麦罗埃打造成了文化和贸易之都。她引导下建立的城市在起始时具有文化资源，而且可以通过与新国家接触以组建商队。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Shanakdakhete é a primeira das rainhas de Cuxe, ela ajudou a transformar Meroé em uma capital cultural e comercial. Ela começa com o recurso de literatura e pode ganhar acesso às caravanas ao encontrar novas nações.</pt-BR>
		<ko>샤나크다케테는 메로에를 문화와 교역의 수도로 성장시키는 데에 이바지한 쿠시 왕국의 첫 여왕입니다. 시작할 때 문학 자원이 주어지고 새로운 국가와 대면하면 행상을 이용할 수 있게 됩니다.</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_DYNASTY_SHANAKDHAKETE_STORY</zType>
		<en-US>    I am Shanakdakhete, Kandake of Meroe, Son of Ra and Lord of the Two Lands.

    Under the early rulers Meroe prospered, becoming a center of literature and trade for nations near and far. Our mines for smelting iron outpaced those of our rivals, and the Meroitic script took form.

    The culture of Meroe flourishes under my rule. My name may not be well known, but this will change, for the world is yet to see the potential of Kush.</en-US>
		<es>Soy Shanakdakhete, candace de Meroe, hija de Ra y reina de las dos tierras.

Meroe prosperó, gracias a los primeros que gobernaron en ella, hasta convertirse en el centro literario y comercial de las naciones próximas y lejanas. Nuestras minas y forjas de hierro prevalecieron sobre las de nuestros rivales, y la escritura meroítica tomó forma.

La cultura de Meroe florece bajo mi mandato. Puede que mi nombre se pierda con el tiempo, pero me aseguraré de que el mundo admire el potencial de Kush.</es>
		<de>      Ich bin Shanakdakheto, Kandake von Meroe, Sohn des Ra und Herr der zwei Länder.

      Unter den frühen Herrschern fing Meroe an zu erblühen und wurde schließlich für Nah und Fern zu einem Zentrum der Literatur und des Handels. Unsere Minen und Eisenschmieden übertrumpften die unserer Rivalen und die meroitische Schrift nahm mehr und mehr Gestalt an.

      Die meroitische Kultur erblüht unter meiner Herrschaft sogar noch prächtiger als je zuvor – obwohl mein Name sich nicht allzu großer Bekanntheit erfreut. Aber das wird sich noch ändern, wenn die Welt Augenzeugin des ganzen Potenzials von Kusch geworden ist.</de>
		<fr>      Je suis Shanakdakhete, Kandake de Méroé, fils de Râ et Seigneur des Deux Terres.

      Sous la tutelle de ses premiers dirigeants, Méroé prospéra, devenant un centre de littérature et de commerce pour les nations voisines et éloignées. Nos mines de fer surpassaient celles de nos rivaux et l’écriture méroïtique prit forme.

      La culture de Méroé est florissante sous mon règne. Mon nom n’est pas des plus connus, mais cela va changer, car le monde n’a pas encore été témoin du potentiel de Koush.</fr>
		<ja>      私はシャナクダヘテ。メロエのカンダケ、ラーの息子、二つの国の君主である。

      この地を初めに率いていた指導者たちの下、繁栄したメロエは、近隣諸国や遠方の国々にとって文学と貿易の中心地となっていた。鉄を製錬する鉱山は他国を凌駕し、メロエ文字が生みだされた。

      メロエ文化は、我が統治下で栄えている。私の名は、それほど広く浸透していないのかもしれない…それは裏を返せば、世界はまだクシュの持つ可能性を知らないということだ。</ja>
		<zh-TW>      我是莎娜卡達科特，麥羅埃的坎達克，拉神之子，雙城之主。

      在早期統治者的統治下，麥羅埃走向繁榮，成為遠近各國的文學和貿易中心。我們的冶鐵礦遠超對手，還確立了麥羅埃文字。

      麥羅埃的文化在我的統治下蓬勃發展。我的名字可能不太為人所知，但這種情況一定會改變，因為世界尚未看到庫什的潛力。</zh-TW>
		<ru>      Я Шанакдакете, кандакия Мероэ, дочь Ра и правительница Двух земель.

      Благодаря усилиям первых царей держава Мероэ стала центром литературы и торговли для ближних и дальних народов. Железные рудники наших соперников не могли сравниться с нашими, а мероитское письмо обрело форму.

      Во время моего правления культура Мероэ расцвела. Возможно, мое имя известно не каждому, но всему свое время: мир еще увидит, на что способен Куш.</ru>
		<zh-CN>      我是莎娜卡达科特，麦罗埃的坎达克，拉神之子，双城之主。

      在早期统治者的统治下，麦罗埃走向繁荣，成为远近各国的文学和贸易中心。我们的冶铁矿远超对手，还确立了麦罗埃文字。

      麦罗埃的文化在我的统治下蓬勃发展。我的名字可能不太为人所知，但这种情况一定会改变，因为世界尚未看到库什的潜力。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Eu sou Shanakdakhete, candace de Meroé, filho de Rá e Senhora das Duas Terras.

Meroé prosperou sob o reinado dos primeiros governantes, e se tornou um centro da literatura e do comércio para nações próximas e distantes. Nossas forjas e minas de ferro superavam as de nossos rivais e a escrita meróitica surgiu.

A cultura de Meroé floresce sob meu comando. Meu nome pode não ser tão conhecido, mas isso irá mudar, pois o mundo está por ver todo o potencial de Cuxe.</pt-BR>
		<ko>      나는 샤나크다케테, 메로에의 칸다케이자 라의 아들, 두 왕국의 군주다.

      초기 통치자들의 통치 하에 메로에는 번성했고, 가깝고 먼 나라를 위한 문학과 교역의 중심지가 되었다. 철을 제련하는 우리 광산은 경쟁자들에 비해 속도가 빨랐고, 메로이트 문자가 형성되었다.

      메로에의 문화가 나의 통치 하에 번성한다. 나의 이름은 잘 알려져 있지 않지만, 이는 곧 바뀔 것이다. 세상이 쿠시 왕국의 잠재력을 보게 될 것이다.</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_TRAIT_REVERED</zType>
		<en-US>Revered</en-US>
		<es>Venerado</es>
		<de>Verehrt~Verehrter~Verehrte~Verehrtes</de>
		<fr>Vénéré</fr>
		<ja>崇敬の対象</ja>
		<zh-TW>受人崇敬</zh-TW>
		<ru>Почитаемый</ru>
		<zh-CN>被他人崇敬</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Venerável</pt-BR>
		<ko>존경받는</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_TRAIT_REVERED_F</zType>
		<en-US>Revered</en-US>
		<es>Venerada</es>
		<de>Verehrt~Verehrter~Verehrte~Verehrtes</de>
		<fr>Vénérée</fr>
		<ja>崇敬の対象</ja>
		<zh-TW>受人崇敬</zh-TW>
		<ru>Почитаемая</ru>
		<zh-CN>被他人崇敬</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Venerável</pt-BR>
		<ko>존경받는</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_TRAIT_SICKLY</zType>
		<en-US>Sickly</en-US>
		<es>Enfermizo</es>
		<de>Kränklich~Kränklicher~Kränkliche~Kränkliches</de>
		<fr>Chétif</fr>
		<ja>病弱</ja>
		<zh-TW>體弱多病</zh-TW>
		<ru>Немощный</ru>
		<zh-CN>体弱多病</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Adoentado</pt-BR>
		<ko>허약한</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_TRAIT_SICKLY_F</zType>
		<en-US>Sickly</en-US>
		<es>Enfermiza</es>
		<de>Kränklich~Kränklicher~Kränkliche~Kränkliches</de>
		<fr>Chétive</fr>
		<ja>病弱</ja>
		<zh-TW>體弱多病</zh-TW>
		<ru>Немощная</ru>
		<zh-CN>体弱多病</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Adoentada</pt-BR>
		<ko>허약한</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_TRAIT_DIPLOMATIC</zType>
		<en-US>Diplomatic</en-US>
		<es>Diplomático</es>
		<de>Diplomatisch~Diplomatischer~Diplomatische~Diplomatisches</de>
		<fr>Diplomate</fr>
		<ja>外交手腕に長ける</ja>
		<zh-TW>外交得體</zh-TW>
		<ru>Дипломатичный</ru>
		<zh-CN>外交得体</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Diplomático</pt-BR>
		<ko>외교적인</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_TRAIT_DIPLOMATIC_F</zType>
		<en-US>Diplomatic</en-US>
		<es>Diplomática</es>
		<de>Diplomatisch~Diplomatischer~Diplomatische~Diplomatisches</de>
		<fr>Diplomate</fr>
		<ja>外交手腕に長ける</ja>
		<zh-TW>外交得體</zh-TW>
		<ru>Дипломатичная</ru>
		<zh-CN>外交得体</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Diplomática</pt-BR>
		<ko>외교적인</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_TRAIT_DILIGENT</zType>
		<en-US>Diligent</en-US>
		<es>Diligente</es>
		<de>Fleißig~Fleißiger~Fleißige~Fleißiges</de>
		<fr>Appliqué</fr>
		<ja>勤勉</ja>
		<zh-TW>勤勉</zh-TW>
		<ru>Усердный</ru>
		<zh-CN>勤勉</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Diligente</pt-BR>
		<ko>성실한</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_TRAIT_DILIGENT_F</zType>
		<en-US>Diligent</en-US>
		<es>Diligente</es>
		<de>Fleißig~Fleißiger~Fleißige~Fleißiges</de>
		<fr>Appliquée</fr>
		<ja>勤勉</ja>
		<zh-TW>勤勉</zh-TW>
		<ru>Усердная</ru>
		<zh-CN>勤勉</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Diligente</pt-BR>
		<ko>성실한</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_TRAIT_FERVENT</zType>
		<en-US>Fervent</en-US>
		<es>Fervoroso</es>
		<de>Eifernd~Eifernder~Eifernde~Eiferndes</de>
		<fr>Pieux</fr>
		<ja>熱意溢れる</ja>
		<zh-TW>虔誠</zh-TW>
		<ru>Ярый</ru>
		<zh-CN>虔诚</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Fervoroso</pt-BR>
		<ko>열성적인</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_TRAIT_FERVENT_F</zType>
		<en-US>Fervent</en-US>
		<es>Fervorosa</es>
		<de>Eifernd~Eifernder~Eifernde~Eiferndes</de>
		<fr>Pieuse</fr>
		<ja>熱意溢れる</ja>
		<zh-TW>虔誠</zh-TW>
		<ru>Ярая</ru>
		<zh-CN>虔诚</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Fervorosa</pt-BR>
		<ko>열성적인</ko>
	</Entry>
	<!-- text-achievementTitle -->
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_ACHIEVEMENT_UNIT_BEJA_ARCHER_TITLE</zType>
		<en-US>Beja Archer</en-US>
		<es>Arquero beja</es>
		<de>Bejabogenschütze</de>
		<fr>Archer bedja</fr>
		<ja>ベジャの射手</ja>
		<zh-TW>貝沙弓兵</zh-TW>
		<ru>Лучник беджа</ru>
		<zh-CN>贝沙弓兵</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Arqueiro Beja</pt-BR>
		<ko>베자 궁병</ko>
	</Entry>
	<!-- text-achievement -->
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_ACHIEVEMENT_UNIT_BEJA_ARCHER</zType>
		<en-US>Train a Beja Archer</en-US>
		<es>Instruir un arquero beja</es>
		<de>Ausbildung eines Bejabogenschützen</de>
		<fr>Formez un archer bedja</fr>
		<ja>ベジャの射手を訓練する</ja>
		<zh-TW>訓練一名貝沙弓兵</zh-TW>
		<ru>Подготовить лучника беджа</ru>
		<zh-CN>训练一名贝沙弓兵</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Treine um arqueiro beja.</pt-BR>
		<ko>베자 궁병을 육성한다</ko>
	</Entry>
</Root>