<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--This file is generated by the LocalizationEditor!-->
<Root>
	<Entry>
		<zType />
		<en-US />
		<es />
		<de />
		<fr />
		<ja />
		<zh-TW />
		<ru />
		<zh-CN />
		<pt-BR />
		<ko />
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_NATION_HITTITE_STORY</zType>
		<en-US>      I am Hattusili I, creator of nations and conqueror of empires. I bring fear to the hearts of Kings and Queens, and make Pharaohs kneel before me whether they admit it or not. In my mortal days I am a King and in immortality I am a God.

      My people are the Hittites, the hidden people. Sense our presence until it is too late. Unwise you'd be to think we are not real or it will be much too late. Save your people and kneel before me.

      I demand loyalty and the weak kneel before me. I denied my sons the throne, and with my passing my reign goes to my grandson. He will lead our people into eternity and keep my legacy.

      I am Hattusili, King of Hattusa.
</en-US>
		<es>Soy Hattusili I, creador de naciones y conquistador de imperios. Llevo el miedo a los corazones de reyes y reinas y hago que los faraones se arrodillen ante mí, quieran o no. En mis días mortales soy rey, y en la inmortalidad, soy un dios.

Mi pueblo son los hititas: el pueblo oculto. Si notas nuestra presencia, es que es demasiado tarde. No sería inteligente por tu parte creer que no somos reales o no hacer nada hasta el último momento. Salva a tu pueblo y arrodíllate ante mí.

Exijo lealtad y que los débiles hinquen la rodilla ante mí. Le negué el trono a mis hijos, y tras mi partida, mi reinado pasará a mi nieto: él liderará a nuestro pueblo hacia la eternidad y preservará mi legado.

Soy Hattusili, rey de Hattusa</es>
		<de>    Ich bin Hattušili, Kriegerkönig der Hethiter. Einst unter dem Namen Labarna bekannt, verdiente ich mir meinen Thronnamen durch Kriege zur Vereinigung der hethitischen Kernlande.

      Obwohl das Volk nun geschlossen hinter Euch steht, besteht die Gefahr einer Intrige. Eure Familie muss für die Erbfolge in Stellung gebracht werden, wenn Hatti als Großmacht den Ruhm des Königreichs Eurer Vorväter übertreffen soll.</de>
		<fr>    Je suis Hattusili, guerrier roi des Hittites. Auparavant, je portais le nom de Labarnas, mais j'ai obtenu mon nom de trône en me battant pour unir les terres centrales.

      Même si le peuple se tient aujourd'hui derrière vous, la menace du complot pèse encore. Votre famille devra être mise au pas si les Hittites venaient à devenir une grande nation surpassant le royaume de vos ancêtres.</fr>
		<ja>    我はヒッタイトの戦士王、ハットゥシリである。当初はラバルナスと呼ばれていたが、中部地域統一の戦いを通じて、王の名を得た。

    今は民衆があなたを支えてくれているが、それでも陰謀の脅威が存在する。ヒッタイトが、あなたの先祖の王国を超える偉大な国になるためには、氏族が一致団結する必要がある。</ja>
		<zh-TW>我是哈圖西里，西臺人的戰士國王。起初我叫做拉巴爾那，後來透過戰鬥統一國家腹地，贏得了王位稱號。

雖然現在人民在背後支持你，但你依然有被暗算的威脅。若要讓西臺成為超越祖先王國的偉大國家，你必須讓家人服從你。</zh-TW>
		<ru>    Вы Хаттусили, царь-воин хеттов. Сначала вас звали Лабарнасом, но затем, сражаясь и объединяя земли, вы заработали тронное имя.

Народ стоит за вами, но угроза интриги сохраняется. Чтобы хетты стали процветающей нацией и превзошли величием царство ваших предков, вам нужно усмирить собственную семью.</ru>
		<zh-CN>我是哈图西里，西台人的战士国王。起初我叫做拉巴尔那，后来透过战斗统一国家腹地，赢得了王位称号。

虽然现在人民在背后支持你，但你依然有被暗算的威胁。若要让西台成为超越祖先王国的伟大国家，你必须让家人服从你。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Eu sou Hatusil I, criador de nações e conquistador de impérios. Eu levo o medo aos corações de reis e rainhas, e faço faraós se ajoelharem ante mim, quer eles admitam ou não. Durante minha vida mortal eu sou um rei e em minha imortalidade eu sou um deus.
 
O meu povo são os hititas, o povo oculto. Quando nossa presença é notada, já é tarde demais, porém seria tolice pensar que não somos reais. Salve o seu povo e ajoelhe-se diante de mim.
 
Eu exijo lealdade e que os mais fracos se submetam a mim. Eu neguei o direito do trono aos meus filhos e, quando faleci, meu reino ficou para o meu neto. Ele irá liderar nosso povo até a eternidade e preservará meu legado.
 
Eu sou Hatusil, rei de Hatusa.</pt-BR>
		<ko>      나는 여러 국가의 창시자이자 제국의 정복자인 하투실리 1세다. 내 앞에서는 왕과 여왕의 심장이 공포로 얼어붙고, 파라오조차 자의로든 타의로든 무릎을 꿇는다. 나는 생전에는 왕이요, 사후에는 신이라.

      나의 백성은 숨은 민족 히타이트족이다. 더는 돌이킬 수 없을 때까지 우리의 존재를 마음껏 느껴 보아라. 우리를 생각하지 못할 정도로 아둔한 머리나 너무 늦은 순간만이 적국을 기다릴 뿐. 내 앞에 무릎 꿇어 네 민족을 구원하라.

      귀족과 약자 모두 내게 굴복하여야 한다. 나는 내 아들에게 왕좌를 넘기지 않았기에 나의 손자가 민족을 통치하게 되었다. 녀석이 우리 민족을 영원히 번영시키고 나의 유산을 이어가리라.

      나는 히타이트의 왕 하투실리다.</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_GUIDE_TECH_HITTITE_CHARIOT_1_BONUS</zType>
		<en-US>This bonus grants a free link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_1) Unit in your Capital. A mounted and ranged Unit that is unique to link(NATION_HITTITE), the link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_1) moves especially quickly for harassing your enemies. If a bonus card is not researched when it appears, it is permanently trashed once discarded and will not appear again.</en-US>
		<es>Esta bonificación te concede una unidad de link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_1) gratis en tu capital. Una unidad montada de ataque a distancia, única de link(NATION_HITTITE). El raudo link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_1) es ideal para hostigar a tus enemigos. Si no se investiga una carta de bonificación cuando aparece, se destruirá tras su descarte y no volverá a aparecer.</es>
		<de>Diese Bonuskarte gewährt Euch eine kostenlose Einheit link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_1,5) in Eurer Hauptstadt. Er ist eine spezielle berittene Fernkampf-Einheit link(NATION_HITTITE,1) und bewegt sich besonders schnell, um Eure Feinde zu bedrängen. Wenn eine Bonuskarte auftaucht und nicht erforscht wird, wird sie beim Ablegen entsorgt und taucht nicht noch einmal auf.</de>
		<fr>Ce bonus fournit un link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_1) gratuit à votre capitale. Une unité montée et à distance propre à l'link(NATION_HITTITE), le link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_1) se déplace rapidement pour attaquer vos ennemis. Si une carte bonus n'est pas récupérée lors de son apparition alors, une fois jetée, elle sera définitivement perdue et ne réapparaîtra pas.</fr>
		<ja>このボーナスは、自国の首都にlink(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_1)ユニットを無償で付与する。link(NATION_HITTITE)特有の遠隔騎兵ユニットのlink(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_1)は、特に移動速度が速く、敵に嫌がらせをするのに適している。ボーナスカードが出現した際にその研究をしない場合、捨ててしまうと取り戻せず、二度と出現しなくなる。</ja>
		<zh-TW>這項紅利可提供首都免費的link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_1)單位。link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_1)是link(NATION_HITTITE)專屬的騎兵遠程單位，騷擾敵人時的移動速度尤其快。若不研究出現的紅利卡牌，該卡牌遭捨棄後就會永久廢棄，不會再出現。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Этот бонус дает бесплатную {lowercase:link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_1,3)} в столице. link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_1) — это верховой юнит дальнего боя, имеющийся только у link(NATION_HITTITE,1), он передвигается особенно быстро и хорош для изматывания врагов. Если выпавшая карточка не отправлена на исследование, после отказа она удаляется навсегда и больше не появляется.</ru>
		<zh-CN>这项红利可提供首都免费的link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_1)单位。 link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_1)是link(NATION_HITTITE)专属的骑兵远程单位，骚扰敌人时的移动速度尤其快。若不研究出现的红利卡牌，该卡牌遭舍弃后就会永久废弃，不会再出现。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Esta carta bônus concede uma unidade de link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_1) grátis à sua capital. É uma unidade montada e a distância única a link(NATION_HITTITE) que se move especialmente rápido para atacar seu inimigos. Se uma carta bônus não for pesquisada assim que aparecer, será destruída após ser descartada e não aparecerá novamente.</pt-BR>
		<ko>수도에 link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_1) 유닛 하나가 제공됩니다. link(NATION_HITTITE) 고유 원거리 기병 유닛으로 빠르게 이동하며 적을 쉴 틈 없이 공격할 수 있습니다. 선택하지 않은 덤 카드는 영구적으로 버려지며 다시는 나타나지 않습니다.</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_GUIDE_TECH_HITTITE_CHARIOT_2_BONUS</zType>
		<en-US>This bonus grants free link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_2) Units near your Capital. A mounted and ranged Unit that is unique to link(NATION_HITTITE), the link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_2) moves especially quickly for harassing your enemies. If a bonus card is not researched when it appears, it is permanently trashed once discarded and will not appear again.</en-US>
		<es>Esta bonificación te concede unidades de link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_2,2) gratuitas cerca de tu capital. Una unidad montada de ataque a distancia, única de link(NATION_HITTITE), el raudo link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_2) es ideal para hostigar a tus enemigos. Si no se investiga una carta de bonificación cuando aparece, se destruirá tras su descarte y no volverá a aparecer.</es>
		<de>Diese Bonuskarte gewährt Euch kostenlose link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_2,5)-Einheiten nahe Eurer Hauptstadt. Diese spezielle berittene Fernkampfeinheit link(NATION_HITTITE,1) bewegen sich besonders schnell, um Eure Feinde zu bedrängen. {TEXT_GUIDE_TECH_BONUS_DISCARD}</de>
		<fr>Ce bonus fournit des unités de link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_2) gratuites à proximité de votre capitale. Une unité montée et à distance propre à l'link(NATION_HITTITE), les link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_2) se déplacent rapidement pour attaquer vos ennemis. Si une carte bonus n'est pas récupérée lors de son apparition alors, une fois jetée, elle sera définitivement perdue et ne réapparaîtra pas.</fr>
		<ja>このボーナスは、自国の首都周辺にlink(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_2)ユニットを無償で付与する。link(NATION_HITTITE)特有の遠隔騎兵ユニットのlink(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_2)は、特に移動速度が速く、敵を妨害するのに適している。ボーナスカードが出現した際にその研究をしない場合、捨ててしまうと取り戻せず、二度と出現しなくなる。</ja>
		<zh-TW>此加成可在首都附近給予免費的link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_2)單位。link(NATION_HITTITE)特有的坐騎遠程單位。link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_2)能夠快速移動來騷擾敵人。若獎勵卡出現時未研究，拋棄後就會永久失效且不會再次出現。</zh-TW>
		<ru>Этот бонус дает бесплатные отряды {lowercase:link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_2,7)} рядом со столицей. link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_2,6) — это вид конных войск дальнего боя, имеющийся только у link(NATION_HITTITE,1). Он передвигается особенно быстро и хорош для изматывания врагов. Если выпавшая карточка не отправлена на исследование, после отказа она удаляется навсегда и больше не появляется.</ru>
		<zh-CN>这项红利可在你的首都附近提供免费的link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_2)单位。link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_2)是link(NATION_HITTITE)专属的骑兵远程单位，骚扰敌人时的移动速度尤其快。若不研究出现的红利卡牌，该卡牌废弃之后就会永久不再出现。</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>Esta carta bônus concede link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_2,2) grátis à sua capital. É uma unidade montada e a distância única a link(NATION_HITTITE) que se move especialmente rápido para atacar seu inimigos. Se uma carta bônus não for pesquisada assim que aparecer, será destruída após ser descartada e não aparecerá novamente.</pt-BR>
		<ko>수도에 link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_2) 유닛 하나가 제공됩니다. link(NATION_HITTITE) 고유 원거리 기병 유닛으로 빠르게 이동하며 적을 쉴 틈 없이 공격할 수 있습니다. 선택하지 않은 덤 카드는 영구적으로 버려지며 다시는 나타나지 않습니다.</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_TECH_HITTITE_CHARIOT_1_BONUS</zType>
		<en-US>Free link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_1)</en-US>
		<es>link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_1) gratis</es>
		<de>Kostenloser link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_1)</de>
		<fr>link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_1) gratuit</fr>
		<ja>無償のlink(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_1)</ja>
		<zh-TW>免費link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_1)</zh-TW>
		<ru>Бесплатная {lowercase:link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_1)}</ru>
		<zh-CN>免费link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_1)</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_1) Grátis</pt-BR>
		<ko>link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_1) 증정</ko>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_TECH_HITTITE_CHARIOT_2_BONUS</zType>
		<en-US>Free link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_2)</en-US>
		<es>link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_2) gratis</es>
		<de>Kostenloser link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_2)</de>
		<fr>link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_2) gratuits</fr>
		<ja>無償のlink(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_2)</ja>
		<zh-TW>免費link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_2)</zh-TW>
		<ru>Бесплатная {lowercase:link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_2)}</ru>
		<zh-CN>免费link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_2)</zh-CN>
		<pt-BR>link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_2) Grátis</pt-BR>
		<ko>link(UNIT_HITTITE_CHARIOT_2) 증정</ko>
	</Entry>
</Root>